------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
Thank you for riding JR Kyushu.
This is the express train to Hakota, Yamome 38.
Hey.
Would you let me sit there?
It's my seat.
Sir, is something wrong?
No.
It's nothing.
My old house, which has been empty for years, is going to be sold.
I decided to go see it one last time.
My mom died just after I was born,
and I lived with my dad there for several years.
I was too young to really remember it, but...
I can probably follow the map there.
Hey, Natsume.
Buy a boxed lunch at the station.
That's the first step.
Master Nyanko!
Why are you here?
Boxed lunch! Boxed lunch!
The Door Of Memories
Lunches, tea, coffee, juice.
Beer and snacks, too.
I'll take a boxed lunch.
One boxed lunch, yes?
No, two, please.
Two?
Yes. Two.
Hakota.
Master, we're switching trains.
There's somewhere I need to stop first.
The home of my relatives who live closest to that house.
They have the key.
I have to go get it.
You know how to get there?
I stayed there a while when I was little.
I'll probably remember once I get close.
Which is it? Left or right?
Just a second.
I'll check the map.
You don't even know if it's left or right?
I stayed at so many places, so I don't even remember...
I think it's this way.
You don't have a clue, do you?
Oh, Natsume.
There's a noodle shop.
You can remember from there.
I never really paid much attention to the noodle shops.
This smell...
Just a
Noodle Shop
I remember I'd always smell this place on the way home from school.
That's a weird thing to remember, isn't it?
It's this way, Master.
Hey, wait!
What about the noodles?
You just ate a boxed lunch.
Noodles...
This is the way.
The leaves from this tree would fall onto the road.
See that?
The camellias at that house were always so pretty.
A nice old lady lived in that house.
Once in a while, she would give me candy, without telling my dad.
Why did I forget all this?
Hey, Natsume.
Get walking.
Yeah.
I sense a spirit.
That's right. There are a lot of demons around here.
I think that's it.
I'm just going in to get the key.
You wait outside.
It'd be weird if I brought a cat in.
What's weird about that?
Master, I'll buy you noodles on the way back,
so if I don't come out for a long time, come help me.
What?
Is there something in there?
You mean I can eat the people here?
No.
I remember.
There was this weird demon who was living here.
That's right, when we were in elementary school.
You don't remember?
He was here for a while.
Natsume Takashi, huh?
He'll be coming here today.
He said he wanted to see his old house.
I wonder why.
I don't wanna go home.
Why?
I don't want to see him.
He was a gloomy little kid. I didn't like him.
Something really weird is sitting on our wall!
Shoo! Shoo!
Who's that?
Is that him?
He looks cute!
Cute? Maybe...
Oh, Takashi.
Hello there.
You've grown up.
It has been a while.
Um, Tachibana said you have key...
Yes, he told me everything.
Um... would you like to come in?
No, that's fine.
I'll be leaving right away.
Will you?
Aww, why?
You came all this way. Why not have some tea?
Come on in.
Miyoko.
I'm back.
Mom, get some tea ready.
I'm thirsty.
That girl.
Takashi, come inside.
Please.
Yes.
Thank you.
This is bad.
I knew it was here.
It's looking at me.
If I don't look at it, I'll be okay, right?
I don't want any trouble.
It's somewhere around here...
Ah, there it is.
Here.
Thank you.
Um, well...
We haven't really cleaned it.
That's fine.
It's an old house, you know?
Even if we find a buyer, they're probably going to tear it down,
so we haven't really worked on it.
We all took turns going to see it once in a while...
It's fine.
I just want to see it.
I see.
Takashi?
Um...
It's nothing.
Can I use your bathroom?
That's right.
He used to try and scare me.
Still, am I imagining it,
or is he bigger?
I'm kind of surprised, though.
He's changed.
Maybe I should've been nicer.
What are you talking about?
You hated him.
But...
You and dad were always so nice to him,
but he'd always say the most depressing things.
Or just wander off.
He gave our family a bad name.
He's the one who was a weird liar.
Stop it, Miyoko.
He's got lots of problems.
See, like that.
You're spoiling him.
That's what I hated most.
Miyoko...
But I guess he's not a liar anymore.
Mouth...
Draw a mouth...
Let go!
Draw...
A mouth...
I need to leave.
If I'm here, he'll...
Takashi,
what's wrong?
No...
It's nothing.
That demon's bad.
He'll grab me and attack my mind.
I need to hurry.
Um...
Anyway, you've really grown up.
I was worried.
The Fujiwaras, was it?
They're very distant relatives,
and one day they just came and asked to take you.
They never had children, so I wasn't sure if they knew how to take care of you.
Draw... draw...
Takashi?
Actually, you look kind of thin.
Are they feeding you enough?
Draw a mouth.
If you draw one, I'll eat them all.
All the people who've said bad things about you.
I remember.
I know you.
You can see me.
So you can draw a mouth...
If you want to forget...
The sad memories,
and the warm ones...
I'll eat them all.
Draw a mouth.
Hu—
What?
You're not going to say something weird again are you?
Somebody's here.
Dad!
This weird thing that was on our wall came inside!
What is it?
A stray cat?
Is it a cat?
Master?
Are you okay?
He scratched your face.
Mom, get the first aid kit.
Oh, right.
Dad...
I'm fine.
Thank you.
I'll be going.
Um, but...
What's your problem?
Thanks for the key.
I'll be taking this cat with me.
You could at least have some tea.
No, thank you.
I'll worry them if I'm out late.
Thank you.
I-I see.
What about your face?
Is it okay?
Yes.
Thank you.
You saved me, Master.
Jeez...
You always run into the weirdest things.
Master, can you tell me anything about that demon?
When I was a kid, it wasn't that big.
I think it's called a bug-eater.
A bug-eater?
It didn't have a mouth, right?
It sucks away the strength of insects who come into the house and gets bigger.
It eats bugs?
In that case, we can ignore it.
Yeah,
you're probably good for two or three years.
Two or three years?
You felt it, right?
When they get that big they can't be sated by just insects anymore.
Spirits like that foster darkness in human hearts and then devour them.
Let's get going, Natsume.
Hey!
Wait!
How could you leave like that?!
You haven't changed at all!
You're still exactly the same!
My mom and dad are so nice to you!
What's your problem?
Don't try to get attention from my parents by acting weird!
They really worry about you, you know...
Even though they're my mom and dad!
Draw...
Draw a mouth.
Hey, if you want me to draw one, follow me.
Don't worry.
I won't take your family.
Goodbye.
Huh? Wai—
It's following us.
What's wrong with you?
Why can't you just leave them alone?
Even a dog doesn't forget to repay a meal he's been given, Master.
I'm not a dog and neither are you!
How long do I have to run this damn marathon?!
He's a wimp anyway.
You're my prey. He doesn't get to touch you!
Begone. Now.
Thank you, Master.
Idiot.
They let me into their house.
They let me into their family.
I'll go back
to my home, too.
It's like a treasure hunt.
Fight!
Fight! One ! Fight! Two!
I ran as fast as I could, so I don't know where we are.
You idiot!
I'm looking for this spot on the map.
Hmm, you can just go up that road...
We're still not there yet?
If we don't get back soon, we'll miss Tohko's dinner.
That's true.
Let's hurry.
We still have a ways to go.
I won't take your family.
He wouldn't have been able to say it like that a long time ago.
A long time ago, huh?
He was a kid, I guess.
But, Takashi,
I was a kid, too.
Miyoko?
Miyoko.
Dad...
Why did he come here?
Miyoko,
want to have a nice talk with your dad tonight?
Then you can go to school with Takashi tomorrow.
Walk farther behind me.
Hey, where's your house?
Your real house.
My real house?
The house where your parents lived!
Don't you remember?
About your mom and dad?
I don't remember my mom.
And your dad?
My dad either...
But he was...
really, really nice!
You're weird.
How can you say that when you don't remember him?
How dare you talk like that?
My dad's much, much nicer!
He's going home...
To the house where his "really, really nice" dad lived, huh?
Miyoko,
can you come here?
Okay.
Come to think of it, one time I tried
to go back to that house by myself when I was little.
How did I forget?
So did you—
Natsume!
What's wrong, Natsume?
Go home...
I have to go home...
Natsume? Natsume?
Natsume!
I could hear Master calling.
But it felt like my heart was looking for something...
Natsume!
and getting lost in distant memories.
I have to go home.
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
Long Way Home
Next
Time On
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
I have to go home.
My real home.
Actually, I'd called out
for it again and again.
There's my home.
No matter how many
times I called for it,
I couldn't have it.
I need to get back.
I have to hurry... hurry...
Let's go home.