Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Living through these meaningless days, I let out a sigh
I've lost sight of my true self
Even if I strain my ears I can't hear your voice
So I keep walking trying to catch up
The things I couldn't tell you form into a chrysalis over time
Spreading wings, they take flight
The one, the one precious thing I'll never forget
Someday, that warm emotion
I'll do what little I can
Little by little, to get through to you
Natsume, look!
Lightning! Lightning!
Be quiet. I'm doing my homework.
What, you scared?
It's distracting me. Just close the curtain—
That struck in the forest!
The Broken Mirror
This isn't the path we usually take.
We're going near the school.
Where are you going, Master Nyanko?
I'm looking for the tree that got struck by lightning.
Lightning? You mean, from last night?
That's a strange thing to look for.
You ignorant fool!
Old trees struck by lightning can produce booze that's out of this world!
Every spirit knows that.
And on top of that, it's free!
That way! Let's go, Natsume!
Wait, Master Nyanko!
Jeez, where are you, Master?
Master!
Voices? What are they?
Up in the trees!
It's shining.
It's shining...
You're right.
Is that...
Could that be...
Are the stories true?
They're right. Something's shining up there.
Oww!
Shoot, something got in my eye.
Natsume?
What are you doing out here?
Tanuma?
What about you?
I use this forest as a shortcut.
I see.
And...
I feel like I've been hearing voices around here since yesterday.
Voices?
The other day, there were some minor demons who seemed really excited about something.
You're really amazing, Natsume.
But that's not what I mean.
The voice was kind of frantic,
like it was looking for something.
Looking for something?
Something's coming.
Master Nyanko?
No!
Natsume!
Tanuma!
Tanuma? Are you okay?
Y-Yeah...
What was that?
Just a gust of wind?
Thank you, Tanuma,
but don't try to protect me!
I don't want anything to happen to you!
Yeah...
but I don't want anything to happen to you, either.
I guess so.
This feels... kind of queer.
Before, neither of us had a friend we could be completely open with,
which actually made it harder.
Good stuff!
That was seriously good stuff.
A raccoon demon!
Who're you callin' a raccoon?!
Oh, it's Natsume's cat. Hey, Mr. Kitty!
If you can't remember my name, at least call me "Master"!
Jeez, where were you, Master Nyanko?
Off drinking, where else?
You drunkard!
If you can drink booze without getting drunk, you'd be some kind of monster.
Demons are monsters!
Spirits and monsters are completely different!
I'll be going then.
Okay.
See you.
See you tomorrow.
Demons always make things difficult,
but just having a friend who knows my secret
makes things a little better.
I hope that's true for Tanuma, too.
My head hurts.
What is this?
I feel an evil presence.
Natsume!
Good morning.
You look tired.
Taki, morning.
Good timing.
I got the pictures from the cultural festival.
I thought I'd give you yours.
The cultural festival?
Here.
That's the wrong one!
Somebody took that without asking.
This is the one.
You looked cute.
I look really tired in this picture.
But it's a good picture, isn't it?
Thank you.
I've got one of Tanuma, too.
He's sleeping with his mouth open.
Somebody took one of him sleeping backstage.
Would you give that to him?
Sure, leave it to me.
Year 2
Class 1
Tanuma!
Oh, Natsume!
11th Oct Duty
Nakai, Kitamoto
Kitamoto.
Where's Tanuma?
He's absent today.
Said he had a cold.
A cold?
Um, is Kaname all right?
Oh, you came to visit?
Thank you.
His fever's gone down,
but I don't want you getting sick, too.
I think he'll be at school tomorrow.
Tanuma is really sensitive to the presence of demons.
I hope he didn't get too close to one yesterday.
Maybe, but that's only because he's weak.
It's not your fault.
But at least he was protecting me.
Meanwhile, my so-called bodyguard was drinking himself stupid.
What?
It's your fault for getting separated from me, moron!
What was that, you fat cat?
You should just leave that wimp alone!
Don't call him a wimp!
Wimp! Wimp!
Tanuma! Morning.
Are you okay now?
Were you really sick?
Yeah, but I'm still not quite over it yet.
You should stay away from me for a while.
See you!
Teacher?
What's wrong?
Oh, Natsume.
The mirror just broke.
Maybe it was getting old.
It's really broken.
I'll go get a broo—
I thought I saw a someone for a second.
Did I imagine it?
Natsume, is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
This isn't good.
I've been blaming everything on demons lately.
I hope Tanuma gets over his cold soon.
– The Next Day –
How's your cold?
Sorry, not better yet.
– The Day After That –
Tanuma!
Sorry, I'm going to the teacher's office.
Year 2
Class 1
– The Day After The Day After That –
Is Tanuma here?
15th Oct Duty
Tanaka, Hashimoto
Sure is.
Huh? He was just here.
Tanuma?
What on earth was he digging a hole for?
What? My right eye hurts!
I found you.
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Where am I?
The back of the school?
Why are my hands so dirty?
Natsume!
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
Tanuma...
No, my eye just hurts.
Eye?
Forget that.
If you're hiding something...
If you've got any problem at all, then tell me.
You're right.
Sorry, I didn't mean to avoid you.
But I've been feeling sick ever since then...
I don't have any proof that I'm possessed,
so I didn't think it was worth bothering you about.
It might just be a cold.
But just a moment ago, I woke up behind the school with my hands covered in mud.
That's never happened before.
I see.
So?
What about you?
I...
You know, talking to somebody makes you feel better.
And hiding things just makes you feel worse.
You're right.
Actually, that day...
I want some fried squid.
Fried squid, I want you.
I want you.
I'm so happy!
You're choking me! You crazy girl!
You're choking me!
It just started hurting back there.
But it's fine now.
Also, there's a demon with a hammer going around the school.
I don't know if they're connected.
I see.
Was that...
Yeah, I heard it.
It might be that demon with the hammer.
Don't tell me to go back.
Yeah, I won't.
This room?
Stand back.
What are you doing? I told you to stand back.
I am.
I'm just taller than you.
Did you see that?
Yeah.
Not very clearly, though...
It broke another mirror?
Just what is it—
Natsume?
What? Something's shining...
The pain stopped.
A piece of pottery?
Tanuma, this...
Give it back.
Give me that.
I've found my mirror.
Give it back.
Tanuma?
No, it's the demon possessing Tanuma!
Give it back!
Stop it!
Tanuma, I'm sorry.
You've got a lot of power for a human brat.
Get out of Tanuma!
No, I can't.
Why?
My mirror's broken.
I was struck by lightning while searching for a friend.
I'd like to search for the fragments myself,
but it's taking quite a while to recover from that lighting strike.
This child will be my vessel.
Were you making him dig holes to find the mirror?
I finally, finally got the mirror.
I can't give it up that easy.
The fragments have hidden themselves within things that shine.
And one is hiding within your eye.
When you get close to other fragments,
it starts resonating with them and hurts you, right?
Give it to me...
Give me that eye!
Stop!
Tanuma!
Either way, I'm going to stay in this body for a while.
What?
Tanuma!
Don't worry.
I won't take over his mind for that long.
But if you want him back safely,
you'll have to help me, kid.
With that fragment in your eye,
finding the others will be easy.
Once I have the mirror, I will leave.
Like hell you will.
Master Nyanko?
I'm not getting involved in any more ridiculous errands.
Now, get out of there!
Not yet...
I will stay until I my mirror is restored.
Tanuma!
If she can resist my light, she must be very attached.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I heard what happened.
You'll leave if we get the mirror fragments, right?
Yes, that's right.
That's the safest way.
You were just telling her to get out.
If I got serious, I could take care of her easily.
But if I force her out, it could damage his mind.
Are you okay with that?
That's right.
You just need to gather the mirror fragments.
Tanuma?
I feel like my body still isn't my own.
Natsume, I'm sorry, but would you help me find the mirror fragments?
Sure. We'll do it together.
Thanks.
Can I help, too?
It'd be a big help, Taki.
But where do we start?
That demon said that if I got close to the other fragments, my eye would start to hurt.
We'll know one is close when my right eye hurts.
My eye started hurting out behind the school,
which means there's a fragment there.
Let's go.
I'll get some shovels and scoops for us.
Yes, please.
This is where my eye started hurting.
Oww...
This is the place.
Here?
Should I dig here?
Are you okay?
Just wait, Natsume.
I'll find it right now.
What are they doing?
Who knows.
Practicing for a play?
There it is!
No, that's...
What? Just a piece of glass?
It's a demon's mirror, so normal people can't see or touch it.
Then how do we find it?
Huh? Tanuma?
That's it!
I knew it.
What?
What is? I can't see it.
The demon told me it was under the glass.
The pain's going away.
This is it, I'm sure.
Good, I'm glad.
Thank you.
I wonder if it fits with the other piece.
They joined together.
Wow.
What did? What's going on?
Okay. What's next, Natsume?
Let's search around here a little more.
This is going to take a while, isn't it?
He says it's around here.
Flowerbeds
Growing
Oww...
It's over there.
Here, right?
Got it.
They're still doing that?
Looks like it.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah, see you.
Maybe it's because I'm possessed,
but I think I understand.
How the demon feels, I mean.
I see.
That mirror feels really important to her.
I think her friend is sick,
and the mirror has the power to dispel the sickness.
I guess.
It's for a friend?
And she's warning me.
Warning you?
The mirror is very powerful,
so there might be other demons looking for the pieces.
She says to be careful.
Other demons looking for the pieces...
Lining up the sparks of warmth I've lost one by one
Coming to the rainbow-colored pieces of you
I crack a smile
Not even knowing how to make memories
Even when we took things too fast
We were only going with the flow
No matter where I go, even after this darkness
How many times must I say goodbye?
Shining with the flame of a young heart
Those faraway pieces of you
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Reflection
Is this the world you see all the time, Natsume?
Get away from Tanuma!
He's a dear friend.
I had one, too. But my friend
left one day, without saying word.
I'd bet there was a reason.
Even so, I want to save my friend.