------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
Hiiragi!
Natsume?
It's Lord Houzuki!
What? What have we done?
Wait. Something's strange.
Is that really Lord Houzuki?
The deer-horn mask...
It must be him.
No, I smell a child of man, faintly.
A child of man?
It can't be...
Is a human trying to deceive us?
Wake him up!
Let's see!
How dare you!
Do you not realize that I am Houzuki?
Did Fuzuki allow this?
Are you really Lord Houzuki?
If you are, then show us your face under the mask!
Well...
I knew something was wrong.
Grab him!
Strip him of his mask!
He escaped!
Chase him!
Wait.
Could a human command spirits in such a manner?
Then it must be Lord Houzuki after all...
But I'm sure I smelled a child of man.
What is this?
Lord Fuzuki.
You see...
The God,
Enshrined
Natsume!
I'm fine.
I just hurt my shoulder.
What about Hiiragi?
She'll wake up if we can let her rest for a bit somewhere.
Good.
Take us back to that house.
Am I a taxi?
Master, once we put Hiiragi down,
take me down the river once more.
Why?
When I was swept down the river, I felt a small presence.
That was probably Lord Houzuki.
Then let's fly.
I'll catch up soon.
Understood.
Your friend...
It's not a deep wound.
Hiiragi...
I'm fine.
I'm pleased that your friend is safe.
Now please, go search for Lord Houzuki.
So then, now that Natsume's gone, there's something I want to clear up.
Yes?
Was Houzuki truly sealed?
Whatever do you mean?
When was he sealed?
No... you were in quite a hurry when you asked Natsume.
You could've taken action much earlier.
He's a nice kid, and he has strong spiritual energy,
so maybe you're planning to take advantage of him for something.
Could it be that Houzuki is gone?
The flow of time and the loss of people's faith eroded his power,
and the exorcist destroyed him, perhaps?
Or maybe, as the black robes said,
he got sick of both this mountain and you, and ran off?
Perhaps your plan is to turn Natsume into the new Houzuki?
I see.
That's an excellent idea.
Why you...
Excuse me.
It was a joke.
But it's true that Lord Houzuki was sealed.
It was three years ago.
Then...
We waited until the last moment because we made a grave mistake.
A grave mistake?
The winner of the Moon Splitting Festival dwelled in a shrine deep in the mountains,
watching over the mountain and its villages.
With the dwindling of the people's faith, we simply assumed that his days became uneventful.
Then one day, an ignorant exorcist entered this forest filled with spirits,
and happened across Lord Houzuki, whom he sealed.
I imagine he was trying to test his own power.
We searched everywhere for the stone he was sealed in.
However, it was a weaker exorcist who did the sealing.
The seal was feeble.
Lord Houzuki should have been easily able to break free.
Thus, we assumed that he had grown tired of watching over the mountain from his shrine,
and decided to rest for a while inside the seal.
We assumed that when the fun of the festival began, he would certainly appear again.
We waited and protected the shrine.
When he returned,
we planned to suggest that this be the last festival,
and that with his task over, we could leave on another journey.
Yes, just as you say,
the seal may have been broken long ago.
He may have left these lands.
But...
But he may not yet be gone.
The seal may be stronger than you thought,
and he may be waiting for your help.
Was he the kind of lord who would leave you behind?
If you decided in your hearts to serve him,
then believe in your lord.
Natsume.
Natori.
Where's Hiiragi?
I'm having her rest a bit more, just in case.
Is this the spot?
Yes, probably.
At the bottom of the river?
No, I don't think it fell in the river...
You're really amazing,
to be able to sense a presence while being swept down a river.
He must seem like a pretty valuable tool to an exorcist.
You've got that right.
I'd love to have a powerful, talented assistant more than anything.
However, I don't want to lose a dear friend, either.
Master, Natori!
I think that's it.
That's it, huh?
That's not good.
We can't get down there.
It's okay.
I think Master can do it.
What? Why you—
Master, look at that.
The beast is here, too!
Hide for now!
This is bad.
We can't even get close.
It will repel the fangs of a spirit once.
That saved me.
I know, Natsume!
I've got a great plan!
I'll eat it, and you can take back its head!
Everyone will bow before you!
You can't have a god do that.
Everyone will freak out.
We don't have a choice, do we?
Even if we find Houzuki first,
if Fuzuki gets the beast first, we lose!
I'm sure that even if Lord Houzuki loses,
you're planning on asking me to solve everything, right?
But even I might get cursed if I went up against a god.
He's right.
Natori?
It doesn't really matter how we bring him back, I mean.
I have the spell and vial I prepared to seal Lord Fuzuki.
It might be a better idea to use this to catch him, than to take his head.
Natori!
Want to try it?
Yes.
This way!
That which is not shadow, that treads on old ground,
you are under my power.
Show yourself.
Natsume!
Right!
We did it...
Natori, thank you!
I'm sure this will work!
Thanks for helping out, Master Nyanko...
Master!
What was that light?
I feel something unpleasant.
Natsume, take the vial and go to Misumigahara.
I'll hold them here for you.
Natori.
If I can, I'll go back to that cliff and get Houzuki.
It'll be fine, Natsume.
You've come this far.
You're almost there.
You can do it.
Go.
Yes.
You be careful too, Natori.
Hey, did something just go that way?
I can't let you follow.
A human!
What is a human doing here?
Is he planning something?
Is he going to exorcise Lord Fuzuki?
Exorcising a god is difficult,
but I can play with you.
Come.
Both of them are late.
Maybe neither of them will catch it.
Hurry.
Hurry!
The legends say that if Fuzuki wins, the mountain will dry up, yes?
How terrifying.
It'll be fine.
Houzuki has never lost before.
That's true, but...
Look, he's here!
He's here!
Which one is it?
A crown of peonies... it's Houzuki!
He did it!
Lord Houzuki won!
Something's wrong with Lord Houzuki.
He's a mess.
He looks just like...
I, Houzuki, am here first!
Then show us the beast!
You have done it!
The winner is Houzuki!
I did it.
Now...
It's Lord Fuzuki!
Lord Fuzuki!
You are not Houzuki.
What?
That's...
That's a human!
He was tricking us!
Where's Houzuki?
You humans flattered us gods with your worship,
then tired of us and abandoned us.
Did you banish him as well?
Answer me.
What's that?
But even I might get cursed if I went up against a god.
Master, don't!
Beast, you forget your place.
Master Nyanko!
Natori!
Natsume, take this.
You should be able to undo the seal.
This is Houzuki?
Houzuki, please, wake up!
These are Houzuki's memories?
Is this a dream?
It's a smaller festival than I imagined, with fewer people.
Still, it's warm.
Thank you for your help, child of man.
Why do you make that face?
No.
Sharp.
As you suspect, my power is almost gone.
To the point where I couldn't even undo that seal.
Even if I had won the festival,
I lost the power to protect the mountains and forests long ago.
Then the festival is over?
Yes, it's over.
Then we have no more reason to visit this mountain.
If you wish, you may vanish here on this mountain,
but would you rather come with us?
Fuzuki...
Let us go, Lord Houzuki.
We shall protect you!
Let us go...
Master Natsume,
thank you very much.
Thank you...
Natsume!
That's a relief.
Natori...
Master.
You shouldn't make any sudden movements.
Lord Houzuki and the others...
Look.
That's Houzuki and Fuzuki, and their followers.
Pretty, isn't it?
I'm sure those two are the gods.
It's strange, isn't it?
The two groups, which looked like they hated each other,
are now shining the same color as they vanish into the distant sky.
Natsume.
I'm glad...
I did it.
Thank you, Natori.
I'm glad you came.
I couldn't have done it by myself.
I know... I couldn't have done it alone.
That's right.
That's right, Natsume.
Thus, the Moon Splitting Festival came to an end.
I was laid up for several days from exhaustion,
and was forced to listen to Master's endless complaints.
Jeez, what's wrong with you?
You get involved in something so stupid,
and then you get sick from exhaustion?
Master...
you're heavy.
Shaddup.
That's a spring breeze.
When my fever goes down,
I'll visit Natori sometime.
Oh, Takashi.
Are you okay now?
Yeah, I'm going for a walk.
Don't force yourself.
I won't.
There are still times when our different ways of thinking make me hesitate,
but it's because we're different that we can balance each other out.
The spirits of Misumi have decided
to continue protecting the shrine of Houzuki.
I see.
By settling the matter without banishing the god,
Natori's reputation among the other exorcists has improved yet again.
He's a smart guy.
Has your wound healed?
Yes. It was not a deep wound.
Good to hear.
It's possible the charm you drew had an effect.
Didn't you draw it on me first?
Does that charm work on logs, anyway?
That's true.
I retract my thanks, then.
He's here.
Thank you.
If you have anything you want to ask or say,
say them to him directly, later.
Yeah, that's right.
Sorry.
Been waiting long?
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
A Single Photo
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Next
Time On
What are you
looking at, Natsume?
A picture of my parents.
You've got a picture?
When I was little,
I tried as hard as I could
to forget about them,
but I'm okay now.
You keep that stoicism up,
and you'll become
a weakling.