Midterm Exams
Final Day: English Grammar
Hey, Natsume, Ishimura.
Come on, once the exam's over, the rest is easy.
Let's go somewhere.
Yeah. Fishing, maybe?
Sounds good.
What about you, Natsume?
Where do you want to go?
Let me see...
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Let me in on that.
Sasada...
I've got something cool.
What's this?
My dad's friend gave him these.
Let's all go together.
An art museum?
What?
This is really far away.
Oh come on, the exam's over!
Summer's come again.
Young Days
I'm back.
Oh, welcome back, Takashi.
Oh, this? It's from a class reunion.
From elementary school.
Yours?
I was just thinking about those days.
But I'm so old now!
Well, I guess everyone else is, too.
I miss being a kid.
Honestly, there's something
that's been bothering me a little.
Will you hear me out, Takashi?
Yes.
Once, a bunch of us good friends exchanged presents.
Everybody said that they would make something.
We were all so excited.
We all sang around in a circle,
and I ended up with
Kuriyama's handmade cookies.
Kuriyama got the pressed flower cards I made.
But... she looked so unhappy.
"I didn't want something like this!"
"You're no fair, Touko!"
"Give me back my cookies!"
I was so embarrassed.
I should've apologized.
I don't think she or anybody else
remembers it, though.
But I...
Kuriyama moved away, after that.
I've always wanted to see her again.
It's not that I want to talk about what happened.
I just think that if I saw that she was doing well,
this thing that's been bothering me would just vanish.
I was a bit jealous.
I don't have any good memories of my childhood.
Stupid!
What's so great about going to an art museum?
Nobody asked you to come.
Actually, I think Sasada said
there was a good ramen place nearby.
Ramen?
Ramen? Ramen? Ramen?
Don't sneak into my bag again.
I'm coming!
You just said you weren't!
I'm going, I'm going, I'm going! I'm going!
I'm not taking you.
Ra... ramen...
I'm going.
Stay here and watch the house!
No way!
I'm going!
Now my days are full of fun.
Ramen!
I'm going!
It's quiet.
Summer's here.
I can hold my breath for ten minutes!
That's useless!
It's not useless!
But I guess it doesn't matter.
Anyway, I heard you found something cool?
I found a big bug.
Being invisible is honestly really useless.
Humans just walk past me.
Just like the seasons.
Was that summer, too?
There was one person...
who could see me.
It's really pretty.
Yeah.
Let me see.
Hey, you'll get in trouble.
I'll be fine.
Nobody's watching.
What are you going to do with that branch?
Just toss it.
You suck.
How arrogant! How rude!
Those insensitive lower organisms
can't even sense a noble being like me!
Idiot! Nose hair!
What a crappy day.
There has to be something that could cheer me up.
Hey, the liar's coming.
You're right, the liar's here!
If you get close to him, you'll turn into a liar too!
You totally will!
Get lost!
Shoo-shoo!
Mocking their companions at such a young age.
How ugly.
Get lost!
What?
I didn't do anything!
Maybe that rock came from the sky.
That's the kind of lie you'd tell, isn't it?
Right?
Noisy brats.
Right, Natsume?
Come on, say something!
What?
Bugs!
That was wonderful!
I think... he looked right at me...
No.
Nobody can see me.
Humans can't see spirits.
You really can—
What a rude kid!
I won't forget this!
For every day after that, I chased him,
lied in ambush,
and scared him.
Wait, wait!
He always ran away.
That was all, but...
it was kind of fun.
Now then, where is he today?
Hey, he transferred, didn't he?
Yeah, I heard he's creepy.
He tells weird lies.
Lies?
He says he can see monsters just to get attention.
I heard he doesn't have any parents
and nobody wants him, so he keeps transferring.
That's why he's always alone.
He's always alone.
Just because he can see us.
Mommy!
Be careful.
I made an elephant today!
Wow.
And I did a handstand!
You got scared! You were scared, weren't you?
Why?
That's the first time he's spoken to me.
Why do you care about me?
Are you bored?
Bored?
What...
D-Don't be stupid!
I just happened to be passing by.
Somebody as important as me
has lots of stuff to do!
I don't care about somebody like you.
You don't?
Okay.
What's wrong with him?
How rude!
Nose hair!
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Look at that! It's so pretty!
Yeah, it's beautiful!
I used to live around here.
Shut up about the ramen.
What's wrong, Natsume?
You're spacing out.
What, are you hungry, too?
No, it's nothing.
My relatives passed me from one house to another.
So I don't remember exactly where I was.
But that...
I'm back.
I'm the one with the problem.
Anyway, I need you to take him next week.
That was the deal!
Jeez...
Oh, you're back.
Um... you, well... well...
You'll be living at my brother's house
starting next week.
My kid's got college exams this year.
And... oh, right.
I'll give you this coat.
It might be a bit big, but that's no problem.
Right?
Don't think badly of me.
For, well, everything.
It's kind of dusty.
And just when we'd finally spoken.
I didn't mean to say that.
I don't like this.
Why do I have to be nice to some human kid?
Tomorrow, I'll scare him like always.
That's right.
If I scare him, he might talk to me again.
Where'd you get that coat?
He's here!
My uncle gave it to me.
I see.
All right, now!
Um, well...
Oww...
I'm sorry.
I'm soaked!
What was that for?
Shoot! I didn't mean to do that.
I-I'm sorry!
I just...
Get lost.
Get lost!
What did I do to you?
Why do I...
I hate you all!
That was last day he took this path.
It felt like he was taking
the long way around to school.
I don't think he'll listen to me anymore.
He won't see me anymore.
But still...
The Shikadome Happiness Buddha
He's alone again.
Oh, it's a kitty.
Come here.
You smell kind of nice.
He looks so kind...
He's warm.
I want to stay by him forever.
It must be nice to be you.
I want to be alone, too.
I want to live by myself.
I'm a spirit, so I don't understand humans.
But it's sad to be alone.
I know that.
If nothing else, I know that.
A few days ago, he was taken far away.
Let's go.
Who's that woman?
Her lips and nails are bright red.
And that man's eyes keep shifting around.
I'll take him.
We have a kid your age.
Don't sweat it. You'll get used to it soon.
Right, Mommy?
That's right.
We're a fun family.
After that...
I never saw him again.
So what if I'm alone?
It's much better to be alone.
Why do those humans always
want to be with each other?
What pretty flowers!
Let me see.
What?
What's wrong?
I don't know. Something touched my hand.
Oh, no. That's scary!
Enough of this.
What about you?
Just how long am I supposed to
take care of your mother?!
Come on, don't say that.
What?
I'm sick of this.
Sick of this?
What an ugly, twisted face.
I really hate humans.
Why don't you just take care of her?
I wish they'd all just disappear.
I hate them!
I hate them all!
Those ugly things that only think about themselves...
I wish they'd all disappear!
I heard it's dangerous to go under that tree.
I don't know everything,
but something scary's supposed to happen.
Wait!
Oww...
Shut up.
Oww!
A cat!
I hate cats!
Get lost!
I don't think anymore.
I don't think at all.
Time has stopped for me.
What's he doing now?
With his kind smile, and his sad wish...
Is he smiling?
Good.
You're still here.
I don't know how many seasons it's been,
but I've never forgotten.
I've always remembered.
It was bothering me.
We said goodbye in such a strange way.
I'm glad you're all right.
Back then, I could only get mad at others,
but now, I think I understand your kindness.
I'm sure he's met another kind soul...
if he can smile like that.
I remember this smell.
My name is Natsume Takashi.
Would you tell me your name?
Welcome home!
I'm back, too.
I'm home.
Welcome back.
You met her, huh?
Yeah, what about you?
Did you have fun?
Yes.
I'm glad.
I had one, too.
What? You want to make a stop somewhere?
Um, there's somebody I want to find.
It's an old friend,
but I don't know if I can see them.
Go have fun.
We'll just head home.
That's right.
See you.
Bye!
Hey, hey!
Have a good time!
Bye!
I understand now.
If there's somebody you want to see,
then you're not alone anymore.
There are demons who remember
my grandfather here in this house?
The Thing Lurking in the Storeroom
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Yeah, they all came because they remembered him.
My grandfather was never able to see demons.
Some people see them even if they don't want to.