Face forward and run.
I painted the lights in the sky
with these numb hands to brighten your future.
Cut through it with your hands.
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run.
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Your fingertips were painted in an adult's color.
Embarrassed, you hid them.
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side.
Hey, even now we're always lost,
and I remember the words I said that day:
"I'd paint the future with the color of you."
Face forward and run.
I painted the lights in the sky
with these numb hands to brighten your future.
Cut through it with your hands.
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run.
Teacher! Teacher!
Natsume is telling lies again!
There's no way a woman could be peeking at him through the window.
Right?
Yeah.
We're up on the third floor!
What?
A dream about my past?
Natsume.
I'm sorry.
We don't usually get so much snow.
You tired?
You've got something going on at night, don't you?
You big perv.
Is something bothering you?
I'm fine.
I'm happy every day, honestly.
You're exaggerating.
What a liar.
See ya!
What are you doing, Master Nyanko?
Exactly what it looks like!
I'm teasing this dog.
Fun! Fun! Fun!
Master, you had better be careful, or you'll sl—
Master!
You oka—
And you're supposed to be a cat!
Don't laugh, dumbass!
I've told you I'm not a cat!
Ah, my hip!
Melting into Spring
Which herb is supposed to be good for hips?
You don't even know that?
This is all your fault, too!
My fault?
Come to think of it, I've never been here before.
This place is called Shiba-no-Hara.
Two guardian deities used to watch over this forest.
But now, there's only one.
It's a nice place. There's not a single footprint.
Stop it, dummy!
My... My hip!
If I waste any more time with this idiot, it'll get dark!
The herb! Where's that herb?!
It's been a long time since I played in the snow.
A demon?
Oh, you can see me?
Very well.
I need a vessel to contain me!
Are you okay, Natsume?
Yeah, but...
Damn! I entered the wrong one!
Oh well, at least I can move about in a physical form now.
A-Are you sure?
To create a vessel for me out of mere snow...
I'm impressed, human.
I am Gen.
I dwell within that stone statue.
I require assistance.
For what?
Just until this vessel melts.
If you refuse...
My curse shall be upon your family for three generations!
Nasty thing.
Natsume, can I eat the snow cone?
M-My mistake!
Please help me!
I'll hear you out at least, I guess.
Exterminate an evil spirit?
Yes. Far to the west exists the Demon-Sealing Tree.
However, its seal was broken and the evil spirit inside released.
It is a wicked thing that spreads dark spiritual power,
causing trees and grass to wither and men's hearts to fall into madness.
It cannot be left alone.
I must seal it, without fail.
What is this aura?
Gen, do you have any companions?
There used to be another statue beside yours, right?
Those were pleasant days.
We did everything together...
protected the forest, watched the rain and lightning, the moon and flowers...
But she... Sui was shattered into tiny pieces.
And I was left alone in Shiba-no-Hara.
Alone...
Lord Gen, have you lost interest in this place?
I never will.
Because we'll always be together.
Gen's dream flowed into me.
I'm sure that was Sui.
Sui, broken into pieces by that evil spirit...
Now, Gen...
You'll melt if you cry too much.
We can't let that evil spirit go, Gen.
I have a lot of things I want to protect here too.
Takashi!
Breakfast!
Coming!
The Demon-Sealing Tree?
Pretty sure it's in Forest Park.
I think, anyway.
Oh, they cut that tree down to make room to widen the road.
Seriously? That's pretty spooky.
There's rumors that the plants nearby started to wither because of an evil spirit!
What do you think, Natsume?
S-Sure...
As if, it's because of acid rain.
Welcome back, Master Natsume.
Who are you?
Gen?
I'm mostly accustomed to my snow rabbit vessel.
It seems I can even return to something like my true form for a time.
I was cleaning your yard both to train myself and to show my gratitude.
I see. Thank you.
Cleaning is rather enjoyable.
Work up a sweat and you'll melt.
Let him.
If he melts, we're rid of him.
Peel this, would you?
We promised to help him.
You're still such a pushover.
Sweet!
It's very sweet!
You two get along well.
What makes you think that?
Because of the orange, and your snowball fight.
Master Nyanko!
Natsume!
That was—
Now you've gone and humiliated me!
I am a noble being, I don't frolic in snow!
How are you noble?
And wasn't your hip hurt?
Seeing you two...
I am reminded of Sui.
Gen, the Demon-Sealing Tree was cut down, but I found where it was.
Want to go?
Yes.
I hated the humans who only seemed to make selfish wishes.
Sui felt the same, however...
A long time ago, we heard a human say that if you saw
a tricolored rainbow your wish would come true.
Sui called it ridiculous, and laughed.
But whenever she saw a rainbow, her voice would be sad as she noted that it was not tricolored.
"I wonder if their wishes came true."
Despite that, Sui...
Gen, the one who destroyed Sui...
The truth is...
Hey, Natsume!
What is this?
It's that way!
Follow the trail!
I can feel something from that rundown house.
Gen!
The air is stale.
Don't inhale too deeply, or you won't last!
Curse you, humans.
You will suffer!
It's dangerous!
Get back!
Master Natsume, this is Sui.
Sui became an evil spirit!
So I'm going to seal her myself.
Sui, let's go home.
Together.
Gen!
That can't be Sui.
What's going on, Gen?
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Sui and I were built as a pair.
We resided in the statues in Shiba-no-Hara, purifying the forest and exorcising evil energy.
One day, after the humans had a string of very poor harvests,
they came and begged us to make their land fertile.
But we were gods of purification, and could not do such things.
We asked passing spirits if they knew of any methods, but none did.
Eventually, Sui and I took some of our own life force and sent it to their village.
But even then we could not enrich the fields.
In the end, the accursed humans blamed their failed harvests on us.
Stop!
Please stop!
Sui cried out to the humans, expressing her love and desire for their happiness.
But even then, our voices failed to reach them.
Lord Gen!
Why would they do this?
We spent so many years of our lives wishing for their happiness, protecting them...
Curse you, humans!
I hate you!
I detest you!
I despise you!
Sui became an evil spirit and attacked the village. But it all came to an end when the humans sealed her.
I couldn't protect her.
I couldn't protect Sui from the humans, nor her heart from loathing.
That's why the very least I can do is end her existence as an evil spirit myself... I must...
Gen.
Gen?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Are you looking for the snow rabbit?
It was so cute. I put in the freezer.
It's warm out today.
It looked lonely sitting there all alone, so I made another one.
It didn't turn out great, though.
No...
That night, Gen slept right next to the little snow bunny.
But because it was just a little bunny made of snow, it melted by morning.
The unseasonably long rain continued, and I felt that Sui was hiding herself behind it.
I-Is that you, Sui?
Gen?
S-Stop it!
I am home!
Where were you, Master?
Gen...
Stay back, Natsume!
He's almost turned into an evil spirit!
He's been alone too long; his feelings of hatred and sadness have grown.
He seems to be doing his best to contain it.
No way.
Paper, bring me paper.
I heard once... about the Book of Friends.
Master Natsume, please take my name.
Do you realize what you'd be doing, Gen?
If your name is written inside, it becomes your life itself!
So...
Burn it!
If I turn into something evil, then...
No more.
I can't take it anymore.
I don't want to be alone.
Gen! Don't give up!
You're not alone!
You have Sui!
You have us!
I told you I'd help!
I told you I'd do something!
But I can't do anything.
All I could do was protect the forest.
No, I couldn't even do that.
I'm useless, I can't protect anyone!
You're not useless!
You... You cleaned my garden!
You protected me from Sui!
You might not like humans, but I like you.
And I'm sure Sui, who tried to wish upon a rainbow...
Master!
Master Natsume!
We saw a suspicious shadow in the north woods!
Just letting you know!
So give us a cookie, please!
He's gotten far lighter than he was.
If he melts away,
Gen will remain alone.
Master Natsume!
Sui!
Gen!
Wait!
Let her go, Natsume!
Her evil thoughts have manifested as heat!
No!
If I let her go here...
Lord Gen.
This feeling...
Are these are Sui's memories?
Lord Gen, there was no tricolored rainbow, was there?
I hope it rains again soon.
Don't say that, Sui.
The rain is cold.
I don't mind it.
I'm not cold.
Because... Because you're here.
I'm cold!
Let her go, Natsume!
Your body can't take it!
Can't you tell?
Gen's spiritual power is nearly gone!
If you bring them together, he might be destroyed!
Let her go!
You'll die!
If you refuse...
Master, please don't!
Gen!
I was cold too, Sui.
So very cold.
So let's go home.
Let's go home together.
And someday, when your heart has healed, we'll wait for the rainbow together once more.
I was happy too, Sui.
Because you were with me.
Lord Gen...
Good-bye, Master Natsume.
Good-bye.
I wonder if they'll be able to make it back.
They'll be fine.
Spirits aren't the wimpy weaklings you think they are.
True.
But I'm not as good at farewells as you may think.
I want to cherish the things I feel are worth treasuring.
I never understand the things you say.
By the way, where are we going now?
Shiba-no-Hara.
I thought I'd plant some flowers.
I can't show them a rainbow, but I can plant seeds.
Humans love flowers.
I'm sure spirits do, too.
Because flowers speak of the coming of spring.
Hey, just a little longer. I just want you to listen a little longer.
Hey, just a little longer. I just want to be selfish a little longer.
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed like it would disappear.
So could you say something?
With just you here,
my world changed.
Just look at the monotonous scenery,
it looks so vivid.
We were walking with our hands held,
and before we knew it, we had to seperate.
"Do you think we're a good match?"
Was what I asked the sky.
An Exorcism Amid the Steaming Springs
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
I'm going to a hot spring with Natori.
I won a pair of tickets to one.
But why take me?
Because you're the only one who'll see the same scenery as me.
I'm going too, Natsume!
Eggs! Eggs!
Hot spring eggs!
Woohoo!