------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
It's been a long time, Natsume Takashi.
Matoba.
You snuck in here just like a cat or a demon would.
No. One of your demons dragged me here.
Oh? My apologies, then.
Still, it's good timing.
I was just thinking that I wanted to talk to you.
Come to think of it, is your cat not with you?
The Eastern
Forest
Natsume disappeared?
Yeah. I caught some delicious minnows,
and I wanted to show him, but he's not at his home or that "school" of his.
You don't think it's those eastern monkeys that showed up a while ago, do you?
I don't know, but Misuzu said there've been spirit hunts around that exorcist's mansion again.
Are they after the Book of Friends to put a stop to that?
It's possible.
What's wrong with you guys?
W-Well...
You're from the east!
What do you want?
Where is this Natsume kid?
Return our friend!
What are you talking about?
Didn't you take Natsume?
We did take him to the eastern forest, since he refused to give us the Book of Friends.
But instead, he worked with the exorcist and kidnapped our friend!
That's why we don't like human children.
Where is Natsume?
Where is our friend?
You know what will happen if you hide him from us!
Buddha save us!
I don't really have any reason to save them, but I don't like when people misunderstand Natsume.
What do you mean?
Natsume would never ally with an exorcist, and he'd never kidnap a demon.
She's right.
Begone.
I am hungry.
We're saved.
Saved...
The monkey masks of the eastern forest were led by a powerful spirit named Rokka.
For them to kidnap a human child...
What are you going to do?
You wanna know?
Lord Natsume is in a difficult situation, though.
He should just let the Book of Friends go.
He'd never give that up.
Then you should take it from him, and make it so he can only live in the world of humans.
If you truly care for him, that is.
That's not what he wants.
You think so?
I don't understand the hearts of humans.
Have some tea.
Don't worry.
It's not poisoned.
You seem to dislike me quit a bit.
Let's get to the point.
What do you want?
I've told you before.
You interest me.
Would you like to join the Matoba clan, Natsume Takashi?
After what happened, I did my research on you.
I'm told you were passed around between relatives after your parents died.
You were even sent to an orphanage once.
Some of the other children were scared by your behavior, and you left soon after.
It must've been difficult.
You can see them, but others can't.
That's how you've lived...
Join me, and you'll never worry about that again.
Everybody here understands.
No one here will be scared or put off.
You'll be spared the pain of living with those who do not understand—
I refuse.
Why is that?
It's true that it's been hard at times, but I've met many kind people.
Like the Fujiwaras, who you live with now?
But do they really know and accept everything about you?
Do the two of them know what you see—
They've got nothing to do with you!
I'm leaving.
I'm not done talking to you.
I don't understand.
I would've thought the cold treatment you received from others as a child
would lead you to be entranced by demons, and thus side with them,
but that doesn't seem to be the reason.
Why do you side with the demons?
They deceive humans and betray them.
You've experienced that, I'm sure.
And not just once or twice.
You're right.
But... that's not all.
Some aren't like that...
Have you met many like that?
What's strange about that?
That's the same thing you said a moment ago.
Do you perhaps believe that demons and people are the same?
Master!
Natsume.
Oh, there you are, kitty.
Is this the place?
Yeah.
I told you not to get any ideas, exorcist.
You seem quite thirsty for blood.
You'll be quite useful.
We're leaving.
My bag.
He found it?
Let's go, Natsume.
Yeah.
Master Nyanko!
You're quite dangerous.
The demons have already stolen away your heart.
It's time to wake up.
No!
Move.
That demon is only with you because he can gain from doing so.
He does not like you, nor does he feel any kind of affection for you.
Move.
Throw them in the prison.
Don't let them go any further.
Protect the master.
They're here!
Split up!
We have no intention of leaving this forest until we've captured your master, Rokka.
We won't give you our master.
Why? Why do you obsess over this forest?
Why our master?
What have we done to you humans?
It's simple.
We've heard this forest is ruled peacefully by this Rokka.
Our leader is interested in such a powerful demon.
Just for that?
Looks like the exorcists are involved.
Who are you?
Where is my master, Lord Natsume?
Natsume?
Wanna fight?
Natsume Reiko...
For now, we thank you.
If you hadn't come, they would've hunted us down.
So?
Where is this Rokka?
He is hiding somewhere safe.
Guess he doesn't care about you.
W-What?
If you mock our master, we'll make you pay!
But I'm right, aren't I?
Your master sent you to steal the Book of Friends while he hid in the forest.
No!
Our master isn't like that.
He is asleep.
Asleep?
Then what about the book?
W-Well...
It might be best if we met this Rokka.
I'm hungry.
I'm bored.
Natsume, bring me a drink!
Bring me squid!
Don't be stupid, Master.
I'm bored.
I was planning on taking down that stupid Matoba kid!
Instead, you got knocked out.
What?
And who protects their own bodyguard?!
I protected the Book of Friends.
You just happened to be there.
What?!
I don't understand.
You don't intend to control or lead spirits,
so what good does it do you to have the Book of Friends?
Even the wimp knows better than you.
That's why I told you to give it to me.
What good does giving it to the white pig do?
Give it to our master!
What?
I'm gonna put a letter in you and toss you into the ocean!
Oh, there he is.
You're...
Where's the Book of Friends?
Where is our friend you stole?
Hey! I'm in here! In here!
I know that voice!
We'll make you pay for throwing him in there, kid!
Wait!
I didn't put him in there!
Are you trying to lie to us, human child?
That's...
No, that's—
Look inside! The Book of Friends might be in there!
No, wait!
Don't touch it!
That's even more suspicious!
Do it now!
Yeah!
Wait.
The Book of Friends isn't in there.
I looked myself.
Is that true?
Yeah.
More importantly, get out of here.
The guards will come.
It's Matoba's servants.
Get going!
B-But...
I came to see how you were doing.
Oh? It seems you have the power to command demons.
Command them?
If not you, then who called for them?
The cat?
Or...
Nobody had to call for them.
My friends can get in here easily!
Oww!
What?
What are you doing?
Punishing him.
A demon shouldn't come into a human's home uninvited.
Please stop.
He's got nothing to do with this.
It's a lesson for the rest of them.
He doesn't seem like he's useful for anything, and he has an attitude problem.
Stop it.
Please.
Stop it, please!
Jeez.
You can tell me to stop holding back if you want, Natsume.
Master.
When you go easy on the ones with just a bit of power,
they give you more trouble than anybody else.
Just a bit?
That's not very nice.
I am the leader of the Matoba clan...
Not happening!
He got away again.
You saved me, Master.
I was just protecting the Book of Friends.
Thank you,
for not telling your friends about the book.
I don't understand it.
To humans, demons are like mist.
Why protect them?
I couldn't help it.
I just acted on instinct.
It's really important to me.
We'll be going, then.
Run before Matoba and the others come.
It's a simple seal.
Your friends can undo it.
Natsume.
Yeah.
Natsume,
you may be right.
If I brought the Book of Friends to our master, they might be sad.
There they are.
You guys.
Human child!
You tried to hand us over to the Matobas!
No, I never...
He's right.
I hate to say it, but he protected me.
Don't be fooled!
Then why doesn't he give us the Book of Friends?
If he wants to help us, he should give it to us.
No, it's...
Give it to us.
Enough of this.
Master Nyanko!
Stop it!
Natsume!
Oww...
Give it to us.
You bring disaster.
You bring disaster!
You bring disaster to us...
Wait...
How much tragedy must you bring to us?
Begone!
No, it's not like that!
Begone, human!
Human, begone!
Yeah, we're leaving.
He and the Book of Friends are going back where they belong.
I'm his bodyguard, after all.
Come after him again, and you'll have to deal with me, not the exorcist.
Come whenever you like.
That's enough.
Misuzu.
Master!
My, my...
What are you all doing?
You know better than this.
I'll ask you to forgive their rudeness.
Who are you?
I am the ruler of this forest.
My name is Rokka.
Rokka was weakened by the seals that the exorcist placed on the forest.
He fell into a deep slumber in the depths of the forest, guarded by the monkey masks.
They must have felt scared.
They sought the Book of Friends to give them power.
How foolish.
Then, the Book of Friends...
Your coming undid a small number of the seals, and I was able to awaken.
I would never seek to steal it.
Natsume!
Come on, monkeys!
Bring   it on!
Don't you know that he is the savior of Yatsubara?
Savior! Savior!
The middle-class demons?
Natsume!
Hinoe?
Natsume, don't worry.
Don't worry! Don't worry!
Let's do this, Natsume!
I will now drink the water of life and become a powerful god to save you!
Now, let us fight!
Fight, fight!
Bring it!
Stop!
Don't make things any worse!
Are you sure it was right to let them go?
Even without the Book of Friends, we could've asked them to help restore the forest.
They're doing more than enough.
Can't you tell?
Oh my...
It bothers me how my master refuses to call my name.
Thank you, Misuzu.
You could have just given them the Book of Friends.
I could...
if they would return the names in my place.
The deal is that I get it.
He's too powerful.
Even all our servant demons together might not be able to hurt him.
If the ruler of the forest was that Rokka demon, then there may be nothing more we can use here.
You're going to abandon the forest?
Yes, but there are many ways to do things.
Thus, the eastern forest was liberated,
and the matter settled.
Okay, then we meet at eight.
Don't be late.
Yeah.
Natusme, you need to eat liver before you come.
If you're missing school from anemia, it means you need more iron.
Yeah.
Iron, iron, liver, liver.
What's wrong?
Is there another problem?
No.
There was something I forgot to say.
I'm sorry we made you act strangely in front of your friends.
Natsume, it's ready!
I'll be right there.
You have demons who will help you even without the Book of Friends, don't you?
Yeah.
My friends.
Will I ever be able to talk about this feeling?
Okay, I'll be back.
You have to promise me, okay?
If you'll be late, you have to call us!
Yes, sorry.
You're making too big a deal out of it.
He's in high school now, so it's fine to stay out a bit late, right?
Nope!
Okay, pinky swear.
Lie and you have to swallow a hundred needles!
This frustrating happiness...
You don't think you should wear some more layers?
Shigeru used to wear this.
Is it too big?
It's fine.
It's very warm.
Don't worry.
You'll get bigger soon.
By this time next year...
Days so warm it almost makes you dizzy.
It may be time for me to stop looking away and know for real.
Natsume.
You're late.
Since I've decided to protect the Book of Friends...
Since I decided to live accepting what I hear and see...
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
The Little Ones
Next
Time On
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Tama, Nora, Chibi...
What, are you going
to keep a cat or something?
You've already got me!
I brought them home...
But these are
really boring names.
You think of some, too!
Like this one.
Oh no, the
scrub brush moved!