Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Your fingertips were painted in an adult's color
Embarrassed, you hid them
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
Beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
Hey, even now we're always lost,
And I remember the words I said that day:
"I'd paint the future with the color of you."
Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Snowboarding, man, snowboarding!
What are you talking about?
There's nothing better than viewing
snowcapped mountains while on a train!
The sky goes on forever today...
Dude, you sound like you're sixty.
Natsume! What do you think?
Sorry, what?
You okay?
You don't look so good.
Do you have a fever or something?
I'm okay.
I guess I haven't been getting enough sleep.
Really? Don't run yourself ragged.
What's up?
Over there.
Do you see something?
What's with him?
Freaky!
If they can't see him...
He must be a demon.
Tree of Promise
This jelly from Nanatsuji is pretty good.
I should've tried it sooner.
Slides right down the throat.
So, what'd it say?
About 37 degrees.
You should rest, then.
I took some medicine.
I should be fine if I take it easy.
I don't want to worry Touko-san.
Jeez, when're you going to realize?
Realize what?
Never mind.
Anyway, somebody's been
peeping at us for a while.
Peeping?
I saw him earlier.
What a klutz.
I'll ask you once more.
Why are you following me?
Is it the Book of Friends?
Maybe he doesn't understand human speech.
Not a chance.
We're can't help if you
don't speak up! Say something!
O-Okay. I'm sorry.
So?
Don't you remember me?
I'm not Reiko-san.
You're not?
She died a long time ago.
Looks like he's paralyzed from the shock.
Man, what a pain in the butt.
I see.
So you're Natsume Reiko-san's grandchild?
Yeah.
He's whiny and gloomy,
but he's got power.
Excuse me?
That's great.
All right, I'll return your name now.
That which protects me,
reveal thy name.
What's going on?
He doesn't seem to have a page.
So there was never a contract?
Excuse me...
No, the Book of Friends reacted to him.
He must have a contract.
Was it lost then?
Well... knowing Reiko, that's quite possible.
Excuse me...
Um, excuse me, I don't think
my name will be in there.
It's probably somewhere else.
Somewhere else?
Why'd you wait to speak up?
She tied your page to a tree branch?
Yes.
She said she'd give it back after 50 years.
Why'd she do something like that?
That's just like her.
Still, you actually waited for 50 years.
You're really foolish, you know.
I'm sorry, Nyanko-sensei-san.
Don't call me that, it gives me
the creeps! Drop the "san."
I'm sorry.
Call me "Esteemed Sensei!"
Natsume?
You haven't tried getting it back until now?
Reiko-san said that if I tried anything,
the seas would swell and destroy the world.
So, basically, she pranked you.
Well, seeing how he is,
I kind of understand why she'd do it.
I'm sorry.
So... where's this tree that your contract's tied to?
I'm pretty sure it's around here somewhere...
Pretty sure?
It bothered me to see it, so I stayed away.
Does that mean...
Right, for fifty years.
The whole time?
You left it alone for half a century?
I'm sorry.
In fifty years, the tree would have grown.
The branch it's on must be pretty high up now.
We'll never find it.
But I have to!
Still, just how many trees
are there in this forest?
But...
Just give it up.
If you're safe, then so is the contract.
You can leave it be.
So give up.
Yeah, you're right. Okay, then.
That's good! Okay, let's go home
and eat some yummy jelly!
Are you sure about this?
Well...
Let's keep at it a bit longer.
You might remember something while we're looking.
Okay?
Natsume-san...
Jeez, you are the biggest softie to ever live.
Well, you're on your own!
Tanuma?
Oh, hey... You looking for something?
Sorry, man.
It's okay.
Maybe it is impossible.
We just started looking, didn't we?
If only I could see them too.
He's a nice looking boy.
I see.
I'm glad it's not a girl.
I'd be pretty upset.
Oh, speaking of girls—
Hey, you guys!
Spread out!
We're just doing what you said!
There's no point in searching the same area!
Go look somewhere else, then!
I thought the more the merrier...
but we're probably bothering you.
Stop staying in one place and spread out!
Class rep's orders!
Nah, I appreciate it.
It probably doesn't even occur to them that they're
looking for something that belongs to a demon.
Sasada!
You found it?!
A beehive!
Take this seriously!
What's wrong?
Nothing... it's just everyone...
Are you surprised they're all helping?
I'd heard that humans treat each other coldly.
From who?
Natsume Reiko-san.
Oh, there you are!
Hinoe?
I'm here to lend a hand.
This ugly little thing asked me to help out.
What?!
I told her some idiots were doing idiotic things,
so we should go call them idiots!
Thanks.
Don't thank me so sincerely!
Gives me the creeps!
So!
Was it you who Reiko cursed?
I wouldn't say that...
But that's the truth of it, isn't it?
Don't tease him too much.
Can you search this area?
Huh?
Natsume?
What's wrong, Natsume?
Natsume!
Well, we should go.
Sorry to worry you.
I'm sorry we didn't notice something was wrong.
Thank you.
But his fever's down and he took some medicine,
so I think a good rest will cure him.
I'll keep him home from school tomorrow, to be safe.
Okay, I'll let the teacher know.
If only he'd said something...
Yeah.
Natsume's Book Of Friends
That's what you get for pushing yourself, you idiot.
I'm sorry.
It's my fault.
I made you all look for something you'll never find.
Natsume-san shouldn't have agreed to look for it.
Don't you dare say that again.
Why do you think Natsume overworked himself?
Because I—
Wrong.
I'm telling you to try to
understand how Natsume's feels.
Don't say things that undermine
what he's done for you.
If you say that again, I'll be very unhappy.
He's not great at relating to people,
yet when the time comes, he pushes himself.
He's just like Reiko in that way...
What a boring day.
Excuse me.
Um, I seem to be lost.
Could you tell me how to get out of the forest?
A human?
And it can see me?
This'll be fun.
Come, I'll show you the way.
Thanks, you're a lifesaver.
If it was a boy, I'd push him into a swamp,
but this girl is quite beautiful.
I'll abandon her deep
in the woods and make her cry.
Is something wrong?
No, not at all.
Why's a girl like you in this forest anyway?
Well, I beat up these three boys, and then I thought
I'd hide in the forest until things cooled down.
Three boys?
I don't want to cause trouble
for the family I'm staying with.
People are so hard to deal with,
I don't like them much...
Do you prefer monsters and demons, then?
I don't like creepy things.
I bet.
No human alive likes spirits.
Um... aren't we there yet?
We've got a long way to go.
You know, you're wearing pretty flashy
clothes for hanging out in a forest.
Are you possibly...
S-She's playing with me?
What a brat! I should just eat her now, and then...!
That's right! I am!
Head's up!
Get away from me!
Why are they attacking you?
They're always after my hairpin!
It's precious to me!
They got it...
Does it mean that much to you?
What's she doing?
What are you doing?
You're crazy!
Why is she doing this?
Found it!
Hey!
You're a demon, right?
If you want this back,
lead me out of this forest.
Okay?
What a mean, mean, mean, mean girl...
Just thinking about it makes me fall in love all over again.
No matter how many times I hear that story,
I'll never understand why you fall in love there.
It's too complicated for an ugly,
fat-faced cat to comprehend.
What?! What did you just call me?!
So Reiko-san...
Oh, you're awake?
She dove into the lake to get your hairpin?
Yes. Crazy, right?
You said Reiko threatened that if you took the contract,
the seas would swell and destroy the world, right?
Yes.
You live in the forest, so why'd
she use the sea as a threat?
I think it's because I said I wanted to see it.
The sea?
Yes.
Yes. I've known nothing
but the forest my whole life.
But I heard about it from a migrating bird,
and it said that the sea was wonderful.
So what'd Reiko say to that?
If you want to see it so bad, just go.
It's a bit far away, but not that far, you know.
I can't leave the forest.
Why's that?
Those born in the forest aren't able to leave.
That'd make sense if there was
a barrier or something,
but I've never heard of not being able to leave
a place just because you were born there.
B-But I can't, honest!
You have no idea what the sea is like, do you?
Well, Reiko-san told me all about it once.
She did?
Yes.
It's blue, and infinitely vast.
How there are always waves;
the way the sun and moon shine on its surface...
That long-necked dinosaurs live in it...
And all the islands are actually secret bases,
so if you're lucky, you can see UFOs taking off...
Incredible, right?
Yeah... it got pretty amazing in the middle there...
I can imagine the look on Reiko's
face as she told that story.
I was tricked... wasn't I?
So she took your name
and tied it to a tree branch, huh?
But Reiko didn't take
the names of spirits who obeyed her.
She must've really wanted to mess with him.
How mean...
You think so?
Do you think Reiko-san was a horrible person?
Once my fever goes down,
let's look for your name again.
I think once we find that page,
we'll understand what she was trying to do.
Natsume-san...
Thank goodness,
your fever has gone down.
Don't push yourself so hard, Takashi-kun.
I won't.. I'm sorry I worried you.
Well, I'm going shopping.
You should keep resting.
Yes, Ma'am.
Are you going out?
Take care.
Hinoe found it?
Yes!
So, we'd like to take you all to the forest.
Don't do it.
I see.
Stay put!
Okay, let's go, Kirinoha.
What did I just say?
Touko told you to rest!
The contract's up there.
Thanks.
Don't blame me if this ends badly!
Kirinoha, climb the tree and take it.
M-Me?
I can't climb a tree this tall.
If you don't mind your contract getting
ripped up, you can ask that brute Hinoe.
What'd you say?! I dare you to say that again, Madara!
You ugly, fat-faced cat!
Go on.
Huh? I don't have to say it again!
Hey, stop blowing smoke at me.
Keep at it!
There it is! I found it!
You found it?
Wow, it's sparkling.
That's...!
The sea.
Oh, I get it...
I can see the sea!
Fifty years is nothing for a spirit.
Reiko knew that when she made that promise.
Give me a break, Reiko was no romantic...
Reiko-san...
Reiko...
Thank you!
Kirinoha, I'll return your name now.
Please take it.
It's kind of sad, though, that it's all over.
It's not.
What you saw, what you felt...
Those things will never disappear.
You'll always remember them.
I'm back!
T-Touko-san's home!
How are you feeling, Takashi-kun?
Just like everyone you've met.
Hey, just a little longer
I just want you to listen a little longer
I just want to be selfish a little longer
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed like it would disappear
So could you say something?
With just you here,
My world changed
Just look at the monotonous scenery,
It looks so vivid
We were walking with our hands held,
And before we knew it, we had to separate
"Do you think we're a good match?"
Was what I asked the sky
The Maiden's Circle
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
I found a strange circle in a field of flowers.
I bet it's a crop circle for communicating with aliens!
Ah, you there!
Natsume-kun?
Oh no, I...
What's your name?
I'm Taki Tooru from Class 5!