Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Your fingertips were painted in an adult's color
Embarrassed, you hid them
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
Beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
Hey, even now we're always lost,
And I remember the words I said that day:
"I'd paint the future with the color of you."
Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Oh dear, oh dear...
They're tiny.
Oh my.
We can't cross this.
We're in trouble...
We can't go forward!
Why don't they just go around it?
Look!
A pathway has opened!
We're saved!
Let us press on! Let us press on!
Press on, press on...
I can't believe how little they are.
That shrine's about the size for carrying ashes.
We must hasten to deliver
the Lord to where his body awaits.
Yes, quickly now!
An Exorcism Amid
the Steaming Springs
What? Is that paper stuck in the door?
Oh, they're paper dolls?
Did you just get back?
Master Nyanko?
Where've you been?
On patrol!
I'm sweeping for spirits who look like
they might lure you away to eat you.
Hey, what's that?
Dunno...
They were stuck in the door.
Natsume!
What's doing this?
What could drag me with such incredible—
Ow, ow, ow...
Natsume?
Natori!
It's been a while.
I put a spell on those paper dolls,
and I left them in your door so they'd
tell me when you returned, but...
I guess you didn't catch on in time.
Got a bit tangled there, did you?
So this was your doing?
Natori works as an exorcist on the side.
Well, no sense in talking out here.
But in the public eye...
Hey, isn't that...
Hm? No way!
Care to join me for a cup of tea?
He's Natori Shuuichi, a famous actor.
To be honest, he kind of annoys me.
Have any free time during your next break?
No.
Do you like hot springs?
I guess.
Would you like to accompany me to a hot spring?
What?
I won a pair of tickets to one in a contest
from some fragrances I bought.
You bought fragrances...
and there was a contest?
But why ask me?
Wouldn't you rather invite a girl?
My agency would never allow it.
This guy never fails to come off as shady as hell.
Want me to eat him, Natsume?
Don't you have any guy friends?
No.
You're the only one who'll see
the same scenery as me.
I've never been on a trip...
Before I forget...
The inn allows pets.
Are you serious?!
Go, Natsume!
Eggs! Eggs!
Hot spring eggs! Natsume!
I'll clear it with your family.
A trip? That sounds wonderful!
I give you my word that
I'll take good care of Natsume.
My word, what breathtaking flowers!
I see no reason not to leave him
in the care of such a responsible friend.
Do you really think so?
I'll pick him up tomorrow.
Takashi always makes sacrifices for us,
I'm glad to let him have some fun.
Enjoy yourself, okay?
I'll... bring back souvenirs.
So began our two-day, one-night hot
spring trip for two, plus one pet...
It's really secluded.
It's perfect for traveling incognito.
It can't be all that secret with all
the buses and trains we've ridden.
I'm hungry. Get walking, you big slowpokes.
Tired?
A bit, but the fresh air is nice.
Yeah, sure is.
Thank you for coming all this way.
I need to make a call.
I forgot to tell my manager
about this little excursion.
I'll show you to your room.
Oh, thanks.
Man, I'm beat... but it feels good.
It's nice to get away now and then.
Did that sound... come from the closet?
I'm back, Natsume.
No one's in the springs right now.
Care to take a dip?
Sounds good.
Let's go, Master.
Hey... he's gone.
Reserved Bath
This is bliss...
Hey.
Why'd the cat get in the bath before us?
I've told you a thousand times I'm not a cat!
What are you, then? A pig or a cat?!
Don't call me a pig either!
I'm not a pig or a cat!
How dare you speak to my noble self that way!
Fine, cat.
What?!
Relax, fellas... It's all good.
Don't dirty the water, Master.
I won't. I'm actually made of clay, you know.
Doesn't it feel great?
Yes.
I'm glad you like it.
Natori has a newt-shaped mark
that others are unable to see.
I don't know if I should be looking.
I don't particularly like the demons,
but I'm pretty sure he...
hates them.
What's wrong, Natsume?
Too much time in the bath?
What are you, a schoolgirl?
There are things that make any human lightheaded.
And you freaked me out by showing
up out of nowhere like that.
Hiiragi, I told you not to scare Natsume.
My apologies.
I forgot how weak he was.
Hiiragi is one of the demons that Natori commands.
Sorry about that.
If you don't dry off, you'll catch a cold.
Don't worry about her, Natsume.
Demons can't catch colds.
Right, of course...
That's good.
Did you skip the milk to save room for beer?
It's great stuff!
If only you were an adult;
I'd share some with you.
You know...
What's wrong?
Over there...
Hanging from the ceiling...
It's gone.
Did you see something?
I... guess not.
Must've been my imagination...
I'll take a walk around the inn.
Head back to your room, it's warmer there.
But...
Don't worry about me, I'll be right back.
Let's go, Hiiragi.
As you wish.
I shouldn't have said anything,
he invited me here to relax...
Natsume, keep an eye on the Book of Friends.
I am. It's right here.
Come to think of it,
I haven't told Natori about it.
Don't.
He'll take it.
It's not right to assume
he'd do something like that.
Maybe, but I know what you'd think:
"I wonder if he's only being nice to me
because he's after the book."
That's true...
I wouldn't like that.
You're such a pessimist.
Is there a rat in that closet or something?
Nothing's there.
Except a pot.
A pot?
In the closet?
Yeah, it's got a lid on it.
And there's some half-finished writing on it.
Something's off about it...
Come to think of it, it was about right here...
This is the spot where you saw
that person hanging.
That pot's the perfect size to store a head.
I'll pretend I didn't see it.
You're not going to open it? What a waste.
What if there are delicious leeks stored inside?
Is that supposed to be
an irresistible temptation?
Why are we talking about leeks?
Natori!
I'm back.
Did something happen?
No.
Okay.
Why don't we grab dinner, then?
Maybe I'll add in some sashimi for the kitty.
Promise?!
I have to be honest,
something's been bothering me.
It's just been glimpses and sounds so far,
so I don't think we're in danger.
It was really nice of you to invite me on this trip,
so I'd hate to spoil it by telling you...
You're right.
For today, at least, let's forget about demons.
Sure.
All right, let's eat.
Okay.
Natsume's Book Of Friends
I'm tired...
Can't stay awake...
Are things going well
with your current guardians?
Yes, they're very kind to me.
Really now?
Yeah.
If you ever get tired of lying,
you can come to me.
You think I'm lying?
Perhaps we could be together
without pretenses.
I'm a liar?
No...
When I was a kid, everyone called me a liar
because I said I could see demons.
Liar...
Lately that's been haunting my dreams.
But I wasn't lying.
I wasn't...
Liar!
Are you okay, Natsume?
You were having a nightmare.
Huh...
You're right.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry...
How humiliating... letting a dream make me cry...
"Liar," huh?
Did the lid just come off?
Master! Natori!
That pot opened!
What pot? Oh, the one with the leeks?
I don't think it has leeks...
I'm pretty sure I just heard the lid pop off.
So it's in here?
How can you tell the lid came off without looking?
I felt a nasty presence flow out...
All right.
It was here all along...
It's empty.
Perhaps what was inside got away.
I'll look downstairs.
Come on, Master!
Roger!
You know, that pot had a tight seal on it,
so I wasn't all that concerned.
But it must be a pretty strong one
to break the seal on its own.
Plus, that seal was pretty new.
It was?
Well, let's go.
Yeah.
Is she bleeding?
Yup, thought so, that's a big one.
Natsume, mind if I eat it?
Natsume?
The holder of the Book of Friends?!
Please, I beg you, return my name!
I am called Sumie.
I have lived in this place for untold years.
But humans came and decided I was a hindrance...
So, I was sealed in that pot.
I despise humans.
Return my name...
Once you do, I will have no cause to remain here.
If you return my name, I shall depart
and abscond to the mountains.
I implore you...
Do you swear not to hurt the people in this inn?
If you do, I'll force you to leave
by the power of the Book of Friends.
I swear, Natsume.
I will go, you need not command me.
All right.
I'm sorry to have bound your name for so long.
Natsume—
Thanks to you, I have nothing left to fear.
You are nothing like Reiko.
You are soft.
You will not suffer,
for I shall swallow you whole!
Natsume!
Natori!
They fled?
No matter.
I've been waiting for a good meal.
They will not escape this inn.
This way, toward the room at the end of the hall!
Damn it, I was tricked.
I thought I understood demons.
Why do I always...
Hey, Natori, you scoundrel.
Tell us what you've got up your sleeve.
Don't play games with us.
He has a plan?
Hiiragi?
What is this room?
I prepared it after our bath.
On the mountain behind this inn lives
a demon who harms humans,
which another exorcist nearly sealed...
Another exorcist?
However, it took refuge in this inn
before he could finish.
That's why I came here.
You mean...
You know Natsume hates killing spirits, so you lied to him.
All to have him help you.
That's right.
I'm sorry.
I'm so used to deceiving people...
If I could've known you'd enjoy it so much,
I would've explained everything from the start.
I'm sorry, Natsume.
It's okay, there are things I haven't told you.
So it seems.
The two of us have spent so much of our lives telling lies...
I'll help you.
This happened because of my own weakness.
Thank you.
We'll seal the demon with
a barrier around the whole room.
Hiiragi, you should leave.
You too, Master.
What? Way to spoil my fun.
I'll eat you...
I'll devour you...
He's in here?
I'll gobble you up!
I'll devour each and every one of you!
I'm trapped!
Just kidding!
She slipped free!
Natori!
I will not allow you to harm Natsume.
Who is this?
I've been looking for you, Natsume.
Have you forgotten me?
You made a bridge for me.
Three eyes...
The demon I saw the other day?
I shall purify her.
Where'd you come across
a huge spirit like that?
I just gave him a hand.
I guess he was returning the favor.
You just can't help getting involved with them.
Because...
Because, I can see them.
When they cry, get in trouble,
break promises and repay favors...
The Master...
The Master merely came to confirm
that the spirit had been properly sealed.
I'm sure he thought it would be
a good opportunity to talk with you as well.
There are many things I'd like to talk about...
With him, and the Fujiwaras, too...
But the words won't come out...
I'm afraid to say them out loud.
I've been afraid for so long,
it's become normal.
But someday, I'll find the courage to speak;
to show the people I trust my true heart.
I'm back.
Sorry to get you mixed up in this.
Don't be. I had fun.
Still want to hang out with me again, after all this?
Of course.
I guess it's time for us to go.
Yeah.
So ended my first trip to a hot spring.
I headed for home feeling slightly uneasy,
carrying many happy memories,
and many words to say.
Where should I start?
Hey, just a little longer
I just want you to listen a little longer
I just want to be selfish a little longer
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed like it would disappear
So could you say something?
With just you here,
My world changed
Just look at the monotonous scenery,
It looks so vivid
We were walking with our hands held,
And before we knew it, we had to separate
"Do you think we're a good match?"
Was what I asked the sky
A Chick Hatches
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
A single egg is left in a bird's nest in the yard.
Master, you're free, help me out.
What, you want me to keep it warm?
Hey, did it grow?!
Whoa, did it just hatch?!
I'll be taking that newborn Tatsumi bird, boy.