------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
I return this to you, Amana.
Please accept it.
Natsume!
Nanatsujiya's selling some good sweets―
You gave back another name, didn't you?!
You're heavy.
Get off me, Master Nyanko.
Deal with it.
I'd freeze my cute little paws off.
Are you planning to hibernate?
You've put on a lot of fat.
What?!
I dare you to say that again.
They're pecking at a kitten!
Hey, get lost!
Are you okay?
It's bleeding...
Is it dead?
This kitten... doesn't have a head!
What?
No limbs, either.
The furball moved!
Natsume, that's a demon!
Throw it away! Throw it away and run!
It moved! It moved!
The Little Ones
You always get involved with demons!
I thought it was a kitten.
But a furball demon sure is strange.
There are some weird ones out there.
Aren't you basically a furball?
What?!
Huh?
Master Nyanko, something's wrong with you.
What's this? Go! Get lost!
It's kind of cute.
What? Do you like anything as long as it's cute and fluffy?
Don't let its looks deceive you!
Come here.
See!
Blood!
Stop it!
You'll just hurt yourself more!
Stop!
I'm not trying to hurt you.
It's okay, just calm down!
Throw it out now, while you still can.
Hey. I told you to get rid of it.
What are you going to do?
You're awake?
That hurt.
This is human medicine, so I don't know if it'll work, but...
Once you've rested here tonight, go home.
You're such a softie.
You get yourself in so much trouble.
Does it hurt?
Yeah, but it's not a bad wound.
Idiot. It's because of the poison.
Poison?
From that furry thing.
Plenty of demons are bad for humans.
Open yourself up too much, and you're bound to get hurt.
Good morning!
Good morning.
Did he oversleep?
That's unusual.
Thanks.
Here, don't forget your lunch.
Hey, what happened to your hand?
I cut it.
Oh, do be careful.
Your bandage is falling off.
Here, that'll do it.
Thank you.
Don't let those crows get you now.
As I had encountered kindness, I wanted to be kind myself.
Bye.
Stay safe.
I wanted to be able to do something, just like others had done for me.
He was pretty cute.
Did he follow me?
I can't have him at school.
It multiplied!
Natsume, you're lively today.
He was around here.
Hey, furball!
Are you here, furball?
There you are.
What? It's just Master Nyanko's tail?
What are you doing, idiot?
Was that your tail during class?
What are you talking about?
The furball multiplied?
You sure you weren't just spacing out?
Maybe...
It really multiplied!
What an ingrate!
You stabbed me!
Which is the one from yesterday!
L-Look at them all!
I'm back.
Snacks!
Jeez...
They don't seem like bad demons, but they're poisonous,
and I'd be worried if there were more of them around the school.
What?
A thief?
A demon after the Book of Friends?
Where is the ring? My ring?
Ring?
Give it back...
Give it back!
Natsume!
Master!
Give it back, thief.
Where is my ring?
Ring?
What are you talking about?
When I came here yesterday, I dropped a very important ring.
A ring with a blue stone.
I looked, but it wasn't here.
Did you steal it, kid?
I don't know what you're talking about!
Or I can burn your house down, with you in it, and search the ashes.
Wait!
I really don't know!
Did you really drop it here?
I had it until I came here.
Natsume!
I'm sorry you lost it, but it was your fault for dropping it!
First you barge into my room, and now you're calling me a thief
Talk about ungrateful!
I'll look for it, so come back!
Three days.
I'll give you three days.
If you still cannot return it, I'll find it, even if I have to burn this whole house down.
Damn it, this is humiliating!
Natsume, get this off me!
Fine.
Ow, ow, ow...
Stop it! Stop!
You're pulling my fur out!
It's not working.
Maybe it won't come off until we return the ring?
What?!
Find that ring with the blue stone right away!
It's no use. I can't find it anywhere.
Think it happened back then?
Back then?
When that furball was bouncing around?
Maybe it got tangled in his hair!
It's the only possibility!
Then if we find that furball...
So, this is the demon you're looking for?
Just so we're clear, that's really what it looks like.
If I can't find the ring he took in three days,
a demon will burn my house down.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Come to Yatsuhara then.
It's dangerous here.
Dangerous! Dangerous!
I've always thought the world of humans was a difficult place for you.
Why don't you come to Yatsuhara and live a fun life with us?
Fun!
Thank you, but my life right now is very dear to me.
Hey, isn't that a Karu?
Hinoe? You know them?
Something like this.
Yes, that's certainly a Karu.
They're legendary demons that migrate like birds.
You saw them around here?
Yeah.
That's bad... they move in packs.
They're very hungry, and they devour everything in their path.
Oh, my! That's scary!
I'll get rid of those wimps.
Look at you, Madara!
T-This is, well...
It's complicated!
How are you going to get rid of them with that seal on you?
That's right.
A pig-cat without his flashlight is just a short-legged, fat-faced pig-cat!
What?!
Anyway, with Madara like that, you should stay away from them.
Maybe, but...
I'm sorry, but I can't do this alone.
Help me with this, please.
When you're honest...
it's so creepy!
Leave it to us, Natsume!
The Group
That Earns
Favors
From
Natsume
Leave it to us! Leave us to it!
We'll help you instead of that flashless pig-cat!
Don't let them fool you, Natsume!
Hinoe!
It's obvious what they're after.
Stop it!
Furball!
Have you seen this?
Natsume, leave the rest to us.
But...
Nasty things come out in this area at night.
Okay.
Good luck.
I'm home.
Welcome back, Takashi!
What were you doing out?
I was looking for Master Nyanko in Yatsuhara.
Your clothes are dirty.
Go take a bath.
Okay.
I won't let her burn this house down.
But still...
how can I find such a small demon?
Go to bed.
You'll wear yourself out.
Are you okay?
Don't lump me in with you.
Maybe I should get a little fatter, like you.
Idiot!
I'm not fat!
I'm round!
Go to sleep.
Blood!
Natsume?
It's not blood...
Berries?
What are those doing here?
These are Akazasa berries.
They're famous among spirits as an antidote for poison.
Antidote?
What's that doing here?
Was it him?
Furball, are you here?
Maybe I missed him.
If that furball came back, does that mean...
it didn't go back to its pack,
and found these berries for me instead?
I should've given him a name.
How about Harry?
'Cause he's so hairy.
No way.
He's a fluffy ball, so I'll call him Fluffball.
Too obvious!
That name is entirely too obvious!
Yum.
To begin with, if you're going to name something—
Hey!
Goodnight, Master.
I'm still talking!
He's here!
Good...
So you were the one who brought the antidote.
Thank you.
It doesn't hurt now.
Fluffball, would you come here?
I think you have a ring tangled in your hair.
I have to give it back to its owner.
You might not want me to touch you, but I need it.
Come here, Fluffball.
Come here.
Master Natsume!
Big trouble!
Fluffball!
Calm down, Fluffball!
I need to follow him!
Master Natsume!
He's the one with the ring!
It's no good.
It's too dark to see.
That fluffball guy seems to like you.
If you wait in your room, won't it come back?
No, it won't!
He came to apologize, but just ended up hurting Natsume again!
By the way, what did you want?
Oh, right.
All the little demons got scared from the rumors of the Karu,
and are on their way to Yatsuhara!
They believed the rumors that they eat spirits, and are planning to chase them out!
But that little guy earlier seemed smaller than the rumor.
Since they move around all the time, not many people know what they really look like.
According to the little demons, the Karu are gathering near Nanatsumori Forest!
Nanatsumori, got it!
Natsume, we're almost here.
Right!
Fluffball, are you here?
Fluffball?
It's dangerous here!
Tell your friends not to go near Yatsuhara!
The demons are coming!
Let's leave for now, Natsume.
Yeah, but the ring...
Fluffball!
Is that you, Fluffball?
They're heading away from Yatsuhara.
I guess they heard you.
Thank you, Fluffball.
Goodbye.
They're very strange demons, but the way they depart is beautiful.
Yeah.
Thank you, guys.
I found the ring.
If I give it to Amana—
I knew it.
Amana...
Good timing.
Here's your ring—
I knew it.
I knew you had it!
No, I found it just like I said.
You stole it, human.
You will suffer!
You really are ungrateful.
You're getting too cocky.
Master!
That's...
Natsume!
Give him back!
I'm going to crush him!
Did you go mad when you lost your treasure?
Your ring was returned, and he kept his promise.
Go home and cool your head!
Natsume!
What was that dragon?
It wasn't a dragon.
It was the Karu.
Master...
Can you see him?
Right there.
That's Fluffball.
He's the only one with red berry juice on his fur.
I don't know if Fluffball lead them, or if it was just a whim of the Karu.
But that morning, the great, beautiful dragon they saw
was the only thing the demons talked about.
You always go overboard.
Is the wound from the Karu okay now?
Sorry.
I need to say thanks to the others, too, somehow.
Idiot.
Thank me first.
You're my bodyguard, aren't you?
But I was surprised.
Even those little Karu could face a demon like Amana once they were together.
I guess that's just how the weak ones survive.
Yeah.
I don't have much power, and I'm trying to get stronger.
Master Natsume!
Hey, guys.
But if I'm not afraid of sharing my heart...
Master Natsume, here's a present for you.
If I believe I'm not alone...
It's supposedly an antidote for demon poison.
They're called Akazasa Berries.
Antidote! Antidote!
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
Next
Time On
Time on
Stand—In
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Why did I answer then?
You tricked an innocent girl!
Silence! I...
You just couldn't let her
be alone, could you?
I decided I would face her feelings no matter what words it took.
Let's go see the answer
with our own eyes.