------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
Takashi!
Would you mind opening the door?
Touko?
Okay!
Sorry, I lost my key.
You finished shopping pretty quickly.
Huh?
The door's not locked.
Nobody's here?
Shoot!
I think a demon just tried to come in!
It's inside!
Is it after the Book of Friends?
Master!
Master Nyanko!
You're Natsume Takashi, correct?
Where is the Book of friends?
So you're the one who faked Touko's voice?
Now, give me the Book of Friends.
If you don't, I'll break your arms.
Oww!
No way.
I won't give you the Book of Friends!
Give it to me!
I said... that hurt!
Rose
Jam
Hey Natsume, open this jam for me.
Master!
Who's the dirty hobo?
Poke. Poke, poke.
Damn it... I can't believe I lost to a child.
But if I can't win by force...
I thought this might happen,
so I prepared a bribe!
Please hear me out.
Stand—In
I told you, you can't have the Book of Friends.
Then, could you loan it to me?
No.
Really, loans?
What are you going to do with it?
You know of a spirit called Karikami, right?
I've never met it, but supposedly
its name is written in the Book of Friends.
I want you to summon it.
You've never met it?
What will you do with it when you summon it?
This.
Paper?
It looks really old.
It's all crinkled.
That's correct.
It looks like it'd fall apart if you touched it, right?
And?
Paradise
Feeling
Don't you get it, fool?
If you don't, I'll tell you!
It's a long story, so prepare yourself!
Sake!
I'm very skilled at imitating voices.
My name, Yobiko, comes from my ability to make humans hear my voices.
I used to live in an old tree just off the path in Kariyama.
One day, a human girl started to walk by my tree.
She came almost every day.
I wasn't interested in humans.
It was just a whim.
I was a little worried, since it was dangerous for a human to be so deep in the mountains.
So I followed her.
There was an old shrine
where she met a man with gentle eyes.
She looked so happy...
So happy when she talked to him.
It seemed the two of them were having a tryst there.
Even though all they did was meet and talk casually.
But it was every single day...
So were you spyin' on them, huh?
No!
I was watching to make sure they didn't damage the shrine!
Master.
I'm sorry.
Would you continue?
They seemed deeply in love,
but the man was busy.
He would talk for a short while, and then leave.
The woman would stare in the direction he had gone for a long time,
and then, when the sun set, she would finally head back down.
I didn't want her to be attacked by a beast or a snake,
so I kept them away.
Don't laugh!
It was every day!
Think about all the extra work I had to do!
Sorry.
I thought it was kind of you.
No, not at all.
Enough!
Call Karikami already!
Sorry, but I can't.
What?
You liar!
I've heard that any spirit with its name in the Book of Friends
cannot resist its owner's orders!
Only if you know their face and name.
My grandmother was the one who gathered the names.
They're all demons I've never met.
What?!
I can't believe it won't help me.
You drank my sake, too...
I didn't drink any.
I'm going to stay here tonight.
I need to decide what to do.
Hey!
He's already asleep.
I don't want him sleeping in my room.
Some spirits have to spend a lot of their strength just to come into human lands.
What a pain.
Every time I meet a seemingly carefree demon like this,
they always have their own baggage...
With that on my mind, I had a dream that night.
Takahiko! Takahiko!
The voice that called out was so sad,
Takahiko!
that I'm sure the spirit who heard it...
Takashi!
It's time for breakfast!
Go on and eat.
So, what did you decide to do?
I've no choice.
I will find Karikami myself.
I still haven't asked.
Why do you want to meet this Karikami?
Scythe It's Natsume!
Scythe He looks delicious!
Scythe Natsume of the Book of Friends!
You've got guts, wimp!
Thank you, Yobiko.
You saved me.
I see.
Natsume?
What are you doing?!
Where are you going?!
I don't know what Karikami looks like,
but I know where it's supposed to live.
If Natsume of the Book of Friends shows up,
it may come to demand its name back!
You're going to use me as bait?
I've heard that Karikami is a gentle spirit.
I promise to protect you and return you home safely.
So please help me, Lord Natsume!
Then...
tell me why.
Karikami is a spirit with the power to restore old paper.
Maybe it can help me open this letter
that has been sealed shut by rain.
Remember the tryst I spoke of yesterday?
One day, the man stopped coming.
But the woman still came every day and waited for him.
It bothered me, so I went to the man's house.
From what the two of them had said,
I knew that the man was the eldest son of an influential family in town.
The bride and groom look wonderful.
Yes, and she's from a very wealthy family.
Now the family's declining fortunes will be saved.
As the center of the family, we need him to do this.
I knew that humans and spirits could never be together,
but I never thought that two humans who loved each other so much
couldn't be together either.
Takahiko?
But the woman kept waiting every day, never knowing the truth.
Every single day, she would call his name.
Takahiko...
Yes?
Takahiko?
Are you there?
Don't open it, Youko.
Well, I'm a little sick.
I can't be near you right now.
Sick?
Are you all right?
What kind of illness is it?
Well...
I-I'm almost better.
Really?
Yes.
I didn't want you to catch it, so...
I see...  I see.
I'm so glad.
Yobiko?
What I should have done then
was say goodbye in his place.
But she sounded so happy when she laughed...
Thank you, Takahiko,
for coming to see me,
but I don't want you getting sick again,
so go home.
No, I'm fine.
But...
In exchange...
Tomorrow.
Come here tomorrow.
And tomorrow
became the day after, and then another day...
I went to see her again and again.
Takahiko, you must be tired.
Not at all.
It looks like it's going to rain.
Please, go home first.
No, you go home first.
No, you first.
No, you go first.
You're so stubborn.
What? You're the stubborn one!
Oh my!
The weather is beautiful today.
Yes, you're right.
The leaves have almost finished turning.
Aren't you cold?
No, I'm fine.
I had a dream last night.
It was a good dream.
I was looking out at the sea from a tiny window.
The sea was calm and shining.
Where was this?
Well you see,
I don't remember ever being there,
but for some reason,
it felt so much like home, that I almost cried.
It was like I'd come home...
A peaceful, wonderful feeling.
I want to go.
It was a dream.
Even if it was a dream.
You sound like a child.
That's not the Takahiko I know.
What?
T-That's not true at all!
Now you're getting mad.
That's even sillier.
Is it silly?
Yes.
Very.
The more I met with her,
the more she laughed,
the more guilt I felt.
It's strange.
Ever since I stopped being able to see your face and only hear your voice,
I feel like we've become closer.
But even just a little...
I want to see your face.
I want to see you!
I'm sorry, Youko.
For the sake of his family, he stopped being able to come here.
I am an impostor who pretended to be him.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
What I did was horrible.
I couldn't stand to see her hurt.
That was the end.
I was terrified of both my sin and of her,
and I never went back to the old tree or the shrine.
I left on a journey.
After what humans would call a "long time" had passed,
I returned to the shrine once more.
There I found a letter,
with a rock placed on it to keep the wind from blowing it away.
It might have nothing to do with me,
but it might be something that Youko left for me.
If it is...
It might be for Takahiko,
or for me.
And that's...
If the words are those of rage and hate,
I've no choice but to accept them.
I've run for so long...
but I can never forget.
If I can, I'd like to read this letter.
I see.
After hearing all that,
I want to know what it says, too.
Jeez...
Where'd that dot-browed demon go?
Hey, Karikami!
Hey!
Is Karikami here?
I've come to return your name!
That idiot!
He's doing it again!
Hey, Karikami!
I've got something important to return to you!
Please come out!
Who's there?
Hey, Natsume!
Master Nyanko?
Jeez!
Are you trying to get eaten by a demon, wandering off like that?
Is it true that you'll return my name?
You have a slightly different aura than Reiko.
Natsume Reiko is my grandmother.
I inherited the Book of Friends from her.
I'm sorry to have kept you bound for so long.
I'll return your name.
Also, I have a request.
A request?
If you have the Book of Friends, you could simply order me.
It is my request.
I want you to restore this letter.
Please.
You seem odd, but in a different way than Reiko.
Very well.
I shall grant your wish in exchange for returning my name.
That which shields me, reveal thy name.
I return this to you, Karikami.
Please accept it.
I've been defeated.
I can't believe I lost to a human.
Call me whenever you'd like.
If that paper ever gets old, I shall restore it.
This?
I have received my name.
Now it is my turn.
The paper is restored. The paper is restored.
Take good care of this.
Thank you, Lord Karikami.
Thank you, Lord Natsume.
Hey, Dot-brow!
Show your appreciation with booze!
Thank you.
You were a big help.
It's a woman's writing.
But this feeling...
The one who wrote it is no longer in this world.
Yes.
That's right.
The color of that paper...
The voice, the smile, and everything that still remains in his heart...
it was all a long time ago.
Humans live such short lives.
And Reiko...
is gone, isn't she?
This?
Nah.
I'd be an old woman by then!
Natsume!
Master?
You're spacing out.
Don't blame me if you almost get eaten again.
Are you going to return to your journey?
No, I'm going back to my old tree.
The shrine's still there.
I want to watch over and protect it.
I see.
Was the letter for you?
Can I ask what it said?
Well, I'm embarrassed to say this, but I can't read human words.
Would you read it for me, Lord Natsume?
What does it say, Lord Natsume?
That she's sad?
That she'll never forgive me?
No.
Thank you,
for telling me
the truth.
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
To You, From Bygone Days
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Next
Time On
What was he looking at?
Natsume?
You've got something weird on you.
I've met this demon before.
I said goodbye before I could ask.
There was this weird kid there.
I wonder if he's happy right now.