------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
Look, you did it again.
You keep focusing on your rook.
That leaves you open diagonally, so...
Oh, I see.
And that ends the match.
That's why you—
Natsume?
The Other Side
Of The Glass
Check.
Hold on, that was...
You're the one who said no take backs.
I didn't think you were this bad, Kitamoto.
Shut up.
Don't get so cocky from just one win.
Now, how about that corn on the cob you promised?
Maybe I'll have a candy apple instead.
Why do I have to feed you, too?
Natsume, how'd it go?
Natsume's the one who won, right?
Oh, I won.
Thanks to you.
Hold up, Natsume. You got Tanuma to coach you?
Yeah. Just a little.
You should come with us.
Kitamoto's gonna treat us.
Since when?!
I didn't know they had a festival this time of year.
A tiny one.
They're celebrating some Lord Omibashira, right?
No, Lord Omibashira's the one they do on the mountain.
Here you go. Two fresh ears.
Here's your coaching fee.
Thanks.
You buy your own.
You're so stingy!
He's revived.
Really?
Then we must hurry...
What are these voices?
And this presence...
Take this.
What's this?
Hey, what are you doing?
That's a human.
My mistake.
But it's rare for a human to have such strong spiritual powers.
Excellent.
Let's take him back with us.
Wait, I'm...
Hey, Natsume!
Natsume!
Where are you?
Natsume, are you okay?
Natsume, what's wrong?
Are you not feeling well?
Yeah, just a bit lightheaded.
Sorry, Kitamoto.
Even though you were nice enough to buy this for me.
Aw, forget it.
If you're not feeling well, let's go home.
Natsume?
Tanuma.
Did you...
It's nothing.
Did something happen?
Oh, nah.
No, it's nothing.
Thank you.
Sorry. Let's go.
Fun, warm days.
So much so that it feels like the smallest thing
I'm back.
Welcome back.
could snatch it all away.
I'm back.
Master Nyanko?
He's out again?
He left the window open, too.
I thought if I asked him about that flyer,
he might know something.
A bottle?
What?
Where'd that come from?
Did a demon throw it?
I'm back!
Festivals are the best!
Is that Natsume still out?
He's always wandering around...
Whatever.
I'll have a drink while I wait.
Master!
Am I hearing things?
Master Nyanko!
Is that you, Natsume?
Where are you?
Here! Right here!
Master Nyanko!
Here?
Natsume's a NatsuMiller!
No, here!
What happened here?
I was sucked into this.
Open it!
It looks like a spirit's bottle.
It's stuck!
Just a second.
It's tougher than it looks.
Stop!
What about this?
Don't!
You'll crush me too!
Well?
It's hot, Master.
Yep, you're doomed.
No way!
I like it. It keeps you from wandering around.
Well, I absolutely hate it!
At this rate, the humans are gonna call the police, and it'll be a big deal!
Seems like the bottle can only be opened by its owner.
If I try to force it open, it could put your life in danger.
Where's the owner, then?
Hell if I know!
We'll have to search for him.
Search for him?
But what do I do until then?
And Tohko knows I'm back!
At this rate...
Takashi!
It's almost time for dinner.
Right.
I would guess that humans can't hear you right now.
Or see you, either.
No way...
Then...
They're having pork cutlets tonight.
You owe me big for this, Natsume.
This isn't normally something I'm good at,
but since I'm a powerful demon...
W-What are you going to do?
What do you think?
What do I think?
I've never made that pose before,
so I don't really know,
but it's kind of creepy.
Let me see...
Perfect!
Is that what I look like?
Takashi!
Dinner's getting cold!
Okey-dokey!
I'll be right there!
Don't get so excited over dinner, Master!
Here I am.
Oh, my.
Where did you get that bottle?
Don't sweat it.
I mean, pay it no mind.
She really can't see me?
Will you get Shigeru a beer from the fridge?
Okey-dokey!
You don't need to talk like that!
You sound like a kid!
Don't do it, Master!
Don't even think about it!
Oh, my. You must've been hungry.
He's still a growing boy.
Yum!
I mean, this is good.
Please stop gulping it down.
Master...
It's a shame that there's no sake to go with the meal,
but it's a hundred times better than what I usually get.
Don't make things any worse!
Seconds.
No seconds!
Oh, my, that's rare.
Oh, and tomorrow we'll be a little late coming home.
'Zat so?
Is that so!
Is that so?
We just got a call...
an old acquaintance of ours passed away,
and we'll be helping with the funeral.
Here you go.
Wait, Master!
Wait for them to finish talking!
I'll make some gratin for tomorrow night's dinner.
Warm it up and eat it.
Sure.
Now then...
That was delicious.
I guess we're lucky that they'll be home late tomorrow.
I've gotta get out of here before then.
When will that gratin be ready tomorrow?
Before you worry about the gratin,
why not do something about me?
As is, I can't eat or use the bathroom—
You hungry?
No, not particularly.
I thought so.
There're no air holes in that bottle, either.
The inside of that bottle
is probably connected to the demon world.
Demons don't get hungry?
Some don't have to eat unless they realize they're hungry.
They're fundamentally different from humans.
It's late.
Sleep.
But...
Don't worry.
I'll think up a plan.
He may say that...
but can he really find the owner of the bottle?
We don't even know what kind of demon it is.
What's that sound?
Oh, good.
It got him.
Let's take him back.
This demon was from the festival!
Master!
I knew it.
I thought somebody would come to take it.
What?
The one in the bottle is my prey.
Let him out now.
This is a present for Lord Omibashira!
Don't interfere, beast!
Omibashira?
Let him out now.
He's a fast one.
You saved me, Master Nyanko.
Didn't get you out of the bottle, though.
That demon was talking about Lord Omibashira.
What about it?
Nishimura and the others were talking about it at the festival.
They said it had something to do with the mountain...
The mountain?
Which mountain?
And what does it have to do with it?
I didn't get that much information.
Why didn't you ask?!
If you ask them, they'd probably know.
Come to think of it, when you go to school,
they gave you something called a "boxed lunch", right?
I'll do it in exchange for that.
Will this really work?
What do you think?
We'll be late, Master.
Fried chicken, huh?
You can't eat it until lunch.
We'll be leaving around noon, too.
When you come home, make sure you eat and lock the doors.
Gotcha.
I mean, yes.
Okay, goodbye.
Lunch, lunch, I get a boxed lunch.
So many people all wearing the same outfits.
Don't dwell on that.
You just need to say hi.
Nothing more than that.
Just ask Nishimura what you need to, and then we go home.
I get it.
Morning.
That's a big yawn.
Nishimura.
Get over here.
Quit stalling.
Just get your ass over here.
Okay...
Master!
Tone it down!
And smile!
He goes on about every little thing...
Natsume, are you a bit mad—
Stop.
Sure!
I've just got one little question.
C'mere.
Natsume, you wanna go to the nurse's office?
What a pain.
Master, politely!
Be polite!
Omibashira?
Yup.
Where is it?
The mountain.
Where on the mountain?
Tell me what you know about it.
Dunno.
I really don't know the details.
Is he an idiot?
I told you not to say anything you don't have to!
Kitamoto might know.
Class 2-1
Omibashira?
Yeah.
Tell me what you know about it.
Dunno.
Master, calm down!
I really don't know the details.
But the girls were saying that there's something called Omibashira on the mountain.
Which girl would know?
Which female would know?
Female?
Stop worrying about the details.
I'm very annoyed right now.
Sorry.
I think... Sasada might.
She likes things like that.
Sasada?
Master, you've met her plenty of times.
Oh, her.
Master, calm down.
Don't do anything that will stand out!
Sasada.
Is Sasada Jun here?
Jun went to the library to return a book.
She returned the book and went to the science room to get some papers.
She went to the teacher's office to hand in those papers.
We'll by using those papers in the third years' class, so I had her take them there.
She went back to her class.
Natsume!
They said you were looking for me?
Master, be polite!
Be gentle!
What's wrong?
Oh yeah, this morning,
I saw a cat almost as ugly as yours!
It was so fat...
We need to talk.
Now?
Right now.
Wait!
Um...
Everybody in the class was watching...
Master, stop!
Let go of her hand!
I need to know right now.
What is Omibashira?
What's wrong, Master?
Um... Natsume?
You...
smell delicious.
Master!!
What does that mean?
Does "delicious" mean that...
That was yummy.
Jeez...
Even if I go back to normal,
how am I supposed to explain this?
More importantly, we need to talk about Omibashira.
You were just eating lunch!
Sasada said there's a legend
that somewhere on this mountain, there's a shrine sealing something called "Omibashira."
And people said that the shrine was a stone
that was destroyed during some recent construction.
So then, a demon that was sealed away has revived?
Probably.
That's...
"Lord Omibashira has revived.
Any who are weak and seek his protection are to come bearing an offering."
If the spirits are all talking about it,
then once his power returns, he'll be fairly strong.
We should stay away from him.
Then what happens to me?
That bottle doesn't belong to Omibashira.
It's Onizaru's.
If we can find him...
Oh, there you are.
Tanuma.
What's up with you?
Nishimura and Kitamoto said you were like a totally different person.
Nothing.
What's that bottle?
I'm not feeling well today, so I'm going home.
Bye, Tanuma.
Natsume?
You should stay away from the mountain, too.
Wait, Natsume.
What's in that bottle?
I suppose...
there's something very interesting in it.
Interesting?
You might not be able to see it, though.
You're not Natsume, are you?
What are you talking about?
Something's wrong with you, Tanuma.
Who are you?
Natsume wouldn't say that.
Where's Natsume?
Tanuma...
Are you a demon?
What are you?
Jeez...
I was just giving you a warning.
The sharp ones are always trouble.
Do you really want to know who I am?
No, Master!
Ponta!
You middle-aged cat!
Why did you get Tanuma involved?!
I didn't get him involved!
He involved himself!
Because you led him on!
What?
This only got complicated because you kept making a mess of things!
I'm going to roll you!
Roll, roll, roll!
It just looks like a cat playing with an empty bottle.
Is Natsume really in there?
Yeah.
No use. I can't see him.
I bet not.
By the way, he looks really pissed right now.
Is he mad?
I'm sure I don't need to tell you why.
Well, yeah.
But I can't hear what he's saying right now,
so it's up to me whether I help him or not.
Natsume would do the same if I were in his position.
No, Tanuma!
Don't!
If you want to complain,
you can do it when you get out of that bottle.
The more someone cares for me, the more scared I get.
Scared that someday, something terrible will happen.
Anyway, Master Nyan Nyan sure made a mess of things.
Sasada was passed out at her desk.
It didn't work because Natsume kept distracting me.
So what do we do?
We capture the bottle's owner, Onizaru.
We can just wait, and he'll—
Something's wrong here.
Is something here?
There you are!
Wait!
What? Is something here?
Tanuma, that's enough!
Stop!
Onizaru is after the bottle!
You need to leave it behind and go!
What is this presence?
Tanuma!
Tanuma, behind you!
What was that?
I got dizzy all of a sudden!
Natsume?
Natsume, where are you?
Natsume!
No way!
Can I feel anything?
I should be able to feel something...
This way!
Natsume!
This is...
What is this place?
There weren't any
stone steps like this behind the school.
I can see them.
The demons?
Why?
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
In The Valley of
Humans and Demons
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Next
Time On
Tanuma, don't do
anything stupid!
If something
happens to you...
I have to save Natsume.
I got Tanuma
caught up in this.
The window won't open!
Am I locked in?
I sense a
strange presence.
This might get bad!