Natsume Yuujinchou
San
Living through these meaningless days, I let out a sign
I've lost sight of my true self
Even if I strain my ears I can't hear your voice
So I keep walking trying to catch up
The things I couldn't tell you form into a chrysalis over time
Spreading wings, they take flight
The one, the one precious thing I'll never forget
Someday, that warm emotion
I'll do what little I can
Little by little, to get through to you
Tanuma was possessed by a demon.
And until we find all the pieces of the broken mirror,
it won't leave.
I was worried about leaving him alone,
so I decided to stay at his house.
Where's the priest?
My father's on a business trip again.
I see.
Hey, Tanuma kid.
Gimme a chestnut.
Right, right.
Hey.
How many mirror pieces did we get this afternoon?
This is all. Can you see it?
You're amazing.
I can just barely tell there's something there.
I see.
Hey, kid.
Be more careful with that.
And you be more careful with Tanuma!
That's right. Gimme back my chestnut!
I said, gimme back my chestnut!
I'd feel much better if I were the one who was possessed.
The mirror went into my eye!
I told you. It wants to become whole again.
The pieces will resonate with one another,
and demand that you pick them up.
When you find them all, this will end.
Reflection
Has this ever happened to you, Natsume?
What do you mean?
Having a demon ask you for something.
Don't get me started.
It happens all the time.
All the time?
Master Nyanko.
He's too nice.
He can't say no to anything a spirit asks him to do.
He ought to just tell them to buzz off.
But I can't help it.
I see.
Tanuma...
No, it's not him.
This is goodbye.
Don't come here any more, please.
This is the dream of the demon that's possessing Tanuma.
What do you mean?
Have I done something wrong?
Please, just don't come here anymore.
Why?
Goodbye.
Goodbye...
You were looking into my dream, weren't you?
Was that the friend you're looking for?
That demon seemed to be sick.
Can you heal him with that mirror?
That is a terrible disease...
Is there something... anything that can heal him?
Do you truly wish to heal him?
Yes.
Then, there is something.
Really?
Yes.
However, it won't be easy to get.
You must be tired.
You must be cold.
Just rest!
We'll warm you up.
We'll give you a hot bath,
and you can rest in our arms.
Why do you persevere?
You're not here to take our mirror, are you?
We won't let you.
We won't!
Fool.
It's not there.
You've been deceived.
Oh no!
The hated sun will rise!
Our mirror will appear!
Curse you!
Where are you?
Where did you go?
I found a way to cure your disease!
Huh?
Natsume?
Tanuma, are you okay?
Did it... happen again?
That sound was from the temple.
A thief... or not.
It was broken from the outside.
The forest raccoons like to play tricks at this time of year.
Natsume?
That way.
Hey!
If I knew what he could see,
I could at least understand what he's trying to do...
Do you want to see?
Can you do that?
I can lend you my eyes
in exchange for borrowing your body.
Do you want to see?
Yes.
What is this?
Natsume can see this?
Natsume?
The hammer wielding demon from school is in here.
Does Natsume see a world with stuff like this everywhere?
You can see it, Tanuma?
The demon lent me her eyes.
I found the mirror.
I'll break it and take it out.
I will not let a weakling like you take my mirror.
Don't get in my way.
Begone!
T-Tanuma?
Are you okay?
Tanuma!
Enough of this.
Don't show the demons to Tanuma.
I know you saved me, but don't put him through that!
You want the mirror, right?
Your friend's important to you, right?
Tanuma is my friend, too!
I won't let you do anything more to him!
Can't you possess me instead of Tanuma?
I'll help you look for the mirror,
so please, let Tanuma go.
He was the one who wanted to see spirits.
You never talk about them.
Because you don't need to, I suppose.
It's because you're so kind.
He knows that,
but he'll never understand unless you tell him.
He'll never understand something so important.
He's right beside you, but he doesn't understand.
My friend didn't tell me either.
He never told me...
that he was seriously ill.
He left me so that I wouldn't get sick, too.
I only heard the rumors on the wind.
Even if he had told me,
I couldn't have done anything.
But after my desperate search, I finally found it.
The mirror that can purge his illness.
All I have to do is find him.
I need to find the pieces of the mirror soon!
Or he'll...
I must find the mirror before it's too late.
I'm sorry, child of man.
Right now, it's all I can do to stay in his body.
Just a little longer.
Just a little longer...
That's Yatsuhara for you.
It's pretty sad that a weak demon like that could get onto the temple grounds.
Master Nyanko.
Where have you been?
We were in serious trouble.
I was watching to see who that hammer guy was.
But she got rid of it before I could help.
You should go to bed, Natsume.
I'll look after things.
I refuse to spend any more time on this.
We're finishing it tomorrow.
Right, Master.
But first, carry Tanuma to his bed.
W-What?
I need to clean up the broken window.
You owe me big time for this.
It's gonna take more than a meat bun from Nanatsujiya!
I'm gonna have to pay Tanuma for this.
Heavy!
He's too heavy.
Go on a diet!
Like me!
Get slim!
Morning.
Are you two okay?
Morning...
I guess not.
I don't really remember,
but I think something incredible came out of my mouth.
What did you eat?
No, not that kind.
Oh, yeah. Natsume, here.
I made this talisman based on some books I found in my house.
I don't know if it'll help,
but not being able to do anything bothers me.
I'm sorry it's not much, but I want you to take it.
Thank you, Taki.
Did you stay up all night making it?
N-No, I didn't go that far.
You get bags under your eyes really easily.
I hope I can get better at sewing soon...
I think the problem's your aesthetic sense, not your sewing.
If you're going to be mean,
I won't give you the one I made for people who are possessed.
S-Sorry... wait, you made one for me, too?
Here you go.
Thank—
It's kind of creepy.
There's nothing I could do.
That's how it said to make it.
I had to make it in the middle of the night, so I was pretty creeped out too.
Thanks.
Okay, let's finish this today.
Where's Master Nyanko, by the way?
He said he'd look around the school by himself.
Hey, you guys.
Make sure ya find that spirit's mirror pieces fast, 'kay?
Right.
Where is it?
She said that the fragments would merge with things that shine, didn't she?
Is this it?
The pain's going away.
We need to check all the mirrors we can find.
We'll have stay after school to do it.
Hey.
What?
Are there demons here, too?
Yeah, small ones.
Want to see them?
Fine.
Natsume sees these things everyday?
Natsume?
I'm back.
Natsume, the stuff you see...
No, never mind.
Let's look for the other pieces.
I can't see them.
It's gotta be here.
What're you guys doing?
This is a nice mirror, isn't it?
Somebody must've put a lot of work into making it!
That's right.
Is there a name on it somewhere?
That was a terrible excuse.
We've checked every mirror in school.
What else is there that can shine?
I see something shining really brightly!
You're right.
It's shining.
It's around here.
Got it.
Around here, right?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
It still hurts.
There's more here.
Nothing?
Wait!
Thank you, Taki.
It doesn't hurt anymore.
Wait, I'll get you a towel.
Yeah.
Thank you, Tanuma.
I'm the one who's possessed.
I'm helping myself, too.
You go through this a lot, don't you?
Yeah.
I'm sorry about not talking about it much.
It's hard to talk about being scared or uneasy.
You're right.
It's hard.
Hey, kiddos.
It's a raccoon! Wait, it's just Ponta.
Natsume?
Master, are you carrying something?
You bet I am.
Behold.
When you're as powerful as I am,
finding the fragments is as easy as finding hay in a haystack!
Mister Madara!
Take this seriously already!
Hay in a haystack...
It sounds really impressive,
but that doesn't actually mean anything.
What was that, kid?
Now, take this and go.
Thank you.
I want that mirror!
Oh no!
I want the power!
Natsume!
Give it to me.
Give me the mirror.
Sorry, but I can't give you this mirror.
I'm sure that could get rid of a disease.
Natsume, are you okay?
Are you leaving?
Yes.
I must find my friend.
And get rid of his illness, and talk to him.
Yeah.
Will she find him?
It was a serious illness.
It's possible that her friend is already...
There's no need for you to worry.
I want to look for him, that's all.
No matter what happens, I need to yell at him,
or I'm not going to feel right.
Farewell, child of man.
If you have the chance to speak
to someone from the heart,
do not fear it.
But that's a difficult thing to do.
That's why it's rare,
and why you sometimes fail.
Thus, the Tanuma Possession Incident ended, somehow.
I see. So she's gone.
We need to tell Taki.
Yeah.
I'm sorry I made you guys worry so much,
but it was kind of fun.
I could see what you saw,
and I was able to talk to that demon.
What did you talk to her about?
She didn't tell you anything weird, did she?
You really go through a lot, don't you?
Do I?
But it's not all bad.
Right?
Yeah.
That's right.
Lining up the sparks of warmth I've lost one by one
Coming to the rainbow-colored pieces of you
I crack a smile
Not even knowing how to make memories
Even when we took things too fast
We were only going with the flow
No matter where I go, even after this darkness
How many times must I say goodbye?
Shining with the flame of a young heart
Those faraway pieces of you
Next time on
A Place To Go Home To
Natsume Yuujinchou
If that person hadn't come to see me back then, I'd...
I like the lonely ones. They're fun to watch.
Hey, Natsume, where are you going?
It was the first time somebody asked me to go with them.
You shouldn't go with strangers!