Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Your fingertips were painted in an adult's color
Embarrassed, you hid them
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
Beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
Hey, even now we're always lost,
And I remember the words I said that day:
"I'd paint the future with the color of you."
Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
A bird's nest?
Yeah, it was warming five eggs.
Four hatched, one's left.
You gonna eat it?
I'm keeping an eye on it.
All you ever think about is eating.
Is someone here?
I don't see anyone.
land
I swear I just saw...
What's this?
land
Looks like something a spirit wrote.
There's nothing actually written there?
land
but only we can see it.
A Chick Hatches
The mother hasn't come back, huh?
Takashi, is something wrong?
Nope, everything's fine.
Really?
Don't do anything dangerous, okay?
I won't.
It's still warm.
What is this?!
Good morning, Master.
You're not busy, right?
Could you keep that warm for me?
Do what?!
You are seriously the king of fools!
The minute an egg's abandoned,
it's as good as dead.
That chick might be pretty
tasty once it hatches, you know.
Good point.
I'll be back.
line
The character changed?
And so, on a whim,
I decided to have Master warm the egg.
Damn... I could really use some sake.
I'm back!
For crying out loud!
Hatch already, would you!
Hey, knock it off.
I think it's gotten a bit bigger.
I wonder what's inside this egg.
If it actually hatches,
I wonder what I should name it...
See ya later.
come
"Come."
"Three."
Three?
Like the number?
six
That first day it was "six."
The second, "five."
five
Yesterday was "four,"
four
and today's is "three."
three
A countdown?
To what, though?
Child.
Most humans cannot see those characters.
You wrote this?
Indeed.
You belong to this household?
Yeah.
three
Then do you happen to know
of the egg which was in that nest?
My Master desires it.
Desires it?
Of course...
To dine upon.
The meat inside is considered to be
the most succulent of delicacies,
and the blood drawn from
it grants everlasting youth.
I had at last discovered its location,
and had come to await its hatching,
but I could not find it in its rightful place.
I presume a mere human such as
yourself would not dare steal it.
O-Of course not.
I am not mistaken, correct?
Yeah.
Child, do not be taken by flights of fancy.
three
Master!
I just met a really strange demon outside.
Can't take anymore.
Gone drinking.
That wuss...
If I give it to him, will it be eaten as soon as it's born?
This egg is alive.
It's just trying to survive.
Would you like to live a little longer?
I have returned!
Oh, the heavens...
See you later.
two
one
That will be all for today.
Stand.
Bow.
Natsume?
What's with that guy lately?
one
M-Master! The egg!
What? A chick! A chick!
Warm water, warm water!
Towel, towel! Get a towel!
Natsume's Book Of Friends
This is probably the chick of a spirit called Tatsumi.
Tatsumi?
They're a breed similar to birds or dragons,
and they never raise their own children.
Which is why so few exist.
I've heard the chick's form depends
on the first living thing it sees,
but once they've been raised to a certain stage,
they take their true form and leave.
So if it had seen you first...
You don't know how lucky you are.
What's that supposed to mean?!
Hey!
Natsume!
Hey! I'm talking to you!
All right, this should do it.
Ignoring me, huh?
How long before it grows up?
Who knows?
I hear they grow quickly,
but I don't know the details.
What do they eat?
Would milk work?
Maybe it needs human flesh!
Ah, hey! You'll get a stomach ache.
How ungrateful!
I've been more of a parent than you, matchstick!
What do you mean by "matchstick"?
You're skinny as one,
that's why you're a matchstick!
What's that, you stupid cat?!
Damn you, dirty Matchstick!
I wonder if it was careless of me...
to take in a living thing on a whim.
Humans wouldn't know anything
about a dragon's child,
and dragons wouldn't know anything
about a human child.
I should have known that, but...
Is it good?
Oh, yes!
Very much so.
Someone gave me this, so I thought I'd test it out.
Can I have another?
Oh, but...
Those didn't turn out.
I think they're great.
Sensei didn't eat him... right?
Oh, there you are.
You want me to follow you?
What's that?
A nest?
Tatsumi never raise their own children.
The chick's form depends
on the first living thing it sees.
He just wants to be close
to the person he takes after.
I'm sorry.
I know you worked hard on this,
but I can't go in with you.
A few nights later, I had a dream.
I went inside the nest, and found
something precious within its walls.
He's grown quite big.
He may not look like it, but he's a dragon.
Your time with him's almost up.
Oh... yeah.
Once he's big enough, he'll leave.
I was even thinking of naming him...
Don't bother, I already have.
He's Eggy, because he hatched from an egg.
I don't think he likes it.
You little runt! You're not
getting away with it this time!
Little by little, Eggy grew.
And,
for some reason, weakened.
What's the matter, Eggy?
He hasn't even touched his food.
I'll get him some fresh milk.
Ah! A rat!
You're...!
I am a rat of Isodzuki.
Child...
I warned you.
I will be taking the Tatsumi chick.
What vile creature do we have now?
How impudent of you to enter my domain.
My right hook's been perfected by batting cattails;
a mere rodent will be no match for it!
How rude!
What a strange creature.
Is it swine?
A raccoon?
Insolent rodent!
I'm going to eat you, you damn rat!
Halt, child!
Damn!
Where should I go?
Just what is wrong with him?
He's thinned out so much.
Why won't he eat?
Don't you want to get big and strong?
Don't you want to grow up and live on your own?
Eggy...
Do you... want to stay with me?
I've found you, child.
Sorry, but I won't let you have him!
If you refuse, then I'll just have to take him!
What say you, child?
Feeble human...
To the powerless, a Tatsumi's fate is naught but tragedy.
Release him.
It is the life of one mere spirit.
It is of no significance to you.
E-Eggy!
Stay still!
It's okay.
You don't have to go.
You can stay here with me.
Eat your food.
Even if you end up leaving,
it won't be the end.
Until then... you can stay with me.
Natsume!
Stop it, Eggy!
Let him go!
Stop it, he'll die!
Eggy!
It's no use, Natsume.
The shock of growing so fast
has made him forget himself!
Let's go home, Eggy.
Let's go home.
This is amazing!
You're just like a bird!
Listen to me, Eggy...
I don't know my real parents either.
I've always been alone.
This may sound strange,
but I really wasn't all that lonely.
Though...
I was very sad.
Then I came to this town and met a lot of people.
And now, I'm not as sad anymore.
I wish the same for you.
I wonder if, as you struggled to be known and loved,
I was able to lighten your heavy heart, even a little...
When it was all over, I looked
into the nest Eggy left me.
Takashi!
Coming!
It was empty, just as I thought,
but I had a feeling that I knew what
was left behind at the bottom.
Hey, just a little longer
I just want you to listen a little longer
I just want to be selfish a little longer
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed like it would disappear
So could you say something?
With just you here,
My world changed
Just look at the monotonous scenery,
It looks so vivid
We were walking with our hands held,
And before we knew it, we had to separate
"Do you think we're a good match?"
Was what I asked the sky
Tree of Promises
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
What's your name?
I'm Kirinoha.
About my name...
I know, I'll give it back.
Huh?
His name's not in the Book of Friends.
It's someplace else.
Oh? Let's go take a look.