Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Your fingertips were painted in an adult's color
Embarrassed, you hid them
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
Beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
Hey, even now we're always lost,
And I remember the words I said that day:
"I'd paint the future with the color of you."
Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Natsume!
Over here.
Master?
What are you up to?
I came to buy some bowls for Touko,
Shigeru, and myself.
Wait.
I want a bowl!
Buy one for me too!
Stand! I said stand up, Natsume!
What was that?
I just felt a strange presence.
Did it come from this painting?
Caught your eye, did it?
I'm about to close up the shop,
but that one didn't sell.
You can have it, if you want.
The Man Amidst the Rows of Cherry Trees
You're actually putting that up?
It's just a bunch of dumb branches.
You think so?
I think it's kind of nice.
For real?
He might have a point, though.
I guess it'd be nicer if the flowers were in bloom.
What is this?
Where did these come from?
Oddly...
Ah! Again?
And the next morning...
Man, not again!
And on the following morning,
I found more petals on my pillow.
You haven't been getting drunk
and tracking them in, have you?
What? Of all the nerve!
I have no interest in flowers!
Hmph! Hmph! Hmph!
It started after I hung that painting up.
If some demon is to blame for this,
I have to act fast.
Thank you! I've always wanted one of this size.
I'll get rid of anything that could threaten this house.
Don't think you can just curl up in here with me.
Uh, why do you have a net?
Haven't you even considered
that fairies might be behind this?
If they are, I'm gonna catch 'em!
I don't think some imaginary creature is to blame.
Can you say that without a doubt? Huh?
Are you really sure?
Hey? Are you absolutely positive?
I don't appreciate you barging
into my territory, missy.
Why do you keep putting flowers here?
They are an offering to him,
and have nothing to do with you,
you damn thief.
Thief?
What have I stolen?
How impudent! I'll eat you!
Stop, Master!
Why me?
What was that for?
I was actually acting like a bodyguard for once...
Who do you mean by "him"?
Only Master and I are here.
What are you talking about?
He's right there.
Him.
Don't be so loud.
You'll startle Lord Yasaka.
R-Right...
The people in the house, too.
Lord Yasaka?
Right.
He lives in this painting.
I'll be reclaiming this.
It belongs to me.
It was misplaced and got left behind,
then some human picked it up and sold it off...
Now it seems it's come to this wretched house.
It's not...
It won't come off!
Huh? Why?
It's really not coming off...
What did you do, nail it to the wall?
Of course not!
You did something weird to it, didn't you?
What?
Very well.
I will continue to visit until it comes off.
What?!
My name is Miya.
I'll return tomorrow.
Wait! H-Hey!
Hey! Don't leave these creepy petals behind!
And so, true to her word...
Excuse me.
Miya came back the next night.
Put your hand out, boy.
This is my thanks for looking after Lord Yasaka.
It's a nice gesture, but don't
let them loose in my room!
Hey, wait!
Pretty, aren't they?
Lord Yasaka was once human.
He loved gazing at flowers and butterflies.
Was a human?
It was a long time ago...
I had been looking at the blossoms
on a row of cherry trees.
When in full bloom,
they could take your breath away.
Hidden by the petals,
I tried talking to him.
Do you enjoy your books more than
these lovely cherry blossoms?
Are rows of letters more enjoyable
than rows of flowers?
I love both books and flowers.
I also enjoy talking to you.
He called himself Yasaka.
He was frail, but he was the heir
to a distinguished family,
so he barely had any time to himself.
He never realized I was a spirit,
and came to speak to me many times.
But...
I was always afraid he'd discover what I was.
So, I would only go to that row of trees
when there were cherry blossoms to hide me.
We were friends who only
spoke during the flower season.
Miya,
if I'm ever given freedom,
I want to travel everywhere my heart desires.
Wouldn't it be wonderful to see
the flowers of the world?
Miya, I wonder why.
There are so many things that I want you to hear.
Several springs passed in this way.
Until one year, he didn't come at all.
I waited and waited...
All through the next spring...
and the one that followed.
I looked everywhere for him.
I walked around searching for him,
not even knowing where to look.
Until finally,
I found that painting.
Upon asking,
I was told that it was drawn by a renowned spirit.
Maybe he was dissatisfied with the world of men
and escaped into the painting.
So, I took it and began
to travel in order to comfort him.
I believe that someday,
once his heart has healed,
he'll finally come out.
And then...
I can talk to him again.
Natsume's Book Of Friends
It's true that a famous spirit painted this picture.
However, it's simply a painting.
It's nothing but a drawing of cherry trees in winter,
with this Yasaka guy standing around.
Wait as she might, he's not coming out.
Even so, Miya brought flowers every day.
Every day,
no matter what,
without fail.
Weird cough you've got there.
It just won't stop...
Come on, Master! Don't trample them!
Has Miya been traveling like this,
following the beautiful
scenery wherever it leads her,
carrying only an ordinary painting?
Pardon me. Pardon me.
Oh, it's Harujizou.
Every spring, he goes around telling people's
fortunes as part of his spiritual training.
A sinister shadow entwines you.
I can see your corpse littered with leaves.
Wait! What do you mean "corpse"?
Takashi?
T-Touko...
What's wrong?
You were talking to yourself out loud.
No. Ah...
It's nothing.
Promise?
Yeah, I swear.
Okay...
Yeah.
Well then, shall we go home?
Okay.
I was always afraid he'd discover what I was.
Yeah...
It's the same for me.
Still, what did that Harujizou mean?
Natsume!
What is this?
Oh, now I get it!
I know why you're coughing!
This painting is stealing your energy,
and it's spreading its branches to take even more!
Master!
I won't allow a little painting to pilfer my prey!
I'll tear it to shreds first!
Stop, Master!
That's Miya's...
Natsume, you fool!
What the heck are you doing?
Wake up, stupid Natsume!
Miya, if I'm ever given freedom,
I want to travel everywhere my heart desires.
But, I'm sure that it'd be wearisome traveling alone.
Would you accompany me?
Hello, Miya.
Come to see me again, have you?
What shall we talk about today?
I'm sorry, Natsume.
It appears my carrying it for so long
has given this painting spiritual power.
It has taken root in the wall,
so it won't come off.
At this rate, your life will be in danger,
so I will use my power and burn it.
No, Miya!
Isn't it everything to you?
It's okay, Natsume.
In truth, I'd already noticed...
That he...
That Lord Yasaka... is gone.
Even so, I enjoyed the days I traveled
with it as much as if he'd been with me himself.
Whether it was rainy...
Or it was windy...
I never felt alone.
But...
This is as far as I go.
I only wanted to speak with him face to face,
and not have to care that I'm a monster, just once.
Miya.
I feel fine.
Let's look for a way to take it down together.
But...
I like this painting too.
Idiots...
Miya and I are alike, Master.
We feel sad and anxious at the thought of telling
the ones we care about the truth.
So I'm sorry, Master.
I want Miya to have this painting.
I'm sure Lord Yasaka is inside it.
He's standing in a row of cherry trees in winter,
searching endlessly for her,
though he knows she'll never come.
But even after several days passed,
we couldn't find a solution.
At least Touko can't see them.
Idiot.
I've decided.
I'll burn this picture.
Miya?
But before I do, I want to
make the cherry trees bloom.
Like the day he and I first met.
Will you help me?
There we go.
Natsume!
It's pretty, huh...?
Miya...
Miya, you know, Lord Yasaka...
Thank you, Natsume.
Good night.
Rest well.
I see.
I'm inside the painting...
When I woke up,
the growing branches and
the painted blossoms were completely gone.
I looked inside the painting,
but Lord Yasaka was nowhere to be found.
The second I touched it,
it came right off the wall.
I never saw Miya again.
Miya, it's possible that his heart came
to dwell in the painting.
And the reason it took power
from me to spread its branches
could've been an effort to make
the flowers bloom so he could see you again.
I wonder if those two are still
surrounded by cherry trees in full bloom.
Or were they released from the painting,
and now traveling together?
Takashi!
I wonder if Miya ever told him the truth...
You say something, Natsume?
No, nothing at all, Master.
Goodbye, Miya,
the dear friend I made in the season of flowers.
Hey, just a little longer
I just want you to listen a little longer
I just want to be selfish a little longer
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed like it would disappear
So could you say something?
With just you here,
My world changed
Just look at the monotonous scenery,
It looks so vivid
We were walking with our hands held,
And before we knew it, we had to separate
"Do you think we're a good match?"
Was what I asked the sky
Temporary
Home
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Ever since I saw those strange footprints,
weird things've been happening at home.
Something similar happened to me when I was a boy.
Shigeru?
But after she came, it all stopped.
She was such an odd, yet beautiful girl.