Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Your fingertips were painted in an adult's color
Embarrassed, you hid them
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
Beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
Hey, even now we're always lost,
And I remember the words I said that day:
"I'd paint the future with the color of you."
Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Come on, just go!
What's with you? Jeez.
Just come with me!
But where are we going?
Don't worry about it.
Yeah, just come.
And we're here!
Here?
About time, Natsume!
Sorry, Class President's orders.
We couldn't refuse.
Come in, boys!
So that's how it is?
Right, so let's go in.
The Boy In The Empty House
People say they've heard odd sounds
and strange voices here at night...
Can you sense anything?
It's not like I've got some kind of special—
I don't care how many times you deny it,
I still believe that you have a special power!
Maybe you don't like it,
but I think it's great.
Honestly, you should have more pride!
By the way, where are Nishimura and Kitamoto?
Dunno... Maybe they went home.
Home?
Don't worry about those non-believers, okay?
I see!
I could picture ghosts here for sure.
It's you!
Taki?
This seems interesting.
Let me join you!
Okay, Sasada, you and I will look over there!
Natsume, you search that area!
W-Wait!
Now, don't make a fuss.
I want to go with Natsume...
Come on, come on.
That Taki chick's pretty attentive.
Master?
Come on. Let's get out of here.
You shouldn't stay here too long.
What do you mean?
Is there really something here?
Yeah.
Now, let's get out of here before it senses—
Hey! Where are you going?!
If that's the case,
Taki and Sasada are in danger.
I'll go get them.
Jeez, you really are a softie.
Open up!
Was that a kid's voice?
Wait! It might not be human!
Ah jeez!
A coffin?
Open up!
Let me out!
Open!
He's inside?
Hold on, I'll open it up now.
Wait, Natsume!
Are you okay?
That was one heck of an uppercut.
What would a kid be doing in here?
Judging from his scent, he wasn't a spirit.
Was he playing hide and seek or something?
The lid must have gotten stuck,
and he couldn't get out.
Is something wrong?
I thought I heard voices.
Ah, no, it's nothing.
Find anything?
Nothing, unfortunately.
There he is! Kitty!
I've missed you!
Wow, that's disturbing.
So fluffy!
Ishio Kai
Kai?
Ishio Kai?
Ishio Kai
That guy's in Class 3.
You know, the one who said
somethin' weird's after him.
Oh, him?
He said he thought it might be a ghost.
He's probably just tryin' to get attention
'cause his parents are always out till late.
Is he being bullied?
No way.
He's actually got a ton of friends.
Later!
Bye, bye.
Yeah, thanks!
Master Nyanko!
Was it you?
You put me in that box, didn't you?
No, it wasn't me.
It wasn't me!
I came to return something you dropped.
Is that jerk the one?
The one chasing you?
Get lost!
Hey, stop!
Look!
He even brought the world's ugliest cat!
No joke! It's hideous!
Hideous?!
What's going on?
It's a pervert!
Get him!
Get out of here, bean sprout!
Washboard-boy!
Stick-dude!
Girly-man!
Get lost!
We should get out of here, Natsume.
Gross, it's on his shoulder!
Wow...
He's running!
Don't come back again!
Yeah, don't ever come back!
He was nothing.
Yeah!
That was easy!
Hey, you okay, Kai?
Good grief...
Seriously...
I'm not so good with kids, I guess.
Bean Sprout
Washboard-boy
Stick-dude
Girly-man
I think I took more damage from
that than the last huge demon I fought.
What a depressing guy.
Ah, damn. I forgot to give it to him.
The name tag?
Hey, Master, could you give it to him?
I'll give you 200 yen.
What?
You'd give a noble spirit
such as myself a mere 200 yen?!
Give me the paper! Give me 10,000 yen!
If he's being chased by a ghost...
Can he see demons?
Tanuma.
Hey.
A kid who can see demons?
It didn't seem like he was being bullied though.
I'm glad for that.
Natsume...
I'll devour that kid.
If he breaks his promise, I'll eat him.
Is something there?
It ran.
A demon?
What kid was he talking about?
Natsume?
Oh, Taki.
What are you doing here of all places?
Um, I just...
Oh, Tanuma, have you met before?
This is—
Save that for later,
we should get out of here.
I read in a book that was in my house...
that this area tends to attract demons.
Attracts demons?
Hey, you're bleeding!
When did that happen?
Was it that one I just saw?
The scent of blood might attract demons.
We really should get out of here.
You too!
Y-Yeah.
So, your ancestors were mediums?
Yeah.
Okay, that should do.
Thanks.
Must be a dangerous one...
Yeah.
You must not allow spirits into your heart.
They are not like humans.
They are pure evil.
Do you suppose that Kai kid can see demons?
I'm not sure.
But if that's the case...
You want to protect him?
You're kind.
No, that's not it.
I just convince myself that they need my help
and get myself mixed up in stuff.
Maybe it's just arrogance on my part.
Natsume...
To be honest, I feel like I'm a magnet for trouble.
I used to blame it all on the demons, but now...
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Kai!
A demon?
Lost Property
L-Lost property?
Nice, Master Nyanko!
I'll pay you when we get home.
I can't stop myself!
You again?
That is seriously disturbing...
Kai.
Did you follow me?
You swear it wasn't you?
You didn't chase me
and put me in that box, right?
Right.
It wasn't me.
I see...
I'm sorry about what happened earlier...
Well...
That they called you bean sprout,
washboard-boy, stick-dude, and girly-man...
Ah, w-well, i-it's okay...
It's not funny!
Of course not!
There, I apologized.
Wait.
About the guy who's following you...
Shouldn't you tell the police?
It's fine.
There's no point in telling them anyway.
Of course there is.
I apologized, so leave me alone.
Hey, are you hurt?
What's it to you?
Don't be so damned stubborn!
You'll be in serious trouble
if something bad happens!
Natsume...
Sorry for yelling at you...
It doesn't look like it's broken.
The pain will stop soon, I think.
Get on.
Don't wanna.
I made a kid cry...
How can I prove that I'm worried about him?
It'd be easier if he were a demon...
I wasn't trying to cause trouble.
It's just, when I saw you were hurt...
I thought maybe it was
because you'd saved me;
that you were attacked
by the one who's after me.
So... I figured it was my turn to protect you.
And that's why you followed me?
Thanks.
L-Later.
His parents aren't home yet, huh?
So he's all alone?
That's the first time someone's
ever said they had to protect me.
Now hold on.
What do you think I am?
Oops, I forgot.
You're my bodyguard, right?
Don't you forget it! And it's not funny!
Small fry.
If he's following me,
I guess he's not after Kai.
You honestly thought he was after Kai?
I don't know...
He did say he was going to eat a kid...
Lots of demons eat kids.
You think too much.
It's just a small fry talking big.
Maybe so, but he did get me back there.
What?
I can't leave you for a second.
It's nothing though.
You dunce!
I'd be overjoyed if you were eaten
and I got the Book of Friends,
but I'm not sure I like the idea of something
of mine being hurt by that runt over there!
Not sure at all!
Do you understand the degree
of ambiguity I'm getting at here?!
Right.
Not sure!
So if Kai can't see demons...
If it's not a demon that's after him...
Who put him in that coffin?
Natsume!
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
Oh, it's that boy.
He's so cute.
Is he waiting for someone?
Kai...
I want to protect him.
Since then, I've been spending time
with Kai after school almost every day.
Taki showed me how to do it.
Kai?
Now we match!
Kai.
Yes, Natsume?
Would you tell me about it?
You mean the box?
Yeah.
If you don't want to, that's fine.
For a while now, I've had the feeling
that I'm being watched.
One time, I saw someone staring
at me from behind a telephone pole.
I thought it was just some creep,
so I didn't worry about it too much.
Um, how about we do worry
if that happens again, okay?
That day, it started chasing me,
so I ran to that house.
I hid in that box to hide and...
You couldn't get out?
It got locked.
Locked?
I don't remember it being locked...
Watch out!
What? What's going on?
Taki can't see him, but...
But...
You can see it?
You mean... you can see him too?!
Taki, there's a demon right in front of you!
I'm taking Kai away from here!
Don't follow us!
Natsume!
Stay away!
I know!
Are you okay?
Did we lose him?
I don't know.
This is...
Damn it, he lured us here...
Kai, run!
Natsume!
Master Nyanko!
Let go! Let me go!
It got away!
I let him escape.
You'd nag me if I ate him.
Besides, I'm a picky eater.
I took a good amount of his spiritual power,
so he won't follow you anymore.
How did you find this place?
Taki came to me in a panic,
so I went looking for you.
When will you ever learn?
Taki did?
I see.
Thanks, Master.
You saved me.
Not the nose! It tickles!
Wow...
Amazing!
You have a servant!
He's not my servant.
He just helps me out.
Natsume! Kai!
Taki!
I'm so glad you're safe.
Yeah, all thanks to Master.
Kitty!
Enough! Enough already!
Thanks!
Kai could see the demon...
So was he the one chasing him all along?
What is this awful feeling?
Something tells me this isn't over.
Natsume!
He's the one who locked Kai in that coffin!
N-Natori?
Darn...
And here I was trying to keep you out of this.
I didn't think you'd jump right in.
Then, the one who locked Kai in that coffin...
I didn't lock him in there.
I sealed him.
Seal
You should stay away from him.
What do you mean?
What's going on?
Natsume...
He's...
a demon.
Hey, just a little longer
I just want you to listen a little longer
I just want to be selfish a little longer
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed like it would disappear
So could you say something?
With just you here,
My world changed
Just look at the monotonous scenery,
It looks so vivid
We were walking with our hands held,
And before we knew it, we had to separate
"Do you think we're a good match?"
Was what I asked the sky
Humans
and Demons
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Kai is a demon?
I came to exterminate him.
What did he do?!
What could he have done to deserve that?!
Natsume, don't you think it's time for you to decide?
What's more important to you, humans or demons?