------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
Natsume!
Hey, Natsume!
I have to go home.
I have to go home...
He let a wimp like that get inside him...
If I do something stupid, it could destroy his mind.
Wake up!
Natsume!
I hear Master's voice.
I have to go home.
But to which home?
To where?
Why's he just wandering around?
Is Natsume lost?
Miyoko's family's taking him in, right?
He probably doesn't know how to get home yet.
He must be dumb!
But I'm too scared to go home.
There are monsters everywhere I go.
I've been here a long time.
He's going back!
You going back to school?
Can no one else see them?
All these scary things...
Huh? Um...
I'm really lost.
A shrine?
All the way out here?
It's quiet.
This is great.
I can just run here whenever the monsters chase me.
I can make it a secret base.
A quiet place, just for me,
where nobody else will come.
A Long Way Home
I'm done.
What's wrong, Miyoko?
You barely ate.
Clean your plate.
But...
I don't want to eat.
I'm leaving.
Hey, Miyoko!
Hey, Miyoko.
Make sure you walk to school with Takashi.
I'm going with Nao!
That girl...
Takashi, don't worry about it.
Eat up.
Okay.
I smell something good.
That looks great.
I want to try it someday.
Hey, it's Natsume.
What's he doing?
Hey, it's Miyoko.
Hey, Miyoko!
I heard you're living with Natsume!
That's naughty!
So naughty!
Hey, stop!
Naughty! Naughty!
I hate you!
Miyoko!
Scary!
I have to apologize.
She didn't do anything, and I...
It's my fault for coming to this house.
I'm done.
You're still not eating?
Miyoko, what's really wrong?
Um... I...
I said I'm done!
Miyoko!
Daddy!
Why did he come here?
Miyoko, wanna talk with Daddy until bedtime?
Then tomorrow you can walk to school with Takashi.
Miyoko's still upset, so we're letting her sleep in our room tonight.
Will you be okay, Takashi?
Yeah.
Okay. Good night.
Can I take a look?
Just for today?
Dad... Mom...
No, I can't.
I can't look at this.
It hurts.
I can't read it.
I'm all right.
I'm not lonely.
They're gone, but I'm sure they're...
Bye.
Walk farther behind me.
Hey, where's your house?
Your real house.
My real house?
The house where your parents lived!
Don't you remember?
About your mom and dad?
I don't remember my mom.
And your dad?
My dad either...
But he was...
really, really nice!
I'm sure he was.
You're weird.
How can you say that when you don't remember him?
How dare you talk like that?
My dad's much, much nicer!
My real home...
You're weird!
How can you say that...
If I went to my real home,
I might be able to remember more about my dad.
But...
If I remembered a lot, and it hurt a lot...
Your house?
Oh, the Natsume place?
I think Tachibana gave us a piece of paper with the address on it.
Here it is.
Why do you want it?
Umm... I wanted to keep it as a good luck charm.
This piece of paper?
Oh, it's not that far.
Shiromachi is west down the Shirokawa River just a ways.
Oh, another tiny monster.
What is that?
I'll eat it for you.
This is...
She didn't eat her food again.
She's a bad girl.
I'll eat her for you.
What are you talking about?
Don't do it!
Get lost!
Scary, scary...
Go someplace far away!
You can't cause trouble for people.
You can't!
Shiromachi.
West down the Shirokawa River just a ways.
What should I do?
What time is it?
I have to go home.
I'll cause problems for them again.
I'm all right.
Thunder isn't scary.
I have to go home.
I have to hurry!
Anyone there?
There he is!
I'm so sorry.
We're sorry for the trouble.
No, I'm glad we found him.
Poor kid was terrified.
I'm sorry.
Oh, Takashi.
You can go inside.
I'm going to apologize to everyone.
Go eat dinner with Miyoko.
I'm so sorry.
No, not at all.
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
Why do my parents have to apologize for you?
Why do they have to have people get mad at them?
You're the one who's weird!
Get out of here!
Just leave!
Leave, please...
Shiromachi.
West down the Shirokawa river just a ways...
My home's there.
I'll go home.
I'll go home... to my real home.
To that empty home...
Dad...
Dad... Mom...
I called for them again and again.
And I learned that each time, nothing called back.
I learned that no matter how much you want something,
no matter how many times you scream for it, sometimes it's out of your reach.
I never did make it there.
I got lost, and ran out of energy.
I decided to stop calling out for someone who would never call back.
Sad memories you want to forget...
I'll eat them for you.
Draw a mouth.
No.
They're a part of what makes me who I am.
No matter how much they hurt, they're important to me.
Let me eat them.
Your memories and your heart.
Let me eat them all.
Natsume!
I hear a voice.
Takashi.
Tohko.
Natsume!
We'll be here when you get back, Takashi.
That's right,
I'm going home!
You did it.
I destroyed his spiritual energy.
He's just a harmless bug now.
Thank you,
Master.
Did you call for me?
Did you see my memories?
I'm not interested in your memories.
I'm only staying with you until I get the Book of Friends.
Shiromachi...
West down the Shirokawa river just a ways.
Natsume
I'm home.
Did I draw this?
I must've been a mischievous kid.
My dad kept it, even though I drew it in a place like this.
So, what do you think?
Remember anything about your life here?
No, I forgot most of it.
So many...
So many important things
I've forgotten.
Master, somewhere in this yard
my mom planted some flowers.
I wonder where they are.
It's too late to tell.
Takashi...
I hope they bloom this year.
I hope they bloom every year.
Takashi...
Bye,
Dad.
Goodbye, my home.
Now let's go home.
After that, I felt really tired,
so I just went straight home.
We didn't get to eat those noodles,
but for once, Master didn't get mad.
I'm back.
Welcome back.
Welcome home, Takashi.
I'm home.
Huh?
Lost again?
Which way is it?
I think we're almost there.
This is the third time!
Master Natsume!
See you later!
Later! Later!
Soda spring! Soda spring!
Hey, I've got a feeling that it's this way.
Thanks for this!
How was it?
I loved it!
Sasada!
Taki!
You finally made it.
Sure took you a while.
How'd you get here ahead of us?
We looked it up!
Natsume said you were going today, so I waited!
Is this where the soda spring is?
What?
It's red!
Of course it is.
It's rusted.
It's fine. You won't get sick unless you've got bad luck.
Then you drink first, Nishimura.
Rock paper scissors!
We can do rock paper scissors!
There were sad days, and painful ones,
and there may be more.
Even so...
Okay, ready? Here we go.
Come on, Takashi. Get closer.
Come on, smile! Takashi!
Let's see how it turned out.
I can't wait!
Tonight it's the croquette blues...
Shigeru, Tohko,
can we take another?
Stay still, Nyangoro.
Treasured days
that I'll never forget.
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on