Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Your fingertips were painted in an adult's color
Embarrassed, you hid them
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
Beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side
Hey, even now we're always lost,
And I remember the words I said that day:
"I'd paint the future with the color of you."
Face forward and run
I painted the lights in the sky
With these numb hands to brighten your future
Cut through it with your hands
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run
Hey, come take a look at this, Takashi.
Ah, yes?
I bought a bunch of snacks for you.
That's a lot, Touko.
Take it to your study retreat, okay?
Okay.
This last bag of chips won't fit.
Oh well, I guess I'll eat them here.
You have absolutely no manners, you know?
Would you like some too, Master?
If you insist, my troublesome charge.
Emotions Undying
You're late, Natsume.
Sorry, sorry.
Your bag is stuffed!
Whatcha got in there?
Trust me, you're gonna love it.
We will?
Yeah, you'll see.
What a nice place.
This lake sure looks deep.
Check out all the algae.
You'll drown if you fall in.
Spooky.
What's wrong, Natsume?
Someone's swimming.
Someone? Where?
I'm gonna fall! I'm gonna fall!
What are you talking about?
There's nothing out there.
Huh? What?
Ah, my mistake. Come on, let's go.
Come on, what was it?
Hey!
Hello?
Hello?!
No one's answering...
Maybe they're out?
Well, we are a bit early.
It's open.
Anyone home?
Was it okay for us to let ourselves in?
A lake...
So there's one in the garden too.
Naturally!
This area is renowned for its mermaid legends,
so there are lakes and ponds everywhere.
Mermaids?
Why the hell are you in my bag?!
Natsume's family cat.
No wonder it was so heavy!
Smuggled in?
You little...!
Oh dear, and here I thought
I had time to run an errand.
Please excuse me.
No, no. We're sorry for letting ourselves in.
Come, come. I'll show you to your rooms.
Is something wrong?
N-No, no... It's nothing.
My name is Sakanaka Chizu.
Please relax and enjoy yourselves, okay?
What's up with this one?
Ah, I don't get it either.
Same here.
So question three is a mystery then.
Ah, this is so tasty!
I think you're supposed to substitute for "α" there.
Quiet.
You'll ruin the food.
Take this!
This is pretty fun.
Master, look, it's a carp!
Yeah, so? What's the big deal?
It blinked! The fish blinked!
Get back, Natsume!
Fish with eyelids are said
to be spirits in disguise!
You'll be eaten!
Oh-ho, it was so terrified of me it fled.
Yeah, even demons think you have a creepy face.
That's right, even demons think I have a—
My face is not creepy!
I wonder if that was what I saw
in the lake this afternoon.
It might've realized who you are and followed you.
Which means it's after the Book of Friends...
Give it to me.
It's here.
Give me the Book of Friends!
Now, give it to me!
What the heck? Her flesh is so hard.
A raccoon dog... A raccoon dog is...!
I'm not a raccoon dog!
How dare you... A sneak attack?
This is why I don't trust humans!
Though I suppose this is what
makes them good for smacking around.
Give me the book, boy.
It's not something a human should have.
What are you doing out so late?
I'm sorry!
I couldn't sleep.
Shall I make you something warm?
No, I'm fine.
What is it?
I'm sorry.
You remind me a bit of the person I'm looking for.
You're looking for someone?
Yes.
A person to whom I can never truly atone.
Atone for what?
Have you heard the legend of the mermaid?
They say that those who drink the blood
or eat the flesh of a mermaid will gain eternal youth.
I see.
Just once, long ago, I saw
a mermaid in the lake nearby.
I was young, though,
so perhaps I was only dreaming.
I made someone drink the blood
I received from that mermaid.
He is the person I'm looking for.
Thank you very much.
We had a blast!
I enjoyed myself as well.
Thank you for coming.
That was awesome.
What a great study retreat.
You didn't do anything but eat.
That's not true!
Hey, wanna go the long way back to the station,
and then take one of the old trains home?
Sounds good to me!
The boxed lunches at that station are great!
Natsume, be on guard.
How can you still eat?
Want to, Natsume?
Sorry, I forgot something.
Go on without me.
Leave the Book of Friends!
Uh... sorry, you startled me.
What's your name?
I have no name to give to a mere human.
To begin with, a noble,
ravishing mermaid such as myself—
Listen when you're being spoken to!
Humans are so damned rude!
Are you the mermaid Chizu met?
Wouldn't you like to know.
I have no reason to tell you.
That's true.
Sorry, but I can't give you the Book of Friends.
Don't follow me anymore, okay?
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Mermaids hate humans more than anything.
They were hunted for their flesh,
so there aren't many left.
You shouldn't have let her go, Natsume.
You could've eaten her and become immortal.
If I did that, you'd never get
the Book of Friends, Master.
Chizu.
Sorry!
Forgive me, an acquaintance told me that someone had
seen a person who looked like Keiichi at this station.
So, I thought you were him.
So, the errand you ran yesterday...
Yes, I came here.
What is Keiichi like?
You believe me?
Yeah, I do.
My parents both worked, and I had no siblings.
I spent a great deal of time alone,
playing at the lake in front of my house.
And then my neighbor, Keiichi,
took pity on me and began to play with me.
He was about your age and very kind.
I adored him.
But he was ill...
One stormy night, he took a turn for the worse.
I recalled the legend that a mermaid lived
in that lake, and hurried there.
In those waters, I saw a mermaid with gentle eyes,
and she gave me some of her precious blood.
And so, I poured some onto his lips...
You made him drink the mermaid's blood?
The adults said it was just a dream,
and it's been so long,
I'm no longer sure myself.
Keiichi was transferred to a hospital far away,
and his life was saved.
But he never came back.
The shock of him moving away made me
completely forget about the mermaid's blood.
Terrible of me, don't you think?
No...
Last year, my husband passed on,
and when I said to myself,
"I won't be long behind him,"
I suddenly remembered it all.
I can't stop wondering if it was a dream.
If not, then he cannot die or even age.
What if my reckless, thoughtless
love causes him to suffer even now?
To live forever alone, watching
everyone you love pass away...
Master's probably lived like that.
Like with Reiko, for example.
And someday...
Maybe I'll catch that mermaid...
What?
She might know something.
Always with the stupid ideas...
I'm not helping.
I'll buy you a steamed bun
from Nanatsujiya on the way back.
We're just catching her.
Hey! Mermaid! Hey!
I just want to talk!
Please come out!
Natsume, the sun's going down.
So we came for nothing?
You don't like humans, I get it.
But, aren't you lonely all by yourself?
I haven't always been alone.
What do you want, boy?
What are you doing?!
Get off me!
I want to talk.
I'm not letting go until you answer me.
Fool.
You can't possibly beat me in the water!
I'd always regret not doing
everything in my power to help her!
So tell me!
Did you ever give a little girl your blood?
What?
She's hurting because she gave it
to the person she cared about.
If you know some way
to break the immortality...
All anybody cares about is immortality;
our flesh and blood!
Yes, she often used to come here.
She didn't know I was a mermaid,
and she would always play with me.
So when she came back after a long absence,
I showed her this form,
and when she asked for blood,
I gave her some.
I see...
She regrets giving it to another,
and her timeworn heart is saddened.
Poor thing...
In that case, to end her suffering...
I'll eat her!
Wait!
She took off?
Hey! Where are you going, Natsume?
This isn't what I wanted!
I was just trying to help.
Why didn't it work?
For me...
For Chizu...
He...
Keiichi is...
...the exact same!
What have I done?
Keiichi!
Wait, Keiichi!
You poor thing...
Are you tired?
That voice... Are you that mermaid?
Wait, mermaid!
She was just a child!
Just a little girl who didn't
understand your loneliness or scars!
She called you a mermaid
with kindness in her eyes...
It's reacting to you.
Is your name in the Book of Friends?
Is that why you want it?
I was just killing time.
That's why I was after the Book of Friends,
why I fought Natsume Reiko,
and why I gave that girl my blood.
It was all to kill time.
So you're Reiko's grandson?
You look delicious.
I found it.
Sasafune, I return your name.
Please take it.
What a stormy night...
She hasn't come by for months,
but she's back now.
Maybe I'll ask her to be my friend.
Should I smile so she won't be scared?
Mermaid! Mermaid!
Please give me your blood!
I see... that's all you were after.
Is that true?
You saw my thoughts, didn't you, Natsume?
That's right...
I was so disappointed,
I decided to play a trick on her,
and gave her a vial filled with grape juice.
She smiled with tears in her eyes and thanked me.
And then I became disappointed in myself.
Sasafune...
But it was for the best.
It was all for the best.
Please tell her for me, Natsume...
Tell her I'm sorry for tricking her.
Wait, Sasafune!
Tell her... Tell her yourself!
Chizu!
Mermaid!
Take care.
Did you hear that, Chizu?
Yes...
That same gentle voice I used to hear.
I see, it was his grandson.
Yes, he comes through this station
sometimes on his way to cram school.
Keiichi died three years ago, he said,
but he led a very happy life.
His grandson really did look just like the picture.
He said he'd like to hear about his grandfather.
Hello.
A pleasure to meet you.
Sasafune, Chizu says she'll come back.
Don't think I can save you every time, Natsume.
Some things are just impossible,
which is a fact you seem to constantly forget.
You're right.
I'm painfully aware of my weakness.
But that's exactly why everyone knows
how it feels to want to be with someone,
or to want someone with you,
and what a precious thing it is
when that wish comes true.
Hey, just a little longer
I just want you to listen a little longer
I just want to be selfish a little longer
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed like it would disappear
So could you say something?
With just you here,
My world changed
Just look at the monotonous scenery,
It looks so vivid
We were walking with our hands held,
And before we knew it, we had to separate
"Do you think we're a good match?"
Was what I asked the sky
The Man Amidst the Rows of Cherry Trees
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
I got a picture at the flea market.
Who keeps spreading flowers every night?!
Lord Yasaka is inside that image.
There you are, underling!
Why flowers?
During his years as a human,
Lord Yasaka adored flowers.