------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
I'm back.
Welcome back, Takashi.
Shigeru, is that...
Oh, I found this old camera when I was cleaning.
I was checking whether it still worked...
It's making weird sounds.
The film must've jammed.
I only used this when I went on trips with Tohko.
It's pretty old,
but maybe I can get it fixed.
If I can, let's all take a photo together.
Sure.
A photo, huh?
A Single Photo
Thanks for going shopping for me, Takashi.
I made some iced tea. Take some up with you.
Thanks.
I'm back, Master Nyanko.
Weeeelcome baaaaack.
Welcome back, Master Natsume!
Welcome back! Welcome back!
Don't welcome me back!
I told you not to come in without asking!
Where's Master?
Hey, Master Nyanko!
An acquaintance said her name was written in the Book of Friends, so we brought her here.
Hello.
You who protect me, show your name.
Stare...
Don't stare! It's creepy!
He's so cute when he's angry!
Thank you, Master Natsume.
I'm tired.
Really now, you're such a wimp.
You sure you're Reiko's grandson?
Her grandson, huh?
So Reiko had a family...
A family...
I wonder about that.
You gave back another name, didn't you?
What are you doing to my Book of Friends?
My grandmother kept the name "Natsume" her whole life.
I never dared ask any of the relatives I was staying with...
I was scared to hear them say something bad about her,
or tell me how lonely she was.
What's wrong, Natsume?
You're all pale.
You guys kept me up all night.
Takashi, it's time for breakfast!
Okay.
It wouldn't bother me now.
Good morning.
Good morning, Takashi.
Because of these people I've met,
I'm sure it wouldn't bother me anymore.
I can just forget all the pain now.
Let's eat.
Okay.
What are you looking for, Natsume?
Here it is.
It was in this.
What's this?
This is a picture of my parents.
You had a picture?
I think it's okay for me to look at it now.
Takashi!
Your friends are here!
Okay!
Takashi's Stuff
Soda spring?
You mean, the fizzy kind?
That's right.
Kitamoto said he knows a place
where soda water flows naturally.
What do you think, Natsume?
You're from the city, so you don't believe me, do you?
A soda spring?
I mean, I know two sake springs, but...
Sake?
I dream of that sometimes.
That's some weird dream.
So, how about it?
If you want to see if I'm telling the truth,
why not come with me tomorrow?
We're goin' to the soda water spring!
Count me in!
Me, too.
Right, that settles it.
Nishimura'll get here soon.
He said he'd be late because of cram school.
Nishimura?
I know. Nishimura, going to cram school?
Let's scare him.
Go hide somewhere.
Hide? Seriously?
Oh, come on, why not?
Okay, I'll hide here.
Coming!
Yes, this is the Fujiwaras.
He won't find me here!
Takashi.
I'm sorry, do you have a second?
Yeah, sure.
I got a call from Tachibana.
He says he needs to talk to you directly.
I'll go.
Um, Tohko.
Who's Tachibana?
He's a relative. Takashi lived with him when he was young.
He cares for the house Takashi and his late parents
lived in when he was little.
Yes.
Yes... I'm doing well.
Is something wrong?
The... house?
Yes, I think we've finally found a buyer.
What do you think, Takashi?
That house isn't doing you any good, is it?
You're doing well over there, right?
Yes.
You're right.
It's not something I can do anything about.
Yes.
I'd imagine you barely remember that house,
but I thought I should contact you.
So I can go ahead with this, right?
Yes.
You'll still be able to visit for another two weeks.
If you want, you can look around before it's sold.
Tohko?
What did Tachibana want?
It was about my old house.
It's a small house, but it's been abandoned for years.
He said he finally found a buyer.
It's fine.
He's going to handle all of it.
Oh, my... but...
It's all right.
Hello!
It's Nishimura.
You're late.
Sorry.
I heard you're going to cram school?
Here I am!
Where's Kitamoto?
What the heck, are you kids or something?
But Natsume, what was that?
Behind the closet door.
Ooh, what is it?
It's not worth seeing!
Hey, Nishimura!
Now I'm curious.
You too, Tanuma?
Nice, Tanuma!
H-Hey!
Stop it!
What is it?
Stop! Wait! Wait, I said!
What are these?
Really?
What are they doing there?
Well, you know...
If I put them up somewhere people could see them,
it'd be kinda embarrassing.
So you put them in the closet?
Forget about it.
What are we doing tomorrow?
What about the soda water?
We're still gonna go see the soda water?
Yeah.
Is it real?
You still doubt it?
Well, you'll see for yourselves.
It comes bubbling out of the ground like this.
Bring a canteen.
And eat lunch first.
We meet here at 1 o'clock.
Yeah.
Okay, 1 o'clock.
Don't be late.
Bye!
See you tomorrow at 1 o'clock!
Doesn't tomorrow sound like fun, Master?
You sure about your house?
I am, Master.
The most important place to me right now is here.
Besides, it costs money to maintain it.
I've forgotten almost everything that happened there.
So you remember some of it?
I don't remember my mom, since she died right after I was born,
but I remember a little about my dad.
He raised me on his own.
It was only for a few years, though.
He would pat me on the head,
or put me on his knees,
and we'd sit on the porch for hours...
It hurt when I remembered it,
so I tried as hard as I could to forget when I was young.
Then, sooner or later, I did.
So I'm okay now.
I couldn't bear to look at this picture, you know?
But now I can. See?
It's fine.
There are things you can't have no matter how much you want them.
So it's easier to just forget about them, Master.
Right?
Where is it?
Where's my house?
I don't know.
I can't get home.
I forgot.
I tried so hard not to, and I still forgot where my house is.
Takashi, your friends are here.
Coming!
Hey, Master, wake up.
We're leaving.
Bye, Takashi.
See you later.
Hey, guys.
There he is.
Let's get going.
Yeah.
It's hot today.
Hey, is this really the way?
According to the map I made when I was a kid, it's this way.
Right here!
Big Tree
Wild Dog!
Careful!
Scary!
Old Lady's
Ramen Shop
This is a map?
First, which ways are north and south?
Quit worrying about the details.
If we just followed some map, it wouldn't be an adventure.
Details?
I told you it'd be easier to get there from the road.
Where's the adventure in taking our bikes?
What?
We could've taken our bikes?
Shaddup.
You need more stamina, Natsume.
So do you, Tanuma!
Right, right.
Anyway, let's just keep going.
Getting lost is fun, too.
That house isn't doing you any good, is it?
Natsume?
About yesterday...
No...
You know, when I was a kid,
I made a secret base in my closet.
We're still on this?
I put what I cared about in the closet, too.
It reminded me of that.
Hey, which way is it?
I dunno.
You wrote it!
Wait, wait. Gimme a second.
Do you think we'll ever get there?
The map. Look at the map.
Takashi...
Takashi, look at that.
See?
It's right over there.
Your mom planted seeds.
She was so happy to have a garden.
She secretly planted the seeds to make us happy.
I hope they bloom again this year, Takashi.
No.
I can't remember it.
I can't go back there.
It's just empty space now.
It's okay.
It doesn't hurt.
Forget it.
Oww...
I thought I smelled something delicious.
It's a human!
Wait!
I can't believe I found such a feast all the way out here!
Delicious!
Jeez.
Begone!
Master.
You idiot, what's wrong with you?
You could've knocked that guy's lights out.
Sorry.
What's your problem?
Good question...
I let my guard down a little.
It's because I was looking at this picture.
The picture's gone!
What?
It's gone.
When did I drop it?
You don't know when you dropped it?
It's gonna be impossible to find in the middle of the forest.
Natsume!
Hey Natsume, where are you?
Oh, there he is.
What happened, Natsume?
You trip?
I'm glad.
You okay, Natsume?
I found the path.
Let's go.
Yeah.
You scared me when you just vanished.
Sorry, sorry.
You're a mess.
Right.
Natsume's got it tough.
More demon stuff, Master?
Nope, he lost a photo.
Of his parents.
You sure about this?
I think it was that tree...
What did you drop?
Tanuma...
Nishimura. Kitamoto.
It looks like Natsume dropped something.
Help me look for it.
You dropped something?
No...
You idiot, why didn't you say so?
We were about to leave.
It's fine, really.
I can come look for it later.
Natsume!
I can tell you're lying by the look on your face!
Come on, Natsume.
Don't lie if you don't have to.
I'm sorry.
Could you help me look?
That picture's important to me.
It truly is important...
You find it?
Nope.
What's this?
Ugh, a porno mag?
What?
You're in the way, Ponta.
I found it! I found it!
Is this it, Natsume?
I kinda looked at it...
Is that your mom?
She really looks like you.
They look like nice people.
Yeah.
Thanks, guys.
This picture was taken before I was born,
when it was just the two of them.
When I looked at their kind smiles,
and thought that I was supposed to be there smiling, too...
I couldn't stop crying.
It hurt so much that I wanted to forget.
Huh?
It's Sasada and Taki.
Taki?
Taki!
Hey!
Hey, I don't see you two together often.
I just met her back there.
Right?
Yeah.
We wanted the same CD, so we decided to take turns listening to it.
And what about you?
You're all messy.
Just a manly adventure.
The heck?
We went to see a soda water spring.
A soda water spring!?
Don't laugh! It was all fizzy and bubbly!
Did you actually find it?
Well...
We're going back.
You got lost, didn't you?
You need to get directions first. Right?
Fluffy... fluffy...
Fluffy fluffy!
Welcome back, Takashi.
How'd you get so dirty?
I dropped something.
Everyone helped me look for it.
Did you find it?
Yes.
That's good, then.
Go change.
You must be hungry.
Yeah.
Come on, Natsume.
Don't lie if you don't have to.
Shigeru,
Tohko.
I want to see my parents' house one last time, before it's gone.
Is it okay if I go?
Yes, of course.
We'll wait for your return, Takashi.
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
The Door Of Memories
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Next
Time On
I've got a place I have to stop first.
You always have places to stop.
Hey, wait!
Will he ever get there?
Mom and Dad were
both nice to you!
I'm going back to the home I love...