------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
Takashi, it's lunchtime!
Okay!
Could you get the letter in the living room?
That must be it.
Jeez...
All kinds of demons have been getting in, Master Nyanko.
Don't blame me.
It's your own fault, idiot.
You pay attention to them,
so the rumors have spread and more demons have come to see.
Jeez, it's not worth it for me.
Give me more meat buns!
When you don't give me meat buns, I go on strike!
Meat bun strike!
Maybe I'll feel like giving you a meat bun
once you do enough work for one.
What?!
A froggie.
It's warm, so he must've thought it was spring.
The fool.
Let's catch it, Natsume!
Wait, wait!
Oh, jeez...
The wind is getting softer.
It's almost spring.
The Moon—Splitting Festival
Hey, that's him.
That must be Master Natsume!
What do we do?
What else?
Let's talk to him.
I hear demons...
But will he listen to us?
Good point...
Then let's catch him!
Hey, wait!
I'll listen to what you have to say, so calm down!
Master Natsume, prepare yourself!
Master Natsume!
Master Nyanko!
Master Natsume, please wait!
There's something we want to ask of you!
It's been a long time.
What is it?
I'm happy you came to see me.
And cut.
Thank you, everyone!
We're done shooting for today.
Um, Natori.
It was an honor working with you.
Excuse me.
There was a flower petal in your hair.
It was an honor for me as well.
Goodbye.
Did you see that? That mysterious smile?
I can't tell if he's a playboy or pure of heart!
That slightly shady aura of his is just too much!
But where did that flower petal come from?
10:00
Blade-Washing Hill
Natori, thanks for coming.
It's been a long time.
I'll get right to the point: I have a job for you.
A landlord in Misumi came to me
and said that a spirit was causing him trouble.
Have you heard of the Moon-Splitting Festival?
No.
It's the kind of festival for praying for good harvests that you could find anywhere.
The villagers stage a mock battle between the god of the harvest moon, Houzuki,
and the opposing god of the absent moon, Fuzuki.
The festival was held once every ten years.
Blade-
Washing
Hill
Come to think of it, I've heard that it's an old festival that's no longer held.
Correct.
However, the demons have taken a liking to it.
The two gods gather and compete every ten years.
The festival has arrived again this year.
Oh, those wacky demons.
Uninterested, are we?
I told you, it's a festival for good harvests.
Should Fuzuki win,
Mt. Misumi will dry up.
But the victor isn't predetermined.
If the contest ended naturally, then we could accept it, but...
Normally, the mountain demons all get excited for the festival,
but something's wrong this year.
Houzuki is nowhere to be found.
My investigations revealed that some exorcist
sealed him away somewhere as a monster.
They never stop to think...
If Houzuki loses by default,
Misumi will become a barren land devoid of grass for the next ten years.
So, Natori,
I want you to find Houzuki before the festival ends.
I understand.
When is the festival?
Tomorrow.
Ah, tomorrow...
Huh? Tomorrow?!
If you can't find him in time,
feel free to take drastic measures.
Mt. Misumi
Well, I'm here, but what do I do?
You guys go gather information from the local demons.
I'll go to Misumigahara, where the festival is held.
We cannot leave the master alone.
Hiiragi, you protect him.
Yes.
I'm fine. Go.
I told you to go.
But...
Can you not obey my orders?
Bow down!
Lord Fuzuki!
That's Lord Fuzuki and his men!
It's Lord Fuzuki!
Lord Fuzuki!
So that's Fuzuki.
This is bad.
It's only a matter of time until they find out that Houzuki is missing.
It's been ten years since I've seen them last.
They're always so beautiful.
When both gods arrive at Misumigahara, the festival begins.
I don't see Lord Houzuki.
I'm worried.
Be at ease.
I hear Lord Houzuki will be here soon.
Was Houzuki not actually sealed?
Look at that!
Lord Houzuki is here.
It's Lord Houzuki!
Lord Houzuki!
How beautiful!
So beautiful...
A coronet of peonies and a deer-horn mask...
It's Lord Houzuki...
That's Houzuki?
Bow down!
Hiiragi...
Yes.
I just saw a demon that looked a lot like Natsume...
No, that was Natsume.
The pig-cat was there, too.
I have to ask what's going on.
Are you an exorcist?
What if I am?
We won't let you stop Lord Houzuki!
The servants of Houzuki are here.
What are you doing here?
Stop!
No matter what tricks you may play,
our Lord Fuzuki shall win!
I heard rumors that Lord Houzuki hasn't shown himself yet.
You think he maybe got bored of you and this mountain and ran?
What?
Lord Houzuki would never do that!
That's right!
He's busy with preparations, I'm sure!
We just saw his procession!
Guys!
You sure you didn't mistake him for someone else?
How insolent!
Begone!
Shut up!
Houzuki ran away.
If he's here, show him to us.
I can't have you causing problems here.
Rest assured.
Houzuki is certainly here.
Lord Houzuki! Lord Houzuki...
Black robes, return and await the beginning of the festival.
Good...
They didn't find out.
A splendid bluff, Master Natsume.
Natori?
Well, hello again.
What are you doing out here?
Well now, that's my question!
What are you doing out here in such a gaudy outfit?
I'm not wearing this thing because I want to!
Um, Lord Houzuki, are you perhaps familiar with this exorcist?
I see.
So the white hats asked you to take the place of Houzuki.
Yes.
Isn't that furball supposed to be your bodyguard?
You idiot!
How easy do you think it is to watch over somebody who moves around all the time!
And there's a spring here which flows with delicious sake.
I'm not letting it dry up.
It's true that it's not only the demons
that don't want this mountain to dry up.
I want to help.
Natori, would you help me?
Sure, I'd be glad to.
That's a relief.
Honestly, I wasn't sure I could handle this myself.
But let me be clear about this.
I didn't come here just to undo Houzuki's seal.
I have to protect this mountain for humans.
If I can't find Houzuki, and Fuzuki wins,
then I must exorcise him.
Same goes for if you're put in danger.
Natori...
I have to ask them the details about Houzuki.
Natsume.
Hiiragi?
I feel like you've gotten softer somehow.
Will Natori ever become like that?
The festival is starting.
Come, come, Master Natsume.
No, Lord Houzuki...
Get on your palanquin.
Come to think of it, what do we do in this contest?
We haven't been told, either.
Sometimes it's a race, sometimes it's a scavenger hunt.
A divination is performed each time to determine it.
That's kinda lazy.
How am I supposed to get ready?
That's the point.
Thinking about it won't help.
Come, Lord Houzuki.
Let us go.
Take care of Natori.
Yes.
Make sure you don't slack off, pig-cat.
Yeah.
What?
Okay, let's go.
Bow down!
Lord Houzuki is here!
If you don't want him sealed away,
you'd better work hard.
If you're not ready for that, then you won't be able to pull it off.
Bow down!
It's Lord Houzuki!
Lord Houzuki is here!
If they find out I'm human while I'm out here...
will Natori's group be okay?
What do you think, Master?
Look, there's a round piglet on Lord Houzuki's lap.
What is that strange, white, dumpling-like animal?
Lord Houzuki must be impressive indeed to master such a beast.
Master Natsume, over there.
Lord Fuzuki and his black robes.
You're late, white hats!
Get over here!
Not after what just happened.
You're too dangerous for us to get near you.
What?
I thank both gods for coming to Mt. Misumi.
This contest will decide who rules the mountain.
The nature of this contest has been divined to be...
hunting.
Hunting?
The first to catch the beast
that comes out of this pot will be the winner.
Are you both ready?
It's time for the Moon-Splitting Festival to begin!
It begins.
Follow Lord Fuzuki!
We won't lose, Houzuki!
Lord Fuzuki and his group have gone on ahead!
Look! They're as fast as the wind.
I couldn't even see what came out of the pot.
Lord Houzuki.
Right!
Let's go!
Yeah, this is hopeless.
I'm sorry.
I wasn't any help.
No, if you hadn't done this,
we would have lost when the bell sounded.
We'll find the beast somehow.
You look for Lord Houzuki.
Right, I understand.
Is Natsume safe?
I hope he isn't doing anything stupid.
That's it.
First, let's go see where he was sealed.
Something's there.
A monster!
What's wrong, Master Nyanko?
Natsume?
Natori.
So you're chasing a beast that looks like a dragon...
Again, Natsume?
I'm sorry...
I don't know how much the white hats can do on their own.
Fuzuki has the advantage now.
I suppose he does.
Did I imagine it?
For a second, Natori seemed hesitant
about sealing away Lord Fuzuki.
No.
It doesn't matter if it's my imagination.
Natori, it's not just the white hats.
We have Master and Hiiragi, too.
We have to find him, no matter what.
If we work together, not alone, we might be able to do it.
Natsume...
Get back, Natsume!
Master!
Stop!
Natsume!
Hiiragi!
Master Natsume!
Natsume!
I almost died.
Hiiragi, are you okay?
Yes.
You're tougher than you look.
What happened to the beast?
It ran away after it knocked you off the ledge.
I see.
We need to get back there.
I'm worried about them.
But you're hurt.
I'm fine.
We need to hurry.
Calm down, Natsume.
Natori knows how to protect himself,
and the pig-cat is there as well.
First, you need to compose yourself.
Show me your arm.
This charm will protect you, a little.
It will repel the fangs of a spirit once.
Normally I'd write it on your heart, but...
Thank you.
Then let's do you, too.
Does it work if I write it on a demon?
Probably.
Then hurry.
Let's go.
If we follow the river back up, we should find them.
I'm sure they're coming down it, too.
Impossible...
The request itself was impossible to complete in time.
I believe that the search for Houzuki was a pretense,
and the real request was to seal away Fuzuki.
I believe Natori was assigned the terrifying task
of sealing away a god
in order to remove a threat that returns every ten years.
Sealing a god?
Then that makes this even more important.
We need to do everything we can!
We drifted really far.
If we don't hurry, the black robes will find it first.
The black robes?
Hiiragi!
Natsume?
The trap triggered!
Did we catch the beast?
Let us call Lord Fuzuki!
No, wait.
It's not the beast.
That's...
No!
It's Lord Houzuki!
What? What have we done?
Wait. Something's strange.
Is that really Lord Houzuki?
The deer-horn mask...
it must be him.
No, I smell a child of man, faintly.
A child of man?
It can't be...
Is a human trying to deceive us?
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
The God, Enshrined
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Next
Time On
Are you really Houzuki?
You're not the one
who exorcised him.
They found us!
Is this the end?
Wake up, Natsume!
We're finding Houzuki!
That's right.
With Master and
Natori's group around,
we can do this!
You can pay me
back in meat buns!