Face forward and run.
I painted the lights in the sky
with these numb hands to brighten your future.
Cut through it with your hands.
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run.
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Your fingertips were painted in an adult's color.
Embarrassed, you hid them.
And as I gazed at you resting your chin on your hand,
beyond you was a flower bud, swaying side to side.
Hey, even now we're always lost,
and I remember the words I said that day:
"I'd paint the future with the color of you."
Face forward and run.
I painted the lights in the sky
with these numb hands to brighten your future.
Cut through it with your hands.
Can you hear my voice?
Embrace the fact that you can laugh honestly and run.
Ever since I was young, I've sometimes seen strange things.
They were probably what you'd call demons.
You idiot, watch where you're aiming!
Head's up, Natsume!
He fell!
This is bad! That's someone's house!
You okay, Natsume?
Yeah, I think so.
Sorry, but can you get our ball?
Sure!
Ball... Where's the ball?
There it is.
Might that perchance be the face of Natsume?
You possess the Book of Friends, do you not?
Hold it!
Damn, it's chasing me!
Where did this rope come from?
Don't tell me...
Wait, something like this happened before!
Give me the Book of Friends!
Let go!
Now, hand it over to me. Quickly!
Good grief, it's loud out here.
M-Master Nyanko!
Another spirit giving you a hard time, I see.
I came along because I was bored, and look what I find.
M-Master... I'm in pain...
Butterfly! Butterfly!
Give it to me! Give me the Book of Friends!
I said I'm in...
a lot...
of pain!
What are you doing, Natsume?
What do you think, you stupid cat?
I've told you I'm not a cat!
This lucky cat form is just a temporary one.
But you're my bodyguard, right?
So you should've...
I am not your typical bodyguard.
I'm only waiting for you to die so that I can have the Book of Friends.
Don't talk back to me, Lucky Cat.
What?!
Just wait and see! One of these days I'm going to eat you, you hear?
Geez...
Stolen Book of Friends
With no family, and after going from one relative to the other,
the ones who finally took me in were the kind Fujiwara couple.
Takashi, dinner!
Coming!
Ah, Takashi! Is Nyankichi not home yet?
He hasn't come to eat his dinner.
Maybe he's eating somewhere else.
I'm sure he'll come back when he's hungry.
You think? I hope so.
Here.
Thank you for the meal.
Eat up.
This is good!
What is it?
They're lilies.
In order to not trouble them,
I have to keep the fact that I can see demons an absolute secret.
He's not here either.
Maybe I punched him too hard.
M-Master Nyanko...
Don't scare me like that.
Where've you been?
You're pitch black!
Why?
What happened?
Hey!
For crying out loud, don't track dirt in the house.
It's not coming off.
What did you do, Master?
What's with the silent treatment?
Are you sulking because I hit you earlier?
Get over it, it was your fault.
I'm back!
Master!
What is that black thing?!
Just as I thought, it's a spirit.
Oh, so he's not you.
That should be obvious, buffoon!
There aren't many cats with such big faces.
So does that mean he's disguising himself as you?
I wonder what he's after?
Natsume, the Book of Friends is safe, right?
Yeah, it's fine.
It's right here.
Oh, no!
The Book of Friends!
Damn, where'd that black cat go?
We'll never find him while it's this dark.
Let's try again later.
But... the Book of Friends...
You're human; it's dangerous to wander around at night.
Plus, the air seems to be different tonight.
Just a bit...
Let me look a bit longer!
All of those names are my responsibility!
Plea-
Calm down, Natsume.
We're both upset that the Book of Friends was taken,
but I sensed no malevolent energy from that black cat.
That's why I let my guard down.
Right now, it would be worse to run around in a panic and alert other spirits to the fact that it was taken.
But...
What are those lights?
Ah, those are foxfire.
Foxfire?
Quite a lot of them.
Where are they heading?
Something wrong?
I think... I smell a human.
M-Master... You're heavy...
Bear with it.
I'm camouflaging you with my scent.
Must have been my imagination.
I thought it was a human, but now it seems more like a putrid beast.
A putrid beast?
I am a noble, mighty-
Calm down, calm down.
Come to think of it, the Lord often returned reeking like a human.
Ah, that's right.
He would take human form and amuse himself in the villages, and bring delicious presents back for us all.
The Lord?
Yeah.
Nothing good comes from getting involved with those damned humans though.
You said it.
They're gone.
If it isn't Lord Madara.
It has been a while.
You're as beautiful as ever.
You...
Benio?
Is she your acquaintance?
Yeah.
Oh? A human?
Were you in the middle of your meal?
Please leave me some leftovers.
Hm? I've seen this face before.
Ah! Natsume Reiko!
You fool! You're too loud!
Oh? Natsume Reiko's grandson?
What was with the march of spirits earlier, Benio?
Everyone from this forest is gathering for a banquet.
Did you see a lovely black cat biting onto some paper around here?
Lovely?
I did see a fat-headed gluttonous cat heading toward the banquet grounds.
G-Gluttonous cat?!
That's him!
Would you take us there, Benio?
Are you insane?
A human would be eaten immediately.
Then I'll go as a demon.
Please!
I absolutely need to find that cat.
That impudent look... you truly do resemble Reiko.
Is that what you like about him?
Don't be a fool.
Any more nonsense and I'll eat you.
This sounds interesting.
Very well, I shall escort you,
if you can successfully assume the form of a spirit.
If you can't, you'll make an excellent side dish.
That's fine.
Thank you.
Geez...
There you go deciding things on your own again.
Lord Madara has been shrunk!
How woeful.
Is the sake this way?
We're not going to drink.
The young Natsume will require makeup or a mask.
And you cannot attend as a beast, Lord Madara.
What? Why not?
Do not forget that Natsume Reiko is well-known.
There's a rumor going around that a young man
who resembles her, and who keeps a beast at his side, has inherited the Book of Friends.
The Book of Friends...
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Hey, how long are we going to keep that kid?
We have to for now. Even my brother...
O-Oh, w-welcome back, Takashi.
Perfect timing! Reiko's belongings came.
Reiko...
She's your grandmother.
Hey, what is this? A book of scribbles?
I heard she was way out there, but I guess she was really out there.
You can toss it if you want.
No point in carrying it around.
The Book of Friends.
My grandmother Reiko, who was born with great mystical powers,
would force the demons she defeated to write their names in it, binding them as servant and master.
Back then, I didn't know anything about the Book of Friends or Reiko.
What's wrong, Natsume?
Oh, nothing.
Will you be attending in that form, Lord Madara?
Got a problem with it?
Not at all.
Well then, let us get going.
Okay.
Oh, Benio! You sure are late.
What were you doing?
How uncouth! I was putting on my makeup.
Oh? I haven't seen them before.
Ah, they're my companions.
That looks like fun.
May I join you?
Of course. Help yourself to a drink.
You reek of humans.
You're right.
Reminds me of the Lord.
The Lord did always smell like humans.
The Lord?
The ruler of this forest. He loved them.
Once, after taking human form to visit nearby villages, he fell into a fox trap.
But he was saved by a hunter, and after that he spent much time with him.
He was overjoyed to have made a human friend.
He had strong spiritual powers,
but he wasn't very smart.
Befriending a human... How foolish...
Yeah, and to pick a fight with Natsume Reiko...
Well, drink up!
Thank you.
By the way, has anyone seen a black cat arou—
Comrades!
Let us commence discussions!
At last, we have ascertained the place those wretched humans have sealed the Lord!
Now is the time to settle the score!
The Lord, our great benefactor, blessed us with the power to live in this forest.
Tonight, we shall attack!
Do not fear the humans!
If we attack en masse they will not stand a chance!
Attack? What's he talking about?
The lord attacked the humans' livestock,
so they sealed him away!
But now we know he was sealed in a place with high, red stone walls!
But...
that doesn't mean you have to attack the people living there.
There's no need for it,
but with how drunk they are there's no telling what they'll do.
What should we do?
Don't get involved.
Such a crowd of them won't be easily stopped.
Indeed, indeed. Do not bother.
There are limits to what a mere human can do.
You're right...
But fortunately, I can hear your voice.
And the voices of everyone here.
And those of men as well.
All equally.
Couldn't this be power?
You are not like Reiko.
There he is!
Hey, wait!
I don't understand that child.
What do you like about him?
I'm only interested in the Book of Friends.
Then you should just eat him and take it.
It's a good way to kill time.
A human's life passes by in an instant.
Faster than they can fathom.
I got him, Master!
He's pretty compliant.
You don't think he's doing this deliberately, do you?
Deliberately?
It feels like he took the Book of Friends to lead us here.
For what purpose?
I don't know.
You can find out, right, Benio?
Search him.
I'll try.
I believe it to be the vessel which seals a powerful spirit.
A vessel?
Does everyone around here seal spirits in Lucky Cats?
This mystical energy... I remember it...
M-Might you be the Lord?!
What?
The Lord?
How pitiful! Curse you, humans!
He was sealed, but can move about in his vessel.
A house with high, red stone walls...
Could it be?
The ropes I broke were the barrier sealing him in?
Benio, we have to let everyone know.
In this form, no one would ever believe he's the Lord.
We have to break the seal and return him to his true form.
But how?
Come to think of it, the lower-class demons mentioned that he fought Reiko once.
Indeed, I've heard that as well.
That's it!
With his name taken from him, he lacks the power to break the seal!
So if I give him his name back...
The problem is his name though.
While he's in the form of a vessel, the Book of Friends won't be able to discern it.
Benio-san, do you know the Lord's name?
No, I only know him as the Lord.
Lord.
I will return to you your name
so please help me stop them.
What are you lot doing here?
It's about time we go.
Go attack people?
We don't need to!
The Lord has returned!
You idiot! Stop!
Does anyone know the lord's name?
If I know his name—
You're human, aren't you?
A human?
They say there's a human.
Damn humans!
Let him go!
Shut up and stay back!
Lord Madara!
Listen hard!
There must be someone here!
Someone who knows the lord's name!
Lord Riou...
There!
Natsume!
Let him go!
Lord Madara!
Riou, I return to you your name.
Please take it.
Lord!
It's the Lord!
Lord Riou...
Lord...
I'm back, everyone.
Thank you, human.
Thanks to you, I was able to move again,
and so I went to see my precious friend.
However, he had already passed away.
A human's life sure is short.
I think I know what everyone meant when they called me a fool.
Why did you take the Book of Friends?
When I returned to the forest,
I heard them planning to attack the human house for my sake.
As I lacked the power to stop them, I thought to lead you here and have you intervene.
Forgive me, Natsume.
It was humans who sealed you away.
And yet, you tried to stop them.
That's because I love humans.
Which is why I will no longer tread upon their lands.
That bath was wonderful.
Farewell, human.
Farewell...
The black cat is gone.
He was really cute too.
What's that supposed to mean?!
Just who do you think helped solve his prob—
Well now, since it seems your wounds are not severe, Lord Madara,
I will take my leave.
I just can't come to like humans.
I was thinking of helping Lord Madara find an opportunity to eat you,
But since you've helped the Lord, I cannot.
Lord Madara, will you return with me?
No.
I'm going to stay by him for a while longer.
Until that brief instant passes.
Thanks, Master Nyanko.
It's so creepy when you're nice!
Lately, it troubles me that even small good-byes make me feel a bit sad.
Short encounters, small good-byes...
I'd like to treasure every one of those moments.
Hey, just a little longer. I just want you to listen a little longer.
Hey, just a little longer. I just want to be selfish a little longer.
The moment it was in my hand, it seemed like it would disappear.
So could you say something?
With just you here,
my world changed.
Just look at the monotonous scenery,
it looks so vivid.
We were walking with our hands held,
and before we knew it, we had to seperate.
"Do you think we're a good match?"
Was what I asked the sky.
Melting into Spring
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
What's your name?
I am Gen.
Natsume, please lend me your aid.
Are you a stone statue of Shiba-no-Hara?
There should have been two, so where's your partner?
Sui... She's...