------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
This Saturday?
Yup.
They're supposed to be really big and pretty starting then!
A meteor shower, huh?
We're gonna have to practice our wishes.
Wishes?
Meteor showers are a bunch of shooting stars, right?
You wish three times before they disappear.
I wish I could find my soul mate, I wish I could find my soul mate, I wish I could find my soul mate!
Amazing.
You're worried about marriage already?
Hey, it'd be fun to have more people, so can we invite some?
Like Tanuma, or... Taki?
Sure.
Really?
All right, I'm so looking forward to this!
Why's that?
Good for you, eh, Nishimura?
Until just a little while ago,
the stars were something I only saw by myself.
Bye!
Yeah.
Ever since I was little, I've seen strange things every now and then.
Other people can't see them.
They're probably what people call demons.
Lord Natsume!
Might you be Lord Natsume?
You're...
Lord Natsume, please assist me!
My dear friend's leg is trapped under a rock, and he can't move!
Wait a minute!
Please! We need to help him, or his leg... oh, his poor leg!
I don't hate the fact that I see them as much as I used to,
but it always gets me mixed up in trouble.
Natsume Captured
Just a bit more... a bit more!
Thank you ever so much!
So, um...
Is there something else?
If you're Lord Natsume, then you must have the Book of Friends.
Please...
Please return my name!
I-I see. All right.
You who protect me, show your name.
Thank you ever so much, Lord Natsume!
No problem.
Lord Natsume...
please run away, quickly!
Hey!
Looks like that's the real Book of Friends.
So you're Natsume of the Book of Friends.
Who are you?
Ah, so this is the famous Natsume.
He looks pretty weak.
All the better.
This won't take long.
Now, give us the Book of Friends!
Stop!
Give it to us!
Huzzah!
Master Nyanko!
I only came to say hi, and you're already in trouble.
Stop wasting your time with these things, Natsume.
Thanks.
You saved me, Master.
And I was enjoying a nice buzz, too.
Don't drink when it's light out, bodyguard.
So, who were those guys?
Were they after the Book of Friends?
Probably.
But I've never been attacked by a group before.
The Book of Friends was left to me by my grandmother, Natsume Reiko.
She would defeat demons, and force them to write their names in this book as a sign of their loyalty.
It allows its owner to control many different demons.
I'm back!
Welcome home.
You must be cold.
Some demons want their names back.
Other demons want power.
Many demons come to me in search of the Book of Friends.
But the demons today...
had a nastiness about them that I don't normally feel.
It felt awful.
They probably threatened that little runt...
in order to lure you out.
Yeah.
I want to return the names of as many demons as I can.
So I can't let this get into the wrong hands.
Nishimura said you were coming, too.
Yeah, I guess.
Now that I think about it, I've never really seen a meteor shower.
Me neither. I'm looking forward to it.
Yeah, but...
I might not be able to go.
Can you guys talk to the rest of the group if that happens?
Demon problems again?
Yeah.
There's something that's bothering me.
Natsume, we've gotta get to our next class!
Okay.
See ya.
I think he's starting to rely on us a little.
I guess.
Why's he so stiff?
I asked him once, about why he doesn't tell people he can see demons.
I told him the Fujiwaras would believe him.
That's pretty straightforward.
So, what did he say?
He said it was because he wanted them to stay smiling.
Smiling?
I didn't understand at first.
But then, I had a dream where he was eaten by a demon.
Then I understood.
"Oh, that's what he meant."
For example, any time he's late,
I get a chill, and wonder if he might've been eaten, like in my dream.
But Nishimura and the others don't know anything, so they just laugh and wait.
They'd think he just overslept.
If the Fujiwaras knew, they'd go pale any time he got his clothes dirty.
They wouldn't be able to smile at all.
Natsume doesn't want that.
I'm sure it's what scares him the most.
It's over!
Hey Natsume, let's get some octopus balls on the way home.
Sure.
I'm pretty hungry...
Natsume? What's wrong?
Where is the Book of Friends?
Are you okay, Natsume?
Natsume!
Sorry, Nishimura!
I'll see you later!
They came inside the school?
Oh, Natsume?
Bye!
Hey, Natsume!
This is bad.
If I'm out here in public...
A group of demons in monkey masks?
I've never seen them around here before.
It sounds like they came after the Book of Friends.
It seems the Book of Friends is becoming famous in the world of spirits.
They felt pretty powerful.
Do you know anything?
Come to think of it,
I'd once heard of a forest ruled by such a group in the eastern mountains.
A forest?
A forest where the boundaries between the demon and human worlds are ill-defined.
Ah, I remember now.
What?
You should stay away from there.
Why's that?
There's something bad there.
Something bad?
W-Where am I?
In our forest.
It's not easy for a human to return from here.
If you don't want to get hurt, give us the Book of Friends.
What are you going to do with the Book of Friends?
We can use it to make many demons obey us.
You arrogant humans seek to control demons.
Our master requires that power.
We must give it to the master.
Give it to us!
I don't use it to control anybody, and I won't give it to anybody who would!
Strong words, kid.
Are you ready to back them up?
Natsume, where are you?
Master Nyanko!
What's this feeling?
It's awful.
Be quiet.
Master Nyanko?
Jeez...
I came to see what Misuzu was talking about,
and I find you here.
What's this?
I don't know.
They're all over the place.
Could be a trap.
To stop me from escaping?
No, that's not it.
They weren't the ones who put this here.
It was probably...
Anyway, we're leaving this forest.
The brat hid.
I smell a human around here.
Where is he?
There!
It's him...
He's coming!
Run!
That's...
I may be able to use this for something.
Matoba!
That's Matoba.
Matoba?
The exorcist?
Sir.
How did it go?
I caught one.
I don't know if I can use it, though.
Perhaps the demons' rumors are spreading.
There are far less around here.
Shh.
In that bush over there...
Another demon?
No.
Perhaps I imagined it.
The leader of the Matoba clan of exorcists.
A man who shows mercy to neither humans nor demons.
I don't want to see him.
Natsume, wait!
Is this... another trap?
I don't know, but it was Matoba who set it up.
Be careful.
It might affect humans.
Which way should we go?
If I changed back to my normal form, we could just fly out of here, but then he would notice us.
We'll have to hide.
I guess Misuzu was right.
Somewhere around here...
Master?
Master Nyanko?
Master! Where are you?
What's this doing so deep in the forest?
Is it abandoned?
Matoba?
This is Matoba's...
Matoba's servant.
So many cells...
What is this place?
Where's the exit?
But first, I need to retrieve the bag with the Book of Friends in it.
I see.
It was a young man, caught outside the mansion.
So, he thought he could just walk right in?
Interesting.
Matoba hasn't realized that I was the one he caught?
He was placed in the western cell.
His things were placed in the paulownia room.
I see something under the stairs.
Who are you?
Come out.
Well, if it isn't...
Hey, he's over here!
I think I smell a human.
What?
Something that looks like Master Nyanko was thrown into the garbage can!
I was pretending to be a statue and those stupid demons threw me in the trash!
It's not funny!  Idiot!
Jeez, I can't believe you let those wimpy things catch you and take the Book of Friends!
I'm sorry.
But assuming Matoba acted the way you said he did, he hasn't seen the Book of Friends yet.
If he'd found it, he'd be talking about it instead of you.
But Matoba spends a lot of time around other demons, so it's possible...
Don't worry.
The other spirits know what would happen if he found out about it.
They won't talk about it easily.
I see. Good.
Idiot!
As long as you hold on to the Book of Friends, you'll keep getting caught up in this nonsense!
Just hand it over to me already!
I'll have all kinds of fun with it.
Is that funny? Idiot.
It seems noisy outside.
A boy has found his way into the mansion.
I'll leave the hunting to you, Nanase.
Are you sure?
I'm sure we're going to find the master of the forest today.
This seems more entertaining.
Could this boy be...
Perhaps it's fate.
The Matobas own this? You're sure?
Yeah, Misuzu said that the Matobas had a mansion in the eastern forest.
He said that they used to use it as a base to hunt demons.
From the look of the place, this has to be it.
The exorcism business hasn't been booming lately, so they haven't been using it as much,
but I guess their leader has returned.
Hunting demons...
You arrogant humans seek to control demons.
Our master requires that power.
Are those demons trying to protect their forest?
Which way do we go?
Master Nyanko, you don't know?
Idiot!
You said the Book of Friends was in the paulownia room!
That's what I heard, but they never said where the room was.
What?!
You were just running around without any direction?! Idiot!
You were the one who started runni—
This is amazing.
Where have I seen this pot—
Let me out!
The pot talked!
That voice... are you the Natsume kid?
You're... the one Matoba's servant caught.
You need to give up on the Book of Friends.
It's not here.
Let's go, Natsume.
But where do we go?
You want me to show you?
I snuck in here once.
If you're lost, I can help!
Really?
Let's see if you're lying.
Tell me where the paulownia room is.
The paulownia room?
Oh, the room of the hated master of the Matoba?
You know where it is?
Yeah, but in exchange for my directions, you have to take me there.
What was that?
You're trying to make a trade, wimp?
Tough talk from a piglet!
I'm not a piglet!
Wimp!
You're a pot!
Take that! And that!
Stop that! Come on!
Shaddap, pot-monkey!
Master, stop playing.
There might be traps.
You hide here.
Be careful, Master.
Thank you for telling us where the room is.
No need for thanks.
Give me the Book of Friends.
I can't do that.
Dammit! If I wasn't in this pot, I could just eat you!
I still can't believe a human child would dare steal names from demons and control them!
I'm not trying to control them.
Shut up and give it to me!
What are you going to do with the Book of Friends?
What will you use it for?
If we give it to the master, he'll restore the forest.
To how it used to be.
I'm sorry, but the Book of Friends doesn't have that kind of power.
I know you want to restore the forest, but...
No, it can!
The master will chase them out, and then restore the forest!
You can't do that.
If you used the Book of Friends for that, I'm sure that your master would end up just like Matoba.
It's been a long time, Natsume Takashi.
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
Natsume, we don't have time to play hide and seek with Matoba!
The Eastern Forest
Next
time on
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Yeah, we need to get it back.
We want to acquire
powerful demons.
I can't let him find out
about the Book of Friends.
And powerful humans, too.