Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Living through these meaningless days, I let out a sigh
I've lost sight of my true self
Even if I strain my ears I can't hear your voice
So I keep walking trying to catch up
The things I couldn't tell you form into a chrysalis over time
Spreading wings, they take flight
The one, the one precious thing I'll never forget
Someday, that warm emotion
I'll do what little I can
Little by little, to get through to you
The sky's really clear today.
Natsume.
Give me a fried egg!
Give me back my protein!
Oh, come on!
Take pity on me! All I've got is a melon bread.
Jeez...
I can tell whoever makes your lunches puts a lot of love into them.
Hey, how many times have you transferred?
It must've been tough, but you don't seem too screwed up.
Hey, Nishimura.
I would've been a darn wreck by now.
Don't laugh! I'm serious.
Sorry, sorry.
That's right.
I figured if I let it bother me,
they wouldn't let me live there anymore.
But I think they could tell what I was thinking,
and they didn't like it.
I understand now.
I shouldn't have refused when they made food for me.
I should've just eaten it and told them it was good.
I'm back.
Oh, welcome back, Takashi.
Did you eat?
Yeah, it was good.
You didn't eat your parsley.
But parsley's...
That's no good. Come on, eat it.
All right.
A Place to Go Home To
Master Nyanko, Touko made you some pudding.
He went drinking again?
I'll eat it myself.
I found you.
Did it come to get its name back?
I found you, Natsume.
What?
I found you.
I won't let you go anymore, Natsume.
I'm back.
Who are you?
Let him go!
It ran away pretty quick.
What's wrong, Natsume? Natsume!
You should rest tonight.
We'll go to the doctor first thing in the morning.
I'll go to the supermarket and the pharmacy.
I'll be back soon.
Watch over Takashi, kitty.
Man, you suck.
How can you let a wimpy spirit like that get to you?
Master?
Touko?
Shigeru?
Master Nyanko?
What are you looking for?
Nobody's here anymore, Natsume.
I ate them all.
Don't start moving like that, idiot!
Jeez.
Master.
Shut up and sleep!
I remember that demon!
You met it before?
Yes, before I met you.
I didn't really understand demons back then...
Not that I do now, though.
Shoot, I don't want to fall asleep again...
I'll have another dream...
Wait, kid.
You looked at me, didn't you, human?
I'll eat you!
What should I do?
I can't go home like this.
Up here.
He can't see up very well.
Where are you?
Where did you go?
You can see us, but you don't know anything.
Did you save me?
I didn't save you.
I just wanted to see him get pissed off.
Demons are all real jerks.
Right, what's your name?
Whatever.
Anyway, you saved me.
Thanks.
I'm back.
I'm sorry I'm late...
I'm out shopping.
Watch the house.
She left the window open.
Hey, what are you doing?
Don't come in here!
Hey!
Hey! Wait!
We're back.
I'm sorry, Takashi, I went and picked up—
Get out!
Hey, Mom, did something happen?
Takashi?
What's wrong?
Um... nothing.  I'm sorry.
The room was wrecked?
Yes. I don't think he's a bad kid,
but it's kind of scary.
I should've just ignored that little demon.
Nobody else can see it, anyway.
He doesn't have any parents,
and his situation's a bit unstable.
And sometimes, he just bursts out screaming. It's creepy.
Nobody understands.
Nobody.
I never learn.
I'm an idiot.
I'm cold.
Natsume?
Are you Natsume Takashi?
Um...
Oh, I'm sorry.
I heard you were living here,
so I came to see how you were doing.
And look at me!
I'm so happy to see you.
My name is Fujiwara Touko.
I'm a distant relative of your father.
Where are you going?
Out for a walk.
No, it's dangerous to be out this late!
Go home!
Do you not want to?
No, that's not it.
I see.
Come on, you'll catch a cold.
Go home.
Um... goodbye.
Her voice was very warm.
But was she really a human?
Maybe only I could see her.
We keep running into each other.
This is only the second time.
That's right.
What's your name?
Natsume.
Fool.
Nothing good comes of giving your name to a spirit so easily.
You're lonely, aren't you, Natsume?
I like the lonely ones.
They're fun to watch.
Do you know how I can stop seeing demons?
I don't.
I see.
So that's it.
Bye.
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Yeah, I can't wait!
Natsume?
Um... Mrs. Fujiwara?
I'm sorry about the way we met last time.
I thought about it,
and I figured you should at least know how we feel.
Would you like to come live with us?
We live way out in the countryside.
Just my husband, Shigeru, and myself.
Our house is old, but it's pretty big.
We don't have any kids, and it's a bit big for us.
We heard about you a while ago...
Of course, you don't have to.
The choice is up to you.
But if you came, I'm sure our house would be much more lively.
Shigeru and I will come to meet you soon.
So at least think about it, okay?
Please.
I wonder, is it okay for me to go?
She said she wanted me to go.
Everybody else just took me in because they had to.
She's the first one to ask me what I wanted to do.
But it's only because she doesn't know about me.
I don't want to see her disappointed or scared.
Natsume.
I came to get you.
I'll stay beside you.
I told you, I like people like you.
A sad heart is delicious to me.
So I thought that it might be interesting
to keep a human as a pet.
What are you talking about?
Come on, Natsume.
You're lonely, right?
Don't!
It was stupid of me to talk to a demon.
It didn't follow me, did it?
I can't go anywhere like this.
Don't forget your scarf!
I'm fine, Mom.
Make sure you wear it. You don't want to catch a cold.
Then make sure Takashi wears one, too.
I'll be off.
But, you know...
Okay, it's not here.
I wonder if there's some way
to get rid of that demon before it finds my house.
It's done.
Looks like it's going to rain tomorrow.
That cloud definitely looks like...
Hey.
Well, it's a scrawny guy I've never seen before.
A human chased me here from far away.
Must've been hard.
They're weak, but they don't know fear.
Is there any way for a weak human like that to get rid of a demon?
Hell if I know.
Come to think of it, there's a hole for sealing spirits
that a priest made up ahead, near the fox's boulder.
Some go to see it for fun—
I smell a human.
It was a human!
You tricked us!
Natsume?
Natsume.
I got rid of those weaklings.
What were you trying to do, Natsume?
You really are interesting.
I've been watching you this whole time.
Oh no, it knows where my house is!
Now, Natsume.
Let's go together.
You can't live with humans, can you?
Some get drunk and hit you.
Others conveniently "forget" to give you food.
And then those children say horrible things when they get together.
It read my mind?
You're wrong! Everyone was nice at first!
No, they're good people deep down.
But I...
"They're good people deep down?"
That's strange.
Then why aren't you loved, I wonder?
Shut up!
Of course they don't want to let a freak into their family!
Then you can come with me.
Are you going to go back to a home where nobody's waiting?
You don't know this,
but if a human child disappears, it's a big deal.
It'll cause trouble for them.
What a pain.
I know.
I'll just eat them all.
You can't!
Please, don't!
Please!
I'll let you go for today.
Say your goodbyes, and then come to me.
Nobody's waiting for me...
Is that you, Takashi?
What are you doing here?
Oh, nothing.
Your hair's all messed up.
I'm sorry.
Sorry about my parents.
They don't really think about you, I guess.
No...
Let's go back.
Yes.
I have to think.
How can I get away without hurting them?
It doesn't make sense.
Why would such a distant relative suddenly start to care?
Distant relative?
They're probably going to ask for money later or something.
What's the problem?
To be honest, it'll make things easier.
You were saying the same thing.
We're back.
Oh, welcome back.
Welcome.
Did we have guests?
Y-Yes... I'll get dinner ready.
They came.
Mrs. Fujiwara really came.
I want to go with them!
I'm going to go.
I'm not going to disappear.
I'm going to say thanks to the people I'm with now.
Please, somebody tell me!
What, it's a human?
How noisy.
Stupid brat. Let's mess with him.
Hey, kid.
Tell me where the fox's boulder is!
How can I use the hole for sealing spirits?
What's with this kid?
He's human, but he's not scared of us!
So creepy!
Please, please!
I'm scared,
but I want to go.
Natsume. Natsume. Come out!
Natsume, come out!
Come out now, Natsume!
A child like you could never seal a spirit.
I thought I'd take care of you,
but I guess you got too big for your britches!
You need to suffer, or you won't learn!
Curse you... curse you!
I did it!
One week in the hospital, they said.
What was he doing, going into the mountains by himself?
Was he doing it to hurt us?
Mom...
I caused trouble for them again.
I can't go back to their house now.
Oh, my...  he's asleep.
You need to be quiet, or you'll wake him up.
True.
Mrs. Fujiwara?
See? You woke him up.
But you were talking, too, Shigeru.
Well, I guess...
Takashi,
if you don't like it with us, you can leave whenever you like.
But for now, you need a quiet place where you can think.
Our place is as quiet as you can get.
Come with us.
You shouldn't get up!
I want to go...
I want to go with you.
Please.
Please...
Get out of the way.
That's mine.
Too bad. He's mine now.
Give up and go home.
He's not as interesting to you anymore.
Then I'll give him sadness once more.
How dare a human disobey me?
He must suffer!
The seal must have been broken
when the hole was dug up.
That spirit was stupid enough to get sealed by a little kid.
I got rid of it.
You go back to sleep.
Touko will yell at you.
Thanks, Master Nyanko.
Are you going to go back to a home where nobody's waiting?
No, I have a place I want to go home to now.
I'm glad you're feeling better.
Hey, aren't you late?
Oh my, Takashi, your lunch!
Bye.
Eat it all.
Bye!
Right!
I'll be back!
Lining up the sparks of warmth I've lost one by one
Coming to the rainbow-colored pieces of you
I crack a smile
Not even knowing how to make memories
Even when we took things too fast
We were only going with the flow
No matter where I go, even after this darkness
How many times must I say goodbye?
Shining with the flame of a young heart
Those faraway pieces of you
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's Book of Play
We're having a banquet for Mister Natsume today.
Wait, I'm a minor!
Let's all do a trick! Go, Natsume!
Then let's do a game that children play instead.
Hello, we're the Natsume Gang!
Bark-bark!
What are you doing?