------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
Wait, girl!
You won't get away!
I order you, unholy beast, to disappear within this seal.
Those who come from water, sink within the muddy mire.
Those who come from fire, disappear into the void.
Those who come from wood, burn to ash.
Those who come from earth, blow away in the wind.
What?
Save me!
Curse you!
So you're an exorcist?
Hey!
Are you okay?
Where are you?
So weak.
She's so different from the exorcist in the next town over.
I heard that another one of our friends got beat up.
I heard her name is Natsume Reiko.
Oh, I saw her as she was beating up a spirit.
She's pretty strong.
Hey, where are you?
She's over here!
Where?
She's down there!
Natsume Reiko...
When I Was Deceived
Natsume, the weather's so nice.
Take me to get something to eat.
I just gave you some baked squid.
And you're always eating something, even when the weather isn't nice.
That was an appetizer.
I know... how about one of Nanatsujiya's bean-jam dumplings.
Hey, wait!
Hey, where are you taking me?
Who are you?
Have you forgotten me?
Your voice has become quite masculine in the short time since we last met,
Natsume Reiko.
I'm not Reiko.
This is her grandson, little one.
Come to think of it, you're rather weak for Natsume Reiko.
Then where is Reiko?
She left this world a long time ago.
What?!
No!
Master!
Then where's that paper with the names on it?
I thought Reiko would be able to use it to help.
If you mean the Book of Friends, I have it.
Really?
Grandson of Natsume Reiko, may I make a request?
Request?
What kind of idiot lets go halfway?
What a pain.
This is what I want you to do.
A friend of mine was sealed, and I want you to call him.
His name's in the Book of Friends, right?
Yes, but he's sealed in a stone.
I was planning on taking it to Reiko, and then...
And then?
I dropped it in this forest.
Who put a trap here?
I don't want anyone else falling for it.
Why would a rope lead to a well?
What strange water.
That's...
I can breathe!
So it's a barrier.
But why?
Oh, my.
If it isn't the stupid cat.
W-Who's there?
You're...
I can't leave, thanks to you.
What?
Then you put up this barrier?
If his pet is here,
does that mean the child is nearby as well?
I don't have to answer that.
And I'm not a pet.
That rock...
It seals a spirit, doesn't it?
I can seal you too, if you like.
Try it if you can,
but that's not something you sealed.
I'm impressed you can tell.
They've been sealed for a long time.
Most of them have lost their power and are disappearing.
But this many...
I don't know what exorcist did this,
but since there's so many they must've been the kind of tricky jerk who only went after the weak.
You don't know anything about it.
No...
Did you know Natsume Reiko?
What about Reiko?
She's involved in this a little.
Can you tell?
Only one of these is one I sealed.
I came to search for it, but it's going to take a while.
You won't be able to get out for a while either.
This is just a temporary form.
If I return to my original form, this little well...
I don't know about that.
What?!
It's possible you only made it through the barrier because of that temporary form.
What if you were in your normal form?
Perhaps fate has brought us together.
I'll pass the time by telling you a story.
I was born to a family of exorcists and my talents were recognized early on.
But still, even I was young once.
So you took pity on a demon who wasn't your target?
I didn't mean to...
We exorcise the evil demons
and make the powerful ones our servants.
The rest we ignore.
That is the way of all exorcists.
I know that.
But...
Hey, you.
You're the one from yesterday!
Tell me more about what you mentioned yesterday.
What I mentioned?
About Natsume Reiko.
Take me to Natsume Reiko, at once.
Listen, that person's not only really strong, but also violent!
Who knows what'll happen if somebody weak, like you, comes to visit.
Weak?
Please, no!
Anyway, if you hadn't interfered yesterday, I would've been fine!
They gave us homework!
Let's do it at my house.
Yeah, I'd like to work it together.
My mom will have fresh-baked rice crackers for us, so it'll be fun.
She's the girl who always leaves early, right?
I saw her saying some kind of weird chant near the mountain.
She always has bruises, too.
What a weird girl.
I saw that exorcist in the forest up ahead.
What was that exorcist like?
All rough and tough,
with this sharp look.
Very dangerous.
Why do you want to meet Reiko, anyway?
You want to get lessons?
Waste of time!
That person's totally different from you.
Shut up!
Girl!
You're an exorcist!
Exorcist?
Remember this!
Oh, this is him.
This is Natsume Reiko.
I'm supposed to be Natsume Reiko?
Not at all.
My name is Mikage.
Really?
You're an idiot.
The others said this exorcist's name was Reiko.
It's their fault.
I've heard that name before, too.
That person picks a fight with every demon they see and wins every time.
So that person's an exorcist, too?
I don't know.
If so, I'd like to meet them as well.
Wait a sec.
These herbs grow around here.
I've heard that they heal a wound without leaving a scar.
Thank you.
Hey, let go of me already!
You don't need me for anything else.
It's your punishment for getting the wrong person.
Stay quiet!
Why do you want to meet Natsume Reiko?
I wanted to ask somebody else who can see them
how you tell the difference between the demons you should exorcise and those you don't have to fight.
Why?
My family makes a distinction between
those you are hired to exorcise, those you turn into servants, and those you can ignore.
But I think we should exorcise all the demons!
Scary girl.
We'd be better off if they were all gone!
The way nobody else can see them, but I can...
If you can see them, you want to talk to them.
If you talk to them, you start to take pity.
I can't show any pity or friendship toward a demon ever again.
They should all just...
What do you think, Mikage?
I want to hear what a strong exorcist, like you, thinks!
I'm just sealing them as I've been instructed to.
Instructed?
So you have a teacher...
What did they say?
They said that both humans and spirits are part of the circle of life.
They said that spirits that are harmful to humanity
and those who make their living exorcising spirits
are part of each other's karma.
Karma?
Karma is the role we are born with.
The only way we can live.
Karma...
What's wrong?
My method tears away
at my body each time I seal a spirit.
It's nothing for you to concern yourself with.
It is the karma I was born with.
Can I come to see you again?
I want to be an exorcist like you!
I have a request.
What?
If I ever give into this spirit energy
and become something twisted, will you seal me away?
What... does that mean?
Go now.
Take him.
H-Hey!
Bye!
Several days later, I went to see him again.
Mikage!
What is this place?
Hey, wake up.
Oh, you.
Where is Mikage?
Resting his bones somewhere, probably.
Resting?
He won't last long.
He was already in bad shape when he dueled with Natsume Reiko.
With Natsume Reiko?
Yeah, he asked me to find her, so I did.
Why did he duel with Natsume Reiko?
Well...
I finally caught you!
Girl, this time I'm going to eat you!
Damn it, let me go!
Mikage!
I am he who inherits the power to exorcise the darkness.
You who bring disaster, return to this stone!
Wow!
Mikage!
Stay back!
Mikage...
You can't...
This way!
What are you doing here?
Who are you?
We felt a terrible demonic aura here.
Did you see anything?
No.
I heard the exorcist at this home died
and his servant is still wandering around.
His servant?
It's absorbed the energy of the exorcised demons
and is on the verge of turning into something evil.
Let's look somewhere else.
Yeah.
You get home.  Don't wander around here.
Mikage, you're a spirit, aren't you?
I was originally a piece of jade that fell into a riverbed.
My master found me when he was searching for stones to seal evil spirits.
He made me into his servant, and ordered me to seal away evil spirits.
Ever since then, I've torn apart my body to create these stones,
which I've used to seal them away.
The evil is purified in this well and returns to nature.
However, if I do this any more I shall turn into something evil myself.
I was searching for someone to seal me away before that happens.
That's why you wanted to see Natsume Reiko?
But Reiko refused.
I have a request.
Seal me away.
I'd rather be sealed by someone strong like you.
I can't!
I'm not strong at all!
No, you are strong.
Because you know the anger and sadness of being an exorcist.
That will continue to make you stronger.
I can't seal you, Mikage...
Sealing me is your karma.
Now, quickly,
before I become something evil...
Hey, are you serious?
He helped you!
You don't have to do it...
If this is what he wants,
I'd like to help him.
I seal away evil by Divine Command.
You who will someday bring disaster and harm,
return to this stone.
I seal away evil by Divine Command.
You who will someday bring disaster and harm,
return to this stone!
Ever since then, I stopped having any doubts about my exorcisms.
It is my karma.
A while ago, I learned this house was to be demolished.
I came because I was worried.
But it's possible that because of the purifying power of the well
that he disappeared along with the stone.
We have no choice but to help each other, right?
I've restored the faltering barrier.
I'll undo it, so you take this rope to the surface.
What if I just drop the rope and go?
I'd be in trouble.
Now then...
Maybe I'll fight you and seal you away.
Know your place. Don't get cocky.
I won't try.
I wouldn't want the child hating me.
I think it's around here...
So what's this demon that's sealed in the stone like?
It's not something evil, is it?
Don't worry about that.
The evil energy that was afflicting him is gone.
I'd been waiting for a chance to save him,
and finally the barrier started to falter...
I was finally able to get it out.
That's all for nothing if you dropped it.
Huh?
There it is!
Okay, here I go.
Thank you.
I return this to you,
Mikage.
Mister...
I felt you near me, always.
I'm sorry it took so long.
Thank you, grandson of Reiko.
Mikage...
I want to thank the one who sealed me, too.
Now I shall finally be released from my karma...
Mister...
Don't worry.
I'm just returning to my original form.
Mister...
What is the person who sealed Mikage like?
I don't understand them,
but they were interesting in their own way.
I see.
Grandson of Reiko, sorry to bother you with this.
Thank you.
Natsume!
Master!
I've been looking for you, Natsume.
You okay?
Yeah.
I see.
He was finally released.
No, nothing.
Did anything happen with you, Master?
No, nothing special.
Maybe I'll tell you about it sometime.
What? That's stingy.
More importantly, Natsume, I totally forgot about it,
but we're going to get those Nanatsujiya bean-jam dumplings!
Hey, Master!
It's dinnertime!
Dumplings! Bean-jam dumplings!
Wait!
Master!
Rice cake dumplings!
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
The Moon—Splitting Festival
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Next
Time On
Houzukigami?
The god of the
moon-splitting festival,
which is held once every ten years.
And we have to find it?
Yes, at this rate the
mountain will dry up.
Master, I see someone I know
in Houzukigami's group.
The cat?