Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
Living through these meaningless days, I let out a sigh
I've lost sight of my true self
Even if I strain my ears I can't hear your voice
So I keep walking trying to catch up
The things I couldn't tell you form into a chrysalis over time
Spreading wings, they take flight
The one, the one precious thing I'll never forget
Someday, that warm emotion
I'll do what little I can
Little by little, to get through to you
Jeez. Why are you following me, kitty?
The view's better than usual up here.
Sir, pets aren't allowed in the inn.
Oh, no, look again.
It's just a stuffed animal. See the big head?
So, did you find out anything about Matoba?
No, but we should be prepared.
He's not afraid to use dangerous demons for his own goals.
Wasn't there a crow he used as bait one time?
He doesn't hold back, no matter whose servant it is.
So that's why you left them home?
What do you mean?
Your own servants.
No, not really.
Actually, I sort of regret it...
The charm!
You must have broken it when you left!
So that's why the door was so hard to open.
What were you thinking?
What if something got in?
It'd be your fault for putting up a charm so weak that a cat could break it!
You and I just don't seem to get along.
Natsume?
Natsume!
Exorcist
I won't forgive you...
I'll never forgive you!
How dare you?
How dare you!
Are you awake?
Interesting, isn't it?
Normal people can't see that paper.
Matoba.
The Natori family knows more about that paper than I do.
Ask them.
Why are you doing this? What do you...
I haven't done anything.
I just told them to catch you.
But I don't think you'll buy that excuse, will you?
You can see them.
I'm sorry they were so rough.
They're still learning.
But it's your fault for running.
You said you wanted to talk to me, after all.
Why are you gathering demon blood?
What are you planning?
Demon blood can be used to break the seals binding more powerful demons,
and in turn, summon them.
In a way, it's like bait.
There's a very powerful one sleeping in this forest.
That's what I'm after.
Instead of using your own blood...
you steal it from innocent demons?
If you don't stop this, you'll regret it.
I'll regret it?
You can only see them.
What can you—
I'm sorry.
My depth perception isn't very good.
Your eye...
I can see just fine,
but I need to wear this
or else my eye will be eaten.
Long ago, there was a man who promised his right eye to a demon in exchange for its service.
But in the end, he broke his promise.
And for generations since, demons have been after the right eyes of the Matoba clan.
My eyeball is still in its socket,
but I have a nasty wound here.
Would you like to have a look?
May I have a moment?
I'll be right there.
Watch him.
No matter what your reasons are,
please stop attacking innocent demons.
If you won't, I'll stop you.
I just want to have strong demons to protect people.
If that means people hate me, or I pay
some other price, then that's fine by me.
He's different.
He's an exorcist, but he's very different from Natori.
I'll be back shortly.
If you make a lot of noise, I'll make it so you can't make any noise.
And if you run, I'll make it so you can't run.
Just stay here and wait.
If he finds out about the Book of Friends...
It only took one hit, huh?
I thought he was only capable of seeing them.
Shall we follow him?
No.
You don't have to.
That was close.
Matoba's servants?
There's a very powerful demon in that forest.
I have to protect the few friends I have left.
In a way, it's bait.
I may still be able to stop him.
Natsume, you mustn't go into that forest!
What is it?
I feel a terrible presence to the west.
The west?
My master went that way.
What is that presence?
An eye...
If that eye opens, they'll be devoured.
They'll all be devoured!
Where are you going?
I'm going to save them.
I can't get Natsume involved in this.
He will decide if he wants to be involved or not.
My master and the furball are with him as well.
But...
What can you do, wounded as you are?
Rest.
Natsume...
Why don't you call me, Natori?
I would fly to your side.
Matoba just checked out.
I... I see.
See? You're way behind him!
Your name's been "shady guy" up until now.
From now on it's "screw up"!
Screw Up Natori!
Look everybody, it's the exorcist, Screw Up Natori!
Did you say something, you pig-faced furball?
Sir, I'm pretty sure that's a cat.
N-no.
What was that?
I can't let Matoba get what he's after.
I need to find this powerful demon and stop him somehow.
Which way is it?
I should be able to sense it.
Which way?
Sorry!
This way.
I think it's around here.
Oww...
A cave?
It's back there.
You're a really annoying kid.
Did you come to interfere?
Matoba's servant?
Too bad, but you're going to be my offering.
I'm running out of time.
Wait.
This voice...
Before he comes...
Before he...
Master!
Get lost!
Get back, Natsume!
Natori!
My light didn't work on her.
I know this voice.
The evil that I felt from that masked demon...
That voice in my dreams...
Are you...
actually a human?
Of course.
I see. You're the witch who once served Matoba!
You know her?
Yes, her servant demon was used as food by Matoba.
She's been retired since then, or so I heard.
They used her servants as bait?
I'll never forgive Matoba.
I'll devour you...
and awaken a demon that will devour Matoba!
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
This is it.
It doesn't look like it's woken up yet, but...
Look, Natsume.
A circle of awakening has already been drawn around him.
Those pots...
You idiot.
They obviously hold all the blood that's been gathered.
I found a demon that the greedy Matoba would be sure to love,
and I spread rumors all around.
I drew him to this village so he could be devoured.
Are you out for revenge because your servant was eaten?
It's a shame, but in this line of work, the demons we use are—
Nothing but tools?
It wasn't like that with me.
He wasn't just a tool.
But this is going too far.
I don't care if an exorcist like you understands.
But I need blood. I need more blood.
So I'll take yours!
Do you think that's all I have?
There's no end to them.
Nasty.
I'll tear apart these paper dolls.
Master!
Natsume!
Oh my, excuse me.
There were so many demons that I didn't know which was which.
I didn't mean to hit him.
Matoba!
It was quite difficult to find this place.
Whenever anything happened, I'd send someone to investigate the demons.
I had my servants search the forest many times.
But when I let you go for just a minute,
you found it for me right away.
I wonder about you...
You punk.
You've crossed the line. Prepare to die.
Master!
Calm down, Master!
Don't move!
Your wounds will open!
Natsume!
Don't worry, I'm fine.
But Master...
Master!
You got lucky, Matoba.
What?
How boring.
Master, you're bleeding!
A drop or two of blood won't kill me.
I just have to lick it...
Natsume, your wound...
It just scraped me.
The bleeding's stopped.
What's going on?
You really are a demon, Master.
You idiot!
Even I'd be terrified if I had things like those running through my veins!
The blood...
Look! The blood in the pots, too...
Shoot... that cat's blood is powerful.
He woke it up!
Master!
Was that arrow... aimed at Master on purpose?
He wanted to test this demon... so he did it on purpose?
Get away, Natsume!
This is bad!
He's giving off a nasty poison!
Go!
I'm the one who drew the circle
and gathered the blood to awaken you!
Devour him for me!
Over there! Devour him!
Natsume, run!
Right!
Are you okay?
You never change.
What do we do?
It's gonna be really bad if that gets to the surface.
How vulgar.
An exorcist falling in love with a demon,
and then doing something that stupid and rash.
And now this.
Matoba...
I can't use that demon.
I'm leaving.
Hey, you...
Forget about him, Natsume.
It's dangerous here, so we need to get outside.
Bye, then.
Natori?
I'll seal it away.
You take everyone else and go outside.
No way. I'll help you, too.
What?
Two are better than one, right?
All right.
You stay with her, Master.
Master...
Well?
Can we use it?
No. It can't speak, so we can't make a contract with it,
and it's too strong for me to subjugate it with a spell.
And then there's the poison...
Oh, my.
Since he's not out yet, Natori probably went to seal it away.
Natori?
I only teased him a little, and he came running?
What a child.
Shall we go?
You came all the way out here, and the demon turned out useless.
Such a waste of time.
Not so much.
I can't use the demon, but I am interested in the boy and the cat.
Okay, follow me!
He's fast!
Come on, just a bit more!
Natsume!
Ye who rest in the Earth and hold the keys, come to me.
Ye is the one who disturbs the stones.
Take away the inhuman one.
Natsume!
Natsume...
If you don't need a demon, don't waste time on it.
Just blow it to bits.
I don't care about the demon or that woman...
but you interest me.
We'll meet again.
It was a pleasure to make your acquaintance.
The Exorcist Matoba clan...
I'll never forgive him.
Matoba...
There's nothing you can do for them now.
You'll have to forget it all.
Could you forget?
Could you?
Natsume. So that's him?
Yes.
Natsume Takashi.
The grandson of Natsume Reiko.
I see, so that's who he is.
Then that makes him all the more interesting.
I'll have the Natori clan take care of the rest.
All right.
Master.
I've returned, Hiiragi.
Welcome back.
Are you angry?
I have no reason to be.
I am your servant.
Can't they see it?
The pain of a spirit doing all
she can to protect her friends,
or the pain of someone whose bond with a spirit was so deep
that when it was lost, her heart was broken.
As long as they get what they want,
they don't care who gets hurt.
Natsume.
There's no need for you to worry yourself about them.
That's just how some people are.
That's all there is to it.
That's right.
I have Master, Natori, and Hiiragi.
I'm...
different from them.
Lining up the sparks of warmth I've lost one by one
Coming to the rainbow-colored pieces of you
I crack a smile
Not even knowing how to make memories
Even when we took things too fast
We were only going with the flow
No matter where I go, even after this darkness
How many times must I say goodbye?
Shining with the flame of a young heart
Those faraway pieces of you
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
The Fox Cub's Watch
He's here!
Natsume's here again!
When he sees how strong I've gotten, will he be happy?
The god of the rocks was saying something weird,
but I want to help him as much as I can!