------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
Another bombed test.
What do I tell Mom?
Year 2 Math Test
Jeez, you're always such a klutz, Yuriko.
I was totally scared when I heard you were in an accident, and then I see this.
You just got a sprain.
Talk about a false alarm.
My bad.
But like, why were you visiting a shrine?
You don't know?
She goes there every time she bombs a test.
Don't say it like that!
That's news to me.
She's totally been doing it since middle school.
Like what?
An exorcism?
She's right. I did that back then.
That's how I met Natsume.
To You, From
Bygone Days
Man, this is just hilariously sad.
Math II
Systems of Equations
Another test, another F.
Math II
Systems of Equations
This kid... he's the transfer student...
Wha... What?
He kicked me? A girl?!
Ogata Fusae
Yuriko
Morning.
Hey, Yuriko.
I heard the transfer student lives around here.
Oh, yeah.
What's he like?
What's the kid like?
Natsume
Takashi
I'm Natsume Takashi.
Nice to meet you all.
I heard a rumor
that he was being passed around from relative to relative.
This time, a married couple who lived in a beat up apartment in town took him in.
The girls in class said he was the cool, quiet type.
He's the cool, quiet type.
The hell he is.
Really?
That's not what I've heard.
When he was little, he would make stuff up,
and he acted weird and hurt other kids.
Don't get too close to him.
If anything happened to you, your poor mom's heart would stop.
Make stuff up?
Sure, he acted weird, but...
Natsume.
I'm not too happy about what you did to me yesterday.
Who are you?
Ogata Yuriko! You know, from your class!
Did you forget what the girl you kicked at the shrine yesterday looked like?
Shrine...
Oh, that was you?
I was having a bad dream at the time,
and when I opened my eyes, there was a monster right in front of me...
Hey!
Are you saying I looked like a monster?
That's right.
I'm sorry. I was half asleep.
What?
It was my fault.
Sorry.
Hey, you should cut your hair a bit.
Yeah, it's about time for me to cut it.
No way... you cut it yourself?
You think I can ask for the money...
Sorry.
I'm pretty sure what he almost said was,
"You think I can ask for the money to get it cut?"
Did I say something insensitive?
Will I have a chance to apologize?
He's always alone when I see him,
and it's hard to talk to him.
But I realized something while I watched him.
Yeah, he was definitely a little weird.
Sometimes he would just start running,
or trip and fall over nothing.
Stay back! Go away!
Sometimes it was like he was trying to get rid of something.
I said, stay back!
...and when I opened my eyes there was a monster right in front of me...
Maybe he saw something behind me,
and tried to protect me from it...
No way!
What am I even thinking?
It's raining.
Looks like we'll be using the gym today.
All right, Yuriko.
We've got club stuff,
so we'll see you tomorrow.
Oh.
Yeah, see you.
What am I doing?
Want to share?
Natsume...
I'm sorry about earlier.
For what?
Natsume...
Natsume, can you...
Can you see things?
I felt like if I asked that, he'd never talk to me again.
I couldn't say it.
I'm back!
It just started raining.
Hey, Yuri.
Were you sharing an umbrella with that boy just now?
Yeah...
I told you to stay away from him!
Your mom's worried!
Thank you, Mom.
But...
Natsume overlooked my thoughtlessness and let me share his umbrella.
He's a kind person.
Soon, I was able to talk to Natsume, though a bit hesitantly.
But then, something happened.
What's wrong? Are you okay?
Natsume?
You again?
There've been a lot of broken windows lately.
I hear Natsume's always around when it happens.
No way.
How many times has this happened now?
Why do you do this?
You're coming to the teacher's office.
Wait a second!
Yuriko!
There's something wrong here!
Look. The glass fell inside the building,
and it's broken in a weird way.
You need to pay more attention.
It's not Natsume.
Besides, Natsume would never do something like—
Ogata.
It's all right, Ogata.
Thank you.
Open your eyes, everyone!
Can't you see?
You're not seeing the real Natsume!
Somebody...
Yuriko?
His guardian was called to the school,
and a woman who smelled of alcohol took Natsume home.
Shortly after that,
Natsume said that he'd be transferring away.
So, it's because of what happened, right?
It wasn't even your fault.
Work isn't going well for them.
They don't have the time to look after somebody like me.
I'm sure you'll get some nice people next time.
They've all been nice up until now.
But no matter where I go, I'm always hated in the end.
Both by people, and by them...
That's how I met Natsume, and how I said goodbye.
Oh hey, Yuriko.
You remember Natsume?
You know, the kid who transferred when we were in middle school.
He was in our class for a while.
Oh, him.
What about him?
Toyomatsu said he saw him a while ago.
Toyomatsu? The studyholic who went to Central High?
He joined the cycling club and totally bulked up.
Shut up! That's just crazy.
Anyway, his club went touring during our last break.
He happened to see him...
He didn't even say hi?
He was all like, "But I've never spoken to him in my life!"
I wanted to tell you, Yuriko.
Why?
'Cause you were friends with him.
You were totally crushing on him.
What? Don't be stupid! Of course not!
Aw, come on.
Admit it!
Seriously, it's not like that!
Aw, come on!
That's another rarity you've brought home.
Master?
You saw those guys on the bikes on your way home, right?
Yeah.
When they passed by,
I saw that thing jump from one of cyclist's backs on to you.
You should've told me then!
I was busy thinking about my dumplings!
I can't spend mental energy on every one of these wimps.
Jeez...
Don't worry, Natsume.
It's called a Suneko, and it's harmless.
It's weak, so it protects itself by clinging on to humans.
Oh, I used to call it a clingbug.
You've seen one before?
Before I came here.
It was in a town I stayed in for a while.
It's probably the same one.
There's a scar here.
The sudden visitor.
brought back a somewhat unpleasant memory.
Natsume
Takashi
I'm Natsume Takashi.
Nice to meet you all.
What are your hobbies?
Tell me what kind of girls you're into.
Did you know what club you want to join?
Don't pile so many questions on him.
You might scare him off.
Aw, come on.
What's wrong?
No, it's nothing.
Get off me!
After a sight like that,
the kids who had tried to be nice to me
had stopped talking to me.
Back then, it was easier that way.
I was more worried
about the demon I'd thrown on the ground.
If I'd hurt it, I wouldn't feel right.
So, I went back to check up on it.
What, you're still here?
I guess I worried for—
Was that you, human child?
Stupid brat.
I'll eat you!
That weakling relies on humans to live.
You're going to pay for stopping me, human.
I put a curse on you.
You or someone around you will die.
The people around me have nothing to do with this!
That's how a curse works.
But, should you elude me for thirty days,
I'll undo the curse.
Thirty days...
Remember this, kid.
If you run to another town...
Somebody else in this town will die.
After that, the demon with the black scythe
popped up and chased me.
When I reached the shrine,
I let my guard down and fell asleep.
That's right.
After that, I got to know the girl I kicked.
I'm not too happy about what you did to me yesterday.
Stay back! Get away!
Stay back!
Black Scythe kept chasing me,
but I started to think he wasn't being serious.
He seemed to enjoy chasing me.
It's another fun day for me, Natsume!
Give it up!
Why do you keep following me?
I hate you guys!
Don't get cocky, human.
I just like bullying people like you.
Is that why you were bullying that clingbug?
That pathetic demon
has to cling to humans to protect itself.
I can't stand that.
Is that it?
You remember the curse I put on you, right?
Where you or somebody else around you will die...
Don't!
Hiroshi!
What's wrong?
It's okay, don't cry.
After that, Black Scythe started coming to the school.
How many times has this happened now?
Why do you do this?
You're coming to the teacher's office.
Wait a second!
Yuriko!
There's something wrong here!
Look. The glass fell inside the building,
and it's broken in a weird way.
You need to pay more attention.
It's not Natsume.
Besides, Natsume would never do something like—
Ogata.
It's all right, Ogata.
Thank you.
After that, my guardian was called to the school,
and it was decided that I would go to another family.
Please, undo the curse!
I'm leaving this town.
The people here have nothing to do with me.
Isn't that right?
I see.
You're leaving.
It's not that I'm running.
I just don't have a choice!
A lie.
The curse was a lie.
I was just teasing you.
I cannot kill humans.
This scythe doesn't work on them.
I used to serve the god here.
My task was to take human disasters
and suffer in their place.
I know not how to curse humans.
Then, why did you lie?
Because I hate you.
So go wherever you will, but begone!
No matter where I go, I'm always hated in the end.
Both by people, and by them...
Not everyone hates you.
I know, because I saw the real you.
Thank you, Ogata.
It was kind of fun here.
Goodbye.
I meant it, Ogata.
It was kind of fun there.
Anyway, so Toyomatsu kept an eye on him for a while.
And then...
And then?
A kind looking lady came to meet him,
and he carried her shopping bag home.
Hey, Toyomatsu.
Let's go.
Yeah.
I see...
So that's how it is.
You found some nice people, Natsume.
I don't know what he saw in this town.
I wonder if something he got involved with
saved me from being hit by that truck.
I tried imagining that.
For a few days afterward, Suneko stuck to me.
But one day, it just jumped off and vanished somewhere.
It probably jumped on to somebody else
and went to another town.
Will it ever go back to that town?
If it does,
I hope it tells the demon and people I met
that I'm doing just fine.
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
Other Side Of The Glass
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Next
Time On
That's a nice trick, Natsume,
fitting in a glass bottle.
I've been trapped in here!
Save me!
I'm not giving you
to that Onibashira!
Leave it to me!
You're actually sounding
helpful for once, Master!
Help me!
Well?