Natsume Yuujinchou
San
Living through these meaningless days, I let out a sign
I've lost sight of my true self
Even if I strain my ears I can't hear your voice
So I keep walking trying to catch up
The things I couldn't tell you form into a chrysalis over time
Spreading wings, they take flight
The one, the one precious thing I'll never forget
Someday, that warm emotion
I'll do what little I can
Little by little, to get through to you
It's almost time for the cultural festival.
What's your class doing?
We're gonna decide tomorrow.
I want a bunny girl cafe.
Nobody's gonna go for bunny girls.
Why not fairies?
Fairies?
Hey, that's...
It's Natsume.
What's he doing?
Why'd he climb all the way up there?
Natsume!
Hey, you okay?
Jeez...
What are you doing, Natsume?
S-Sorry.
Nishimura.
Kitamoto.
I can't tell them I was dealing with a demon.
Don't go swimming in your school uniform!
At least put your bag down.
I'm really sorry.
Thanks.
Hey... you'll catch a cold like that.
Want to come by my house?
Welcome ba...
Oh my!
Hi there.
Sorry to drop by unannounced.
Sorry.
Never mind that. But you should get in the bath!
Excuse us!
Come in.
I haven't been here in ages!
Umm, Touko,
it's my fault both of them got wet.
You're really such a handful.
The people I've met in this town are all so kind.
Thanks for having us!
I can't ever let them find out that I can see demons.
Through
the Autumn
Wind
Through
the Autumn
Wind
Sleeping again?
I don't know what to do when it's so quiet.
Get well soon, Master.
A rock?
Did it get into my bag when I fell into the river?
What was that rock's problem?
You always find the weirdest things, Natsume.
Hinoe.
I'm grateful, but why are you wearing sandals in my room?
I came to see how the furball was doing.
How is he?
He's sleeping a lot.
That's a good sign.
When you're in real pain, you can't even sleep.
He's getting better, little by little.
I'm glad.
Mr. Natsume!
We came to check on you guys again!
Again?
Don't go drinking all night this time!
I've got school tomorrow!
Aww, don't be like that.
Don't be like that!
You reek of booze!
You've already had a few drinks, haven't you?
Then drinking more won't hurt.
When did you get here, Moustache?
Tonight, we'll drink, party, and protect you!
Protect you!
That rock felt pretty nasty.
You should be careful for a while, Natsume.
I didn't get any sleep.
Cultural Festival
So, does anyone have any ideas?
A cross-dressing cafe!
None of the guys would come to that. No way.
Bunny girls! Bunny girls!
It's hard to do a cafe.
I want to walk around, so we should do a display.
I say we should do a bazaar!
They're having a good time, too.
Be quiet!
If you have a suggestion, raise your hand and wait your turn.
I'll go.
We could all take stuff from home that we don't need...
I never used to like this sort of thing.
But lately, when I hear everyone's voices, I feel at home.
What's she staring at?
Is there something on the ground?
Natsume, what are you looking outside for?
Were you listening?
Okay, so Natsume will work the store.
Wait a second!
That's great.
I've never worked with customers before!
So you're working the store, huh?
Don't laugh, Taki.
I'm sorry.
Class 2 is doing a bazaar, huh?
What about you, Tanuma?
We're doing a play.
A play? Wow.
Are you going to be in it?
I'm just doing the lighting.
What about your class, Taki?
A cross-dressing cafe.
Last year, I couldn't really talk to anybody, remember?
Yeah, that must've been hard.
Taki was cursed by a demon back then...
I want to do everything I can to enjoy the festival this year.
Hey,
none of us are really into festivals and stuff,
but let's make this work!
S-Sure.
There's the star of our play.
The star?
Kitamoto?
Hey, Natsume.
Come here!
What's wrong, Nishimura?
Natsume, you've been spending a lot of time with Taki lately!
That's not fair! It's not fair at all!
They look like such good friends.
But Natsume can't even tell his best friends about those demons, can he?
He still can't tell us everything, you know.
Taki is mine!
It's not like that!
So you're the star of the play?
I drew the short straw.
What kind of play is it?
Shakespeare.
You're gonna wear tights?
Hell no!
I'll have to go see it.
So you're working a store, Natsume?
Good luck.
Make sure you keep smiling.
Blood?
Is it demon blood?
Natsume!
What's that?
Sorry about that!
Sorry.
Somebody tripped over a paint can.
Make sure not to step in it.
Oh, it's just paint.
Natsume, what's wrong?
You look pale.
I'm fine.
Really?
Yeah.
That class has already started putting things together.
We've gotta hurry.
What if that was demon blood?
What would I have done...
if it were at school?
Natsume?
Who's there?
Who's she?
She's the girl who was looking at the ground.
You dropped this.
Huh? What was I...
Bye!
Supply Room
Was this stone controlling her?
If it's that strong,
what should I do with it?
If I throw it away, and it ends up hurting someone...
Should I break it, or grind it up?
What's it saying?
What?
What do you want to do?
What is the secret?
That voice!
Natsume!
What's wrong, Natsume?
Sasada... I'm fine.
Are you sick?
Let's go to the nurse's office.
No, I'm fine.
If you need to go home, I'll walk with you.
I'm sorry, Sasada.
I'm fine now.
Really?
You scared me.
Oh, shoot, shoot!
It's back to being a regular rock.
Where did the spirit inside it go?
It followed you, huh?
It must have been sealing quite the powerful spirit.
What's it after?
It seems like the type that possesses people.
It probably wants to possess you, since you're so powerful.
If I'm its target, then it won't hurt anybody else, right?
It's probably hiding inside others in order to get close to you.
But the things and people at this "school" of yours are probably making it curious.
Curious?
It was forced to sleep at the bottom of a river for a long time,
so it probably just wants to see what's new.
It went after you not only to drain your power,
but also to see what was inside your heart.
My heart?
What is the secret?
Secret?
My...
Listen, Natsume.
Don't give it any openings, and don't let your guard down.
Yeah.
Your furball of a bodyguard will be better soon.
You'll just have to last until then.
Thank you, Hinoe.
Is it the Book of Friends that the rock demon wants to know about?
Master Nyanko, rest well.
Master, there's a cultural festival coming up at the school.
I'm going to be a cashier at a bazaar.
I want to enjoy the festival this year.
Let's make this work!
There'll be all kinds of shops
to visit and things to do.
I'm sure it'll be fun.
There'll be lots of tasty food to eat.
I hope it goes well.
I have to find that demon.
I can't let anything happen to my classmates because of me.
Natsume!
Nishimura! Kitamoto!
What's wrong, you guys?
Well...
What's up?
It's probably hiding inside others in order to get close to you.
What?
Why are you staring at us like that?
It's nothing.
Natsume, is it just me, or do you really not want to work at the store?
Well, you looked really pale today.
No...
You always try to hide what you're thinking, anyway.
Don't do that with us.
We want you to have fun with this!
If you don't want to do it, tell us.
I'll do it instead.
Thank you.
But I do want to do it.
I'm really looking forward to it.
I'm so happy.
What should I do?
I'll be working the store, too, okay?
This is yours, Natsume.
Here's yours, Tsuji.
So I'll be working the store, too?
An apron?
Yeah.
Everybody working the store wears one.
You can all sew this ribbon on yourselves.
It doesn't look like anything strange is going on.
Don't give it any openings, and don't let your guard down.
Hey, Natsume!
Help me out here.
Sure!
Is this a dagger which I see before me, the handle toward my hand? Come, let me clutch thee.
Ow!
I have thee not, and yet I see thee still...
I can't do it!
There are too many lines to learn!
Ow!
Y-You guys look really down.
Okay, let's do this!
Be careful, you guys.
Days passed as I kept a close eye out.
That demon stayed in hiding.
And finally, the day of the festival came.
You look great!
Welcome!
Please, feel free to pick up and look at anything.
W-Welcome!
Natsume, can we take pictures?
Pictures?
Excuse me, can I get a discount on this?
Um, well...
Hey, Mr. Popular!
Taki!
That's a guy's suit?
Natsume, how much is this?
Hey, hey, how much is this?
Natsume!
Um...
This is harder than I thought.
Natsume, nice work.
You can take a break.
Thanks.
Oh, come on, girls.
What is the secret?
What is the secret that you're keeping from your friends?
What do you want to know?
She's got nothing to do with this, right?
Wait!
You're after me, right?
Watch it!
If I don't catch her, and someone gets hurt because of me...
Was that...
Natsume?
Stop!
Give her back!
Watch out!
Secret...
Jeez...
I came because you said there'd be tasty food, and this is what I get?
Get lost, rock.
Weakling!
Natsume!
What is the secret?
Even though I can't tell them, they're still my friends.
What are you protecting?
I wonder... can I protect them?
Natsume!
Hey, new guy.
Why don't you ask your folks for a bike already?
You can't go out with us without one.
Sorry, you can go without me.
I can't ride a bike.
Why?
What do you mean?
You can't ride those things without somebody behind you, right?
Don't let go! Just don't let go!
These aimless days, and the people I spend them with...
Don't slow down!
are what I want to protect.
You're fine, you're doing great!
I've never had people around me like this before.
They're important to me. What should I do?
The more people I care about, the more uneasy I feel.
There's so much I don't understand.
Master Nyanko?
Oh, you saved me.
I didn't even need to seal that runt.
I just got rid of it.
Master Nyanko,
I'm glad you're better.
I couldn't do anything.
I couldn't do anything alone.
That's the way humans are.
But I think I almost saw something...
Something that gave me a lot of courage.
Natsume, you're up!
What are you doing?
You always do the craziest stuff!
All the freakin' time!
What were you thinking, you idiot?!
I heard you passed out, Natsume! Are you okay?
Oh, good.
Natsume, you're looking better.
Natsume!
Oh, everyone's already here.
The truth is, the people I want to protect are the ones protecting me.
And so I keep finding more things that are different,
and I keep on going.
The cultural festival is over.
Hey!
Want to go to fishing?
Get your bike!
Sure!
Even if they're small, I take one step at a time.
Lining up the sparks of warmth I've lost one by one
Coming to the rainbow-colored pieces of you
I crack a smile
Not even knowing how to make memories
Even when we took things too fast
We were only going with the flow
No matter where I go, even after this darkness
How many times must I say goodbye?
Shining with the flame of a young heart
Those faraway pieces of you
Next time on
The Broken Mirror
Natsume Yuujinchou
I think Tanuma's been avoiding me lately.
You worry too much about other people.
He's my friend.
If there's something bothering him,
I want to talk about it.
I'm sorry, Natsume.
I didn't mean to hide it.
It's just...
I've found you.
Give back my mirror.