I got it!
Wait!
Catch us if you can!
Are you okay?
He's gotten so mean!
Mom, I've gotten stronger.
I'm fine on my own now.
I'm sure I could help Natsume!
Natsume...
The Fox Cub's Watch
You want to go on a trip together?
Yeah.
Do you remember Yasui
from the Kariba Hot Springs?
From back when I had you get me this tea cup.
Oh, on the summer trip.
I've chatted with him a few times since then,
and he asked me to come help him
with a pottery class he's holding.
Are you coming, Touko?
I promised to go shopping
with some friends that day,
so you two go have fun.
The class is just going to cover the basics
with kids from around the neighborhood.
I can turn him down if you're busy.
Oh, no...
Do you have plans with your friends?
No, I'd like to go.
Then, let's do it.
Yes.
Master?
What's up?
Were you moaning just now?
You must have been dreaming.
Does it still hurt?
If I lick it, it'll be fine...
I was planning on having the middle-rank demons
take care of you while I went to the hot springs.
What?
A hot spring?
Natsume!
You're planning on going to
a hot spring without me?
See? You shouldn't move around too much yet.
The Kariba springs won't heal a spirit's wounds.
Hinoe! Nobody asked you!
I heard you were hurt, so I came to visit.
What a cold greeting.
Let me see.
You were hit with a cursed arrow, huh?
This'll take some time.
Will it?
He said it would heal quickly.
He wasn't lying.
From our perspective, it's just a moment.
But it takes time for a spirit as powerful
as Madara to regain his energy.
It looks like he's lost a lot of blood.
Then, he can't go on the trip after all.
I'll apologize to Shigeru, and then...
You should go.
There's a medicinal herb called hazegrass
that grows around there.
Hazegrass?
It's a medicinal herb for spirits.
Normal people can't see it.
It grows on trees that are many decades old.
If you grind it up and apply it
to a demon's wounds, they'll heal.
I don't need it, but take me
to the hot springs anyway!
Fine, fine...
You want to go on the trip, don't you?
Mr. Madara, we've come to visit.
Just a visit!
I heard that the white pig cat was injured,
so I came to see for myself.
Oh hello, Mistress Hinoe.
Have a drink!
Don't mind if I do!
Hey, it's late!
You guys are making too much noise—oww!
It would probably be worse
for his wounds to stay here.
You seem tired, Takashi.
Yeah, I was up late packing.
Want some coffee?
Sure.
Thanks.
There's a place that sells good lunches on the way.
We can go there for lunch.
All right.
Is this what it feels like
to go on a trip with your dad?
It's a bit embarrassing, but it feels nice.
I'm sitting across from him,
but I don't really know what to say.
Young people aren't too
interested in pottery, are they?
I feel like I'm making you come along
for an old man's hobby. Sorry.
That's not true.
I really liked the tea cup I got last year.
I've always liked the feeling of pottery.
It feels cold, but somehow warm...
like soil, I suppose.
I understand that.
So I've always wanted to try making it myself...
It's new for me to have
a conversation with him like this.
This is what humans wear on their arms!
I can see it!
I've often seen you come here
to watch the human trains.
Who are you?
I'm the rock you're standing on.
I suppose you could say I'm the avatar of this rock.
I used to be worshiped by the villagers here.
Worshiped... are you a god?
The humans decided to worship me
on their own. I never asked them to.
You come here to watch the trains often,
but are they that interesting?
No, I just come here because I might see Natsume.
When he doesn't show up, I get disappointed.
But I come anyway.
Natsume... is that a friend of yours?
Friend?
Yeah! He's my friend!
I see you're wearing a watch.
A watch?
A device that humans made to measure time.
It wasn't moving a moment ago!
Do you think wearing
that will make you more human?
More human?
No, I want to be a great fox like my mom!
Then that's something you don't need.
It measures human time.
Human time?
It's Natsume!
Natsume's here!
Wait!
Natsume came to see me again!
I'm not as weak as I used to be, Natsume!
The wind feels good.
Yes.
Shall we go?
It's been a whole year...
I wonder if he's doing well.
Natsume!
That's...
The person Natsume lives with.
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Yasuian
Pottery
School
Welcome, Fujiwara.
It's good to see you.
Takashi, was it?
You came to get that pair of teacups last year.
Yes. It's been a while.
Come in.
I'll lead you to the studio.
Natsume, look over here!
What's this?
He's carrying a human trinket!
The beast thinks he's human?
This brat can't even transform!
Give that back!
Pass!
Here you go, partner!
It won't be as easy as last time!
Give it back!
Sorry, sorry! You can keep it!
Freakin' beasts!
That's the place my mom told me never to go to.
This is where we'll fire the pieces
we'll make in tomorrow's pottery class.
They'll be done the next day,
and then you can take them home.
Sounds like fun.
You must be tired today.
There's a hot spring out back.
Go enjoy yourselves.
Thank you.
I can't get close to Natsume like this!
Thanks.
Let's switch places.
Come on.
You've grown up.
Since you've come to live with us, I mean.
Everyone still calls me a wimp.
You've grown stronger.
I can tell, since we live together.
So good...
Why did Natsume come to such a horrible place?
Didn't he come to see me?
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
It stopped.
I see...
It's only alive when I'm moving.
Make sure you don't get any air into the clay.
Natsume!
Lift me up, wimp!
Me too! Me too!
You're such a wimp!
Won't I get any bigger?
We're going to start the firing.
Can you help me with the kiln, Takashi?
Sure!
Beast child, you must not meet
with the human anymore.
Why?
If you do, one of you will be sad.
Listen well.
Everything in this world lives in its own time.
And they are not always the same.
Humans have their time, and spirits have theirs.
And beasts have their own as well.
I don't understand.
Natsume's time and your time are different.
You must hurry.
You must find a partner and have children,
and teach them as wisely
as your mother taught you.
That is what it means to live in a beast's time.
In the same way, Natsume lives in his own time.
And it is very different from yours.
Do you have your own time, then?
I've lived the time of a rock.
I was here far before the humans
or spirits were born,
and I'll sit here until time itself ends.
You'll always be here?
If I leave this place, I will disappear.
That's what I am.
Aren't you lonely here all alone?
From my perspective, it's not that long a time.
Not that it's short either.
We seal the clay in here for the rest of its time.
Then it takes the form we gave it.
Now then, let's all take a break until the pieces
are done baking and are ready to paint.
Takashi, what are you going to do?
I've promised Yasui I'd go see his other works.
It's not often I get to come here,
so I'm going to go wander around for a bit.
I thought it would be easy to find him,
but I guess I was wrong.
He's got his own life, I suppose.
I know you...
Oh, hello. It's Mister Natsume.
It's been a long time.
Oh, right.
Do you guys know what that little fox is up to?
Oh, him?
He's just no good.
He's grown up to be quite the little delinquent.
A delinquent?
He gives us all kinds of trouble.
Look at this scar!
You two weren't bullying him again, were you?
Of course not!
I see.
There's one other thing I want to know.
Mom, I don't understand.
I just wanted to be with Natsume.
Hey, don't be so stiff.
We wouldn't do anything with Mister Natsume here.
You met Natsume?!
He wanted to see you!
Really?
Natsume...
But he seemed busy.
He said he was here looking for an herb.
An herb?
Yeah. It's called hazegrass,
and it grows in old trees around here.
Hazegrass...
Takashi!
We're going to start the painting!
Okay!
If I could do something for Natsume...
We'll bake them for twelve more hours,
and they'll be done.
That's all for today.
What's wrong?
Excuse me, I'll be right back.
Hey, Master, you need to get back to bed!
There's a storm coming.
I'm sure he'll be fine, though.
That's it!
Natsume...
I'm going to give it to Natsume!
I'm almost there!
Hey!
Natsume!
Natsume! Natsume!
You found these for me, didn't you?
Thanks.
Natsume, the god saved me...
Look!
If I leave this place, I will disappear.
That's what I am.
He told me not to meet you anymore.
Since one of us would be sad.
But... but that's not true, Natsume!
The watch is broken now...
But it really was moving, Natsume.
I saw it happen!
I remember meeting the god,
what we talked about, and how he saved me...
So I'm sure you and I will... will...
I didn't understand everything
that the fox cub told me,
but I think I understood the meaning
of what he learned from the god.
That spirit...
He must have spent a lot of time
watching the differences
between how humans and spirits live their lives.
Natsume!
Goodbye!
You put Nyangoro's face on it.
Yes.
It's nicely made.
Good for you, Nyangoro.
Meetings and partings may just be a moment apart.
Even so, I want to treasure them all.
I've gotten involved with another demon.
Through the Autumn Wind
Next
Time on
Natsume's Book Of Friends
Natsume's
Book
Of
Friends
We need to do a bunny girl cafe
for the cultural festival!
We can't have bunny girls!
What's wrong, Natsume?
Festivals are all about having fun!
Yeah, I'm looking forward to it.
Have a cat cafe where everybody
can admire my beauty!