------------------------------
Natsu
me
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuu
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujin
chou
------------------------------
Yuujinchou
Why are you crying?
------------------------------
Natsume
Yuujinchou
I don't understand any of it
The words I need to say to ask you aren't easy for me
Tell me why you are sad
I want to help you however I can
I devote this song to you, as you experience every passing minute
I devote this song to you, as you live life to the fullest
Until today we lived through such sad times
so I'm sure starting tomorrow we will see only happy days
Don't bear your sadness all alone
I can see demons?
Why?
A demon?
Oh, my.
You must be a strange human to wander into the world of spirits.
The world of spirits?
Is that why I can see them?
My, my...
I'll let you off the hook for now, so go home.
If someone finds you, you'll be eaten as a snack for the banquet.
But, my friend—
Oh, no.
I shouldn't tell him.
Anyway, it's not a good idea to wander outside of your territory.
Now get going.
Thank you.
I guess some demons are nice.
Well, I wouldn't know about that.
He said that there was a banquet.
It's safe to assume that's where he was taken.
I need to sneak in somehow.
Be quiet, idiot!
The Gap Between
Humans and Spirits
Come on, come on!
Until the master arrives, place your gifts on this altar.
Come, come! This is a glorious event.
Drink, drink!
Offerings...
Everything here is a present to Omibashira?
On top of that, there are so many demons here...
It's up to me whether I help him or not.
I'm sure Tanuma is looking for me.
I need to get out before he comes here and something happens to him.
I see.
So this is that Natsume human?
He's too small to see well.
He's a human, but he's supposed to be really strong.
They know who I am!
A splendid find, yes?
Lord Omibashira will be pleased.
He must be delicious.
Is it true you found Natsume?
I saw him once from a distance.
Let me see.
He's pretending to sleep?
Hey, there!
Don't be fooled, everyone!
That bottle is a fake.
What was that?
Tanuma!
The real Natsume is inside this bottle.
He said he had an idea, so I let him go in.
Let's see how well he can do.
Hey, are you okay?
What happened to your kimono?
Did someone take it?
Hey, aren't you...
I suppose now's not the best time to just squash him.
Go get 'em, Tanuma.
I finally caught Natsume, and now I find
that someone else claims to have found him first?
Are you calling me a liar?!
I am.
I know you want to stand out, but your lies won't work.
Y-You're the liar!
Then let's see who's got the real one.
Fine.
Hey, kid.
Show them your face.
Tanuma!
Hey, kid!
I told you to show your face!
Damn it.
He's opening it.
He smells like a human.
What?
Crap!
Natsume!
You're a pain to watch over.
Who are you?
Run.
W-What?!
They'll get away!
I didn't expect any humans to come here.
It doesn't matter.
They can't escape this mansion, so we needn't worry.
If I've come this far, I'm fine.
But man, this place is much bigger than the outside made it look.
This might be trouble.
Natsume?
That's right. I hear he's still somewhere in the mansion.
Supposedly, he's got a fat calico cat with him.
This is hard.
We'll be okay here for a bit.
Thanks.
Really, didn't I tell you to stay away?
It's fine, Natsume.
This demon helped me when I was about to enter the mansion...
That's no demon.
What are you doing here?
I'd rather not say.
We'll just get into another fight.
Besides, that's my line.
What's going on, Natsume?
I guess he's just a normal kid.
You shouldn't have brought him here.
I know that.
Wait.
Natsume didn't bring me here.
I came on my own.
It's fine.
Natsume...
It's my responsibility.
I was careless and got trapped in that bottle, so you...
I guess you're starting to learn.
It's dangerous to spend so much time with demons that they learn your name.
You're not a demon?
Who are you?
I'm Natori Shuuichi.
I work as a demon exorcist on the side.
A demon exorcist?
But I've seen you somewhere before...
Umm...
I'm an actor by day.
Oh, right.
I'm going to be in a movie soon.
I'll give you a ticket.
It was right here...
Now's not the time!
We need to get out of here.
Ah, Hiiragi and Urihime.
Good timing.
Get them some masks.
They'll need two kimonos as well.
Yes, sir.
Hiiragi.
Natsume?
You look pale.
Do you know them, Natsume?
Yeah.
Who is this?
Come to think of it, I didn't get your name.
Natori.
Don't worry.
I'm not gonna try and recruit someone who's just a little sharper than average.
It's Tanuma.
Tanuma Kaname.
Tanuma, eh?
Nice to meet you.
Tanuma is getting more and more drawn into this world,
and it's all my fault.
I smell a strong human scent.
Is it coming from here?
Hiiragi.
Yes, sir.
Found you, you punks!
Oh, Natsume.
You got out, huh?
Not bad, Tanuma.
Is that you, Master?
Master?
Jeez.
They know too much.
It's hard to go around in this beautiful form.
I didn't know you could take human form.
Of course I can.
But taking a human form is for beasts and low-class demons.
It's not for a noble being like me.
But why that form?
The only humans I've ever gotten a good look at are Natsume and Reiko.
No matter what I do, I end up looking like one of them.
Who's Reiko?
Who knows?
This one won't break either.
A barrier?
Do we have to go back to the entrance?
No, that won't be so simple either.
What do you mean?
Come this way.
What the...
There's no staircase or incline,
but that window shows the view from the first floor,
and this has the view from the second floor.
It's pretty complex.
Is it to keep us from getting out?
I thought it might be, but it's too big and involved.
They were talking about offerings,
but Omibashira himself is nowhere to be seen.
Something's wrong.
This energy...
The evil energy is getting stronger.
I'll go upstairs.
Thanks.
I'll go check over there.
Wait.
What's wrong?
You stay here, Tanuma.
If anything happened to you...
I already told you.
I'm here because I want to be here.
Besides, according to the exorcist, since I wandered into the world of demons,
I can see them just like you, now.
So I can help...
You two.
Did you see my friend come this way?
No.
Nobody's come this way.
He must've left already.
Natsume, you're shaking...
I'm happy you feel that way,
but if it got you hurt...
The world of demons is just that dangerous.
Natori, isn't this blood?
Yes.
It's likely they were eaten.
Eaten? Who was? By whom?
By Lord Omibashira.
I was planning on sealing it while it was still weak,
but it looks like that's no longer possible.
I see, so that's it.
So what's it?
Those Onizaru guys didn't spread those flyers to gather offerings.
They wanted to lure the less powerful demons here
so they could be fed to Omibashira.
Right now, they're all locked inside and lost,
and it's eating them one by one to revive itself.
This is bad.
That's horrible...
Then, if we want to leave...
We'll have to either find the exit,
or seal Omibashira away before it regains its full power.
Those are our only options.
It'll be fine.
Natsume...
I promise.
I'll definitely get you home safely.
No matter what happens.
Let's split up.
Natsume and I will look for Omibashira.
The cat and Tanuma will look for the exit.
No matter what we find, we come back here in one hour.
Got it?
Got it.
Master Nyanko, take care of Tanuma.
Yeah.
If he just sticks with me and doesn't do anything stupid, he'll be fine.
Here, this stone will protect you.
Hey, Natori!
Are you saying you can't trust me?
It's my policy not to force a lady to work.
Creepy!
This is just a temporary form.
Okay, see you in an hour.
I guess a strange kid would have strange friends.
It's not funny.
Still, I'm sorry about earlier,
for yelling at you when you saved him.
No, it's my fault for talking like I did.
You never told him you knew any exorcists, did you?
I suppose not.
Even though he's your friend?
Or, because he's your friend?
Yes.
That Natori exorcist guy might actually be pretty nice.
Although he's kind of forceful, and he feels kind of shifty.
Those are just habits he's picked up.
That's what happens when you have a lot of enemies.
Enemies?
You mean demons?
Mostly.
But in that line of work,
spirits aren't the only things after you.
I see.
This world seems complicated.
Well, don't get too involved in it.
Somebody as weak as you will get eaten quickl...
If he's eaten this many,
Omibashira must have regained a lot of his power.
This isn't something he could ever tell his guardians about.
Is that why Natsume...
I promise. I'll definitely get you home safely.
Master?
What?
What did Natsume's face look like
when I said I'd help him?
When I said I'd do what I could,
what did he look like in the bottle?
I thought he'd be happy.
I thought he'd feel a little better.
That's why I...
But...
Ask Natsume.
I don't know.
These are...
Are these...
Omibashira's footprints.
What's this presence?
That was Tanuma!
Tanuma!
He was attacked, but the stone kept him safe.
The poisonous aura was enough to knock him out, though.
Tanuma...
Jeez... everybody keeps wandering off!
You're late.
Aw, shut it!
So where's Omibashira?
Close, most likely.
Which means that even if we did find the exit,
we won't be able to run away so easily.
We'll have to seal him.
You've been planning to do that the whole time.
I suppose so.
Natsume, help me ready the seal.
I've always been terrified...
That something like this would happen one day...
Natsume?
Tanuma isn't the kind of person who would come to a place like this.
He's not like me. He's cautious and thoughtful.
It's just him and his dad,
so he never does anything that would worry him.
When he's with me,
he always holds back what he wants to say for my sake.
I brought him here in spite of that,
and I made him do all these absurd things...
What should I do?
Maybe...
I... shouldn't live here anymore.
Natsume.
You're strong, Natsume.
I hated that feeling so much that I gave all that up long ago,
so I don't know how to say this, but...
You can't give it up.
It might be hard, but you need it.
You need it.
Master.
Omibashira is in the corridor above.
I see.
Hiiragi, you stay with Tanuma.
Natsume, I'll prepare the seal.
You'll help me, right?
Natsume, if you can't do it, I will.
No, I'll do it.
I'll go.
Save us!
The windows!
The windows won't open!
Save me!
Lord Omibashira, you're hungry, right?
Come this way!
Oh no you don't!
Shadow of the one who hides in the gap, grab hold and sleep, and answer my call!
The master's power had almost returned!
How dare you!
You'll pay for this!
Hey, there's a human child here!
And an exorcist, too!
What?
A human child?
Jeez... This is the problem with demons.
Be silent!
Listen weaklings, those two Onizaru
tried to feed you to Omibashira!
What?
Then that was Omibashira?
His barrier is gone.
Now leave!
The banquet is over.
Anyone who remains, I will eat myself.
He's gotten far enough from the mansion that the poison is receding.
Thank you.
Natori asked you to come finish things in the mansion.
Understood.
Tanuma.
Natsume?
Thank you.
Thanks to you, I got out of that bottle,
and we were able to seal Omibashira.
We couldn't have done it without you.
The truth...
Tell me the truth.
Tanuma?
My getting involved made things worse for you, didn't it?
It made you suffer, didn't it?
I'm not really good with other people.
Even if there are things I want to know,
I don't know how much I can ask.
I want to help you, but I don't know what to do.
Well...
If you don't like it, say so.
If you don't want to answer, you don't have to.
I'm glad you told me you could see demons,
but I don't want you to regret it,
or to put a wall between us because of it.
I was so happy you told me, so much that it hurt.
Tanuma.
What should I do?
I'm sorry, Tanuma.
I'm sorry.
Where do I go from here?
It's probably the path that Natori gave up on.
The one that Reiko wanted to follow, but couldn't.
Will I be able to follow it?
Bye.
Natsume...
You'll be at school tomorrow, right?
Yeah, I have to take my chance to complain.
You told me to complain once I got out of the bottle, right?
I'm back.
That's right...
They said they'd be home late.
I'm hungry!
Food! Food!
I'm back.
I'm tired...
Natsume!
Wake up!
We're gonna eat that gratin.
Hey!
You can't give it up.
It might be hard, but you need it.
Hello?
I hid the tears in my eyes from you when you walked away with a sad smile on your face
Now being treated tenderly is a little painful, but I still cherish every day
When the wind goes through the nooks and twilight falls I am reminded fondly of you
and our promises of being together forever replay in my mind, having come to naught
Love and warmth fill my being
as I put the love you gave me behind me and move on
When I Was Deceived
Natsume Yuujinchou
Shi
Next
Time On
We'll exorcise anybody who
tries to stop us, even the cat.
You're merciless, aren't you?
I wasn't always like this.
Humans and spirits are all
born with their own karma.
I want to be strong like you!