Natsume Yuujinchou
San
Living through these meaningless days, I let out a sign
I've lost sight of my true self
Even if I strain my ears I can't hear your voice
So I keep walking trying to catch up
The things I couldn't tell you form into a chrysalis over time
Spreading wings, they take flight
The one, the one precious thing I'll never forget
Someday, that warm emotion
I'll do what little I can
Little by little, to get through to you
Math
Last Day
Midterm Exams
It's over!
How'd you do, Natsume?
Not too good, huh?
I didn't get enough sleep, so I couldn't think.
You idiot, that's what you get for studying all night.
I actually spent the whole night giving demons back their names.
But I can't tell him that, right?
Anyway, the test's over!
Let's go somewhere to celebrate.
Here!
Perfect Day for A Walk Magazine
You guys going somewhere again?
What? Leave us alone.
Why?
Ooh, I want to go to this art museum!
No way.
Natsume's Book of Play
Want to go fishing again?
You need to mix it up a little.
Since it's autumn, want to go grape picking?
No!
We need to go somewhere that will give us lasting life lessons.
That's not my idea of a good time.
Hey guys, let's go home.
Perfect timing.
Where do you want to go?
What?
They're going to go have fun somewhere.
Let's go to the beach.
It's too cold for the beach.
I was just thinking that you've changed lately, Tanuma.
We were in different classes, so I didn't really know,
but I never thought of you as the talkative type.
I never thought you'd be talking about stupid stuff with those guys.
So you're saying we always talk about stupid stuff?
Not Natsume.
Nah, he's just like us.
That's right.
And that goes for Tanuma, too.
Both of you were transfer students,
and you didn't talk very much when you first got here.
That's right.
I thought you guys would be cooler.
Then you turned out to be just like us.
Also, the two of you both seem to collapse from anemia all the time.
That's, uh...
Well...
What a pain.
So, are we going fishing again?
You're the one who said we needed to mix it up a little.
I guess this means we're all grown up.
You know what I mean?
When little kids go out to play,
they can have all kinds of fun in an empty lot.
Ah, so that's what you mean.
As people grow older, they learn to put aside childish things.
Soon, we'll be learning how adults have fun.
How adults have fun?
Hey!
Well, you know, when you were a kid, anything you did was fun,
so it wasn't so hard to find something to do.
Yeah, you're right.
We did something different every day.
What did you do when you were kids?
I played house, tiddlywinks...
I used to go exploring!
Exploring?
Yeah.
I'd take some kids from the neighborhood and go out to the reservoir.
My parents got really mad at me for that.
I used to do things like that, too.
I played hide and seek on the temple grounds,
and one time I hid in this really important shrine building,
and when my dad found me, he whipped me good.
Everybody played tag and hide-and-seek.
Shadow tag!
I used to play shadow tag all the time.
If somebody stepped on your shadow, you were "it".
I know that one.
Everybody does.
Oh, yeah.
I watched the other kids play, but I never joined them.
We never decided on where to go.
You shot down everything.
Hey, where do you want to go, Natsume?
Honestly...
anywhere would be fine.
If we can all go together, any place would be fun.
Oh, right!
Say cheese!
What was that for?
The teacher gave me this for the cultural fair.
He asked me to take some pictures for the senior yearbook.
Senior yearbook?
Isn't it a little early for that?
Not at all.
It won't be long at all.
Tanuma, are you going to take over the temple after you graduate?
I haven't really thought about it yet.
It must be nice to be a priest.
I dunno what I'll do.
Yeah, but you need to start thinking about college and work.
My future, huh?
I need to think about it, for Touko and Shigeru.
But what kind of work can I do?
No, no, no! No way!
Let's enjoy being high schoolers a little longer before we decide.
Yeah, that sounds good.
I'm back.
Welcome back, Takashi.
How was your test?
It went okay.
I think.
I see.
Good job.
I'm making tempura today.
Change and come downstairs.
Okay.
Wait.
Give it a taste.
All right.
Here.
Well?
It's good.
I think it needs some sauce.
Shigeru!
Don't eat until dinner's ready!
What?
Takashi can do it, but I can't?
That's a shrimp!
Those are for everybody to share!
Aww, come on. I'm just eating one.
Nope. You get one less.
I'll go get changed.
Welcome back, Mister Natsume.
Welcome back.
What's everybody doing here?
Did Master call you?
Why would I call them?
They have something to talk to you about.
What do you guys want?
No trouble this time.
Not at all!
We wanted to tell you that tomorrow is the Spirit Moon.
Sake tastes especially good that night.
Yum, yum.
The Spirit Moon?
Indeed.
Plus, the position of the stars is especially good this year,
making the sake several times better than usual.
So, we're all getting together tomorrow afternoon for a drinking party.
Drinking party!
So, all the spirits who know you
have gotten together to throw the first annual
"Party for Mister Natsume in the Run-down Old Shrine Near Yatsuhara"!
Run-down, run-down.
A party for those who have to put up with Mister Natsume's whining and meddling,
and run to him like a dog if he needs us.
You could call us the "Natsume Dogs"!
Bark!
What kind of name is that?
So, we'll be coming to pick you up tomorrow.
We wanted to let you know.
Sorry, but I'm not going.
It sounds shady.
Don't be a spoilsport.
Come on, you can hang out with us.
Hang out, hang out!
That's right.
Please join us, Natsume.
Stop it, you guys!
Takashi, come down.
Coming!
Anyway, just go home for now.
All right.
Master Nyanko, you're my bodyguard, right?
Do something about them.
Why? You should go.
It'll be more fun than you think.
You just want to drink.
Huh?
Taki!
Natsume!
Kitty!
Stop it! Stop it!
Natsume, do something!
I can't breathe!
What's going on, Taki?
You didn't get cursed again, did you?
No, I decided something.
I want to understand the research my grandfather did on demons.
Of course, I won't mess around with anything dangerous.
When I draw my circles, I don't complete them,
and I always erase them.
But sometimes I like to practice, like you just saw.
It might help you out someday.
You don't need to worry about me.
That's not all.
I don't want everything my grandfather worked for to disappear.
Taki...
I don't know what I'm going to do with myself after high school,
but for now, I can do this much, right?
Mister Natsume.
Please return my name.
Master.
Jeez.
Let's help him out.
Taki.
Sorry,
I've gotta do something.
Go on without me.
All right.
Bye.
That which shields me, reveal thy name.
I return your name.
What's this?
You're the demon from this morning.
He fell for it!
Get him!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
What are you doing?
Stop it!
W-Wait!
Oh, Natsume. You're late.
Master!
Party of Dogs
You're quite late. And you smell as you always do.
Welcome!
Over here!
Come sit by me.
Here you go, Natsume.
You have to drink three for being late.
No, I'm a minor.
You're always so stiff.
That tickles.
Please stop!
Natsume.
Benio.
It's been a while.
I came for the free drinks. So all this is for you?
Hey, Benio.
Oh, Mister Madara.
You're still in that pitiful, tiny form.
You're just shallow.
I know someone who adores this form!
Although she's a human girl.
What?
You know a lot of powerful demons, Natsume.
Really?
Hey, Natsume!
You dance too!
I couldn't.
Mister Natsume, what do humans do for fun when they gather like this?
I want to know, too.
What do they do for fun?
I don't know.
They play cards...
and when they're outside,
maybe kick the can or shadow tag.
Shadow tag? That sounds like fun.
I know!
If Mister Natsume can't drink,
then let's play that shadow tag game with him!
Let's do that!
Hey, wait, I didn't―
Natsume, how do you play that game?
You know tag, right?
It's like that, but if the one who's "it" steps on your shadow, then you're "it".
"It", huh?  Sounds like fun.
Of course, if you catch somebody, you get to eat them, right?
No, you definitely can't.
I think the point is to run from the person who's "it",
and hide from them so they can't step on your shadow.
Then shouldn't you just hide in a shadow?
If I remember correctly, you can't do that for more than five seconds.
Okay.
I'll be "it" first.
You can run anywhere on the shrine grounds.
Here we go!
They all ran off.
Stay away!
Don't come over here!
Liar Natsume!
Get lost!
Let's have a drink.
He's here! He's here!
Shoot!
Got you, Moustache!
Oh my, how foolish of me.
I see a creature with short legs.
I stepped on your shadow.
Now you're "it"!
Dang!
I'm kinda pissed now.
My beastly blood roars!
Oh, well.
I'm having fun.
I...
stepped...
...on your shadow!
Natsume, prepare yourself!
Why?
You're not "it" anymore!
No complaining!
Stop running, Natsume.
You need to give up.
Don't joke with me, Master Nyanko.
You're supposed to be my bodyguard.
Don't think you can get away with this!
Get him, Mister Madara!
Get him!
No mercy for humans!
Shut up!
I told you that anything but stepping on somebody's shadow
was against the rules!
That was dangerous.
I'm guessing that was against the rules, too.
Since I was the first one Mister Madara stepped on,
let's get back to work!
Misuzu.
It's been a long time, Lord Natsume.
You've guts to call us "dogs".
Party of Dogs
That was Cyclops's idea.
I stepped on your shadow!
Now you're "it", Mister Misuzu.
Oh, so I'm "it"?
That sounds like fun!
Wait.
You're supposed to step on the shadow of the players who run.
I see.
That sounds like a fun game.
Now, run, lesser beings.
Misuzu, sorry, but could you be the referee?
One... two... three...
If you step on somebody's shadow, you can
do whatever you want with them, right?
There's no rule like that.
I get it!  You should run with your shadow in front of you!
Run to the north!
Run away!
What is this game?
It's endless.
Humans are terrifying creatures to think of such a game.
Natsume, how does this end?
Well, I've never actually played it,
so I don't know.
What?
So you've never played it before?
Nope.
But I can see how much fun it was for everyone I watched when I was little.
I don't!
I don't know when I started meeting so many spirits.
I wonder if Reiko was ever able to feel like this.
So you're "it" next, Mister Madara?
Then let's make this our last game.
If he steps on your shadow, you're out.
And if he steps on them all, he wins.
Wait!
That means the one who's "it" has to do a lot of work!
An excellent idea.
Graveyard
Anyone whose shadow is stepped on has to go inside this circle.
I don't want to go in that.
Hey, listen to me!
Begin!
Stop!
I'll get you all!
Here's one!
I'm dead!
Okay, one more.
Dead!
Next!
Oww...
I fell down a hole?
I guess nobody will step on my shadow if I'm down here.
Wait!
Let me catch you!
Nobody's dumb enough to wait  just because you tell them to.
Wait! Hey, wait!
Hey, you.
Is your name Natsume?
Wanna play?
Every time I moved,
plenty of kids would talk to me at first.
Then, I'd say things they didn't understand.
Of course they didn't like people they thought were liars.
Liar Natsume!
Stay away, Natsume!
Hey, Natsume!
New kid! Come with us!
You're lucky you get to move a lot.
You must go lots of places and see lots of people.
Bye!
Bye-bye!
See you!
Natsume!
Master Nyanko!
You're the clumsiest kid I've ever seen.
Get up here.
You're the last one.
If you step on my shadow, it's over?
So what, are you gonna stay down there forever?
No, I can't get up.
Pull me up!
What?
You're a pain, you know that?
Lord Natsume.
Mister Natsume!
He got you, too?
Humans are weak.
What?
He got you all, too.
Mister Madara wins!
Now, let's drink to celebrate!
Celebrate! Celebrate!
Sorry for being weak.
We'll protect you.
If someone weak like you called us, we wouldn't have a choice.
We like you, so we'd have to protect you!
Hey, Natsume!
What are you doing out here?
We're going over to Tanuma's.
Let's finish planning our trip.
Come with us.
What are you doing, Natsume?
Is there something there?
No...
Go, Natsume.
I'm going to play with them a bit more.
Master...
Yeah.
Natsume!
Bye!
Sometimes, I've hated being able to see demons.
However,
seeing them has also let me meet so many different people.
Now I can feel grateful.
My dear friends.
Right now, both humans and demons
are equally irreplacable to me.